<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Statutory Interpretation Archives - The Clements Firm</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/statutory-interpretation/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/tag/statutory-interpretation/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 15:58:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/cropped-TCFLogo012419White-1.png?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>Statutory Interpretation Archives - The Clements Firm</title>
	<link>/tag/statutory-interpretation/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21395931</site>	<item>
		<title>DC Post-and-Forfeit Is Not A Conviction For Immigration Purposes</title>
		<link>/2013/07/08/dc-post-and-forfeit-is-not-a-conviction-for-immigration-purposes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2013 04:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Criminal Law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Criminal Immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[District]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Immigration Court]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Misdemeanors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Removal Defence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Statutory Interpretation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Washington]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://new.theclementsfirm.com/?p=421</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A colleague recently asked me whether the DC post-and-forfeit procedure after arrest is properly considered a conviction under federal and immigration law. The simple answer is that the post-and-forfeit procedure does not equate to a conviction. Under immigration laws, a conviction is defined as follows (in 8 U.S.C. § 1101(a)(48)(A)): The term &#8220;conviction&#8221; means, with respect &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2013/07/08/dc-post-and-forfeit-is-not-a-conviction-for-immigration-purposes/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">DC Post-and-Forfeit Is Not A Conviction For Immigration Purposes</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/07/08/dc-post-and-forfeit-is-not-a-conviction-for-immigration-purposes/">DC Post-and-Forfeit Is Not A Conviction For Immigration Purposes</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A colleague recently asked me whether the DC post-and-forfeit procedure after arrest is properly considered a conviction under federal and immigration law. The simple answer is that the post-and-forfeit procedure does not equate to a conviction.<span id="more-421"></span></p>
<p>Under immigration laws, a conviction is defined as follows (in <a href="http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/8/1101" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">8 U.S.C. § 1101(a)(48)(A)</a>):</p>
<blockquote><p>The term &#8220;conviction&#8221; means, with respect to an alien, a formal judgment of guilt of the alien entered by a court or, if adjudication of guilt has been withheld, where:</p>
<p>(i) a judge or jury has found the alien guilty or the alien has entered a plea of guilty or nolo contendere or has admitted sufficient facts to warrant a finding of guilt, and</p>
<p>(ii) the judge has ordered some form of punishment, penalty, or restraint on the alien’s liberty to be imposed.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Under this definition, the DC post-and-forfeit procedure does not involve a conviction.</p>
<p>The DC code regarding its post-and-forfeit procedure is as follows:</p>
<blockquote><p>§5-335.01. Enforcement of the post-and-forfeit procedure.</p>
<p>(a) For the purposes of this section, the term “post-and-forfeit procedure” shall mean the procedure enforced as part of the criminal justice system in the District of Columbia whereby a person charged with certain misdemeanors may simultaneously post and forfeit an amount as collateral (which otherwise would serve as security upon release to ensure the arrestee’s appearance at trial) and thereby obtain a full and final resolution of the criminal charge.</p>
<p>(b) The resolution of a criminal charge using the post-and-forfeit procedure is not a conviction of a crime and shall not be equated to a criminal conviction. The fact that a person resolved a charge using the post-and-forfeit procedure may not be relied upon by any court of the District of Columbia or any agency of the District of Columbia in any subsequent criminal, civil, or administrative proceeding or administrative action to impose any sanction, penalty, enhanced sentence, or civil disability.</p></blockquote>
<p>One thing that is apparent is that there is no admission or adjudication of guilt in the post-and-forfeit procedure and no judge imposes a punishment.</p>
<p>The federal district court in DC has also determined that the post-and-forfeit procedure does not involve a conviction. For example, in a recent case, the DC district court stated that “posting and forfeiting is not an admission of guilt, and it does not result in a criminal conviction.” <a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=9516433629804700761" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Fox v. District of Columbia</em>, 851 F. Supp. 2d 20, 25 (D.D.C. 2012)</a>. The court went on to explain that “the payment does not result in a criminal conviction and it cannot trigger any of the collateral consequences of a criminal conviction, [therefore] it is not appropriately likened to a criminal sentence.” <em>Id.</em> at 31.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/07/08/dc-post-and-forfeit-is-not-a-conviction-for-immigration-purposes/">DC Post-and-Forfeit Is Not A Conviction For Immigration Purposes</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">421</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lesser Included Offenses and Attempt</title>
		<link>/2012/09/09/lesser-included-offenses/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 19:14:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Criminal Law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Attempt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[District of Columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fraud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lesser Included Offense]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Statutory Interpretation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theft]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://new.theclementsfirm.com/?p=311</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In a recent case, the trial judge asked the parties for post-trial briefing on whether Second-Degree Theft is a lesser-included offense of Second-Degree Fraud in DC. A straight-forward question, I thought, and one I believed that the prosecution basically conceded by answering that in its view attempted second-degree theft is a lesser-included offense of second-degree &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2012/09/09/lesser-included-offenses/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Lesser Included Offenses and Attempt</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2012/09/09/lesser-included-offenses/">Lesser Included Offenses and Attempt</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a recent case, the trial judge asked the parties for post-trial briefing on whether Second-Degree Theft is a lesser-included offense of Second-Degree Fraud in DC. A straight-forward question, I thought, and one I believed that the prosecution basically conceded by answering that in its view <em>attempted</em> second-degree theft is a lesser-included offense of second-degree fraud.</p>
<p>Attempt is the prosecution&#8217;s catch-all for failure to prove necessary elements (other than intent), and in DC, prosecutors often charge attempt instead of certain felonies to deprive defendants of their rights to a jury trial. The only problem is that the attempt statute,&nbsp;D.C. Code §&nbsp;22-1803, limits its application to crimes that don&#8217;t already have a provision in the Code punishing the attempt. In other words, the attempt statute is not meant to replace more specific attempt offenses, and you can&#8217;t attempt to attempt to commit a crime.<span id="more-311"></span></p>
<p>The Supreme Court (in the wonderfully named <em><a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=12790155691285587220&amp;scilh=0">Schmuck v. US</a></em>) and the <a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=15746005502953545399&amp;scilh=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">D.C. Court of Appeals</a> apply an “elements” test to determine whether one offense is a lesser-included offense of another.&nbsp;“Under this test, one offense is not ‘necessarily included’ in another [and therefore a lesser-included offense] unless the elements of the lesser offense are a subset of the elements of the charged offense.”&nbsp;<em>Schmuck</em>, 489 U.S. at 716.&nbsp;A lesser-included offense is one such that “it is impossible to commit the greater without first having committed the lesser” so that the evidence required to prove the greater offense “would prove the lesser offense as a necessary element.”&nbsp;<em>Schmuck</em>, 489 U.S. at 719&nbsp;There is no requirement that the lesser-included offense incur a lesser sentence,&nbsp;so the fact that second-degree fraud and second-degree theft have the same maximum penalty does not decide the issue; the elements test is the sole consideration.</p>
<p>Examination of the respective elements of second-degree theft and second-degree fraud demonstrate that theft is not a lesser-included offense of fraud. For example, the second-degree theft statute (at D.C. Code §&nbsp;22-3212(b))&nbsp;states:</p>
<blockquote><p>“A person commits the offense of theft if that person wrongfully obtains or uses the property of another with intent:</p>
<p>(1) To deprive the other of a right to the property or a benefit of the property; or</p>
<p>(2) To appropriate the property to his or her own use or to the use of a third person.</p></blockquote>
<p>The D.C. Court of Appeals has elaborated that the essential elements of second-degree theft are that (1) the defendant wrongfully obtained property of another; (2) that at the time he obtained it, he specifically intended “either to deprive [the victim] of a right to the property or a benefit of the property or to take or make use of the property for [himself] &#8230; without authority or right”; and (3) that the property had some value.<a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=16943398911230210719&amp;scilh=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">&nbsp;<em>Price v. United States</em>, 985 A.2d 434, 436 (D.C. 2009).</a></p>
<p>By contrast, the second-degree fraud statute (D.C. Code §&nbsp;22-3221(b))&nbsp;states:</p>
<blockquote><p>A person commits the offense of fraud in the second degree if that person engages in a scheme or systematic course of conduct with intent to defraud or to obtain property of another by means of a false or fraudulent pretense, representation, or promise.</p></blockquote>
<p>The first thing apparent is that theft includes as a required element the obtaining of property, something not required to prove second-degree fraud. This is why the prosecution had to argue for <em>attempted</em> theft as the lesser included charge. By comparison, first-degree fraud adds this element, by adding “and thereby obtains property of another or causes another to lose property.” As <a href="http://koehlerlaw.net/assault-theft/theft-fraud/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">others have noted</a>, second-degree fraud in DC is basically attempted fraud.</p>
<p>Secondly, theft requires that at the time the defendant obtained the property, he or she intended to either deprive the owner of “a right to the property or a benefit of the property or to take or make use of the property . . . without authority or right.” DC Criminal Jury Instructions (Redbook) Instruction 5.300(2).&nbsp;This is not a requirement to a fraud charge, even when the defendant has obtained property through “a false or fraudulent pretense, representation, or promise.”&nbsp;One could be guilty of fraud even without intending to deprive the person from whom property was obtained of a benefit of that property, and may even have received authority or right to the property by the owner.</p>
<p>Now fraud has other elements that theft does not, such as the requirement that there be a scheme or pattern of conduct, and that there be false representations or trickery, etc., which is why the judge asked whether theft was a lesser-included offense of fraud.</p>
<p>I think even the prosecution would agree that second-degree theft is not a lesser-included offense of second-degree fraud, &nbsp;but unfortunately, the judge bought the argument that <em>attempted</em> 2d degree theft is. Crazy enough, I could find only one DC case (from 1963!) where the issue of whether the attempt statute could be applied to another offense that included attempt:&nbsp;<a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=7394727389692746994&amp;q=attempt+%22otherwise+made+punishable%22&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=4,9" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>United States v. Caviness</em>, 192 A. 2d 288 (DC 1963)</a>. I am hopeful that this conviction will be overturned on appeal (and thankfully, the defendant is not in jail while this is happening).</p>
<div>
<hr align="left" size="1" width="33%">
<div>
<p>The Attempt Statute, D.C. Code §&nbsp;22-1803, says:</p>
<blockquote><p>Whoever shall attempt to commit any crime, which attempt is not otherwise made punishable by chapter 19 of An Act to establish a code of law for the District of Columbia, approved March 3, 1901 (31 Stat. 1321), shall be punished by a fine not exceeding $1,000 or by imprisonment for not more than 180 days, or both. Except, whoever shall attempt to commit a crime of violence as defined in&nbsp;<a>§ 23-1331</a>&nbsp;shall be punished by a fine not exceeding $5,000 or by imprisonment for not more than 5 years, or both.</p></blockquote>
</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div><br clear="all"></p>
<div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2012/09/09/lesser-included-offenses/">Lesser Included Offenses and Attempt</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">311</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>9th Circuit Reiterates that BIA&#8217;s 30-Day Appeals Deadline is Non-Jurisdictional</title>
		<link>/2011/06/05/9th-circuit-reiterates-that-bias-30-day-appeals-deadline-is-non-jurisdictional/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2011 02:49:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[appeals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BIA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Statutory Interpretation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://new.theclementsfirm.com/wordpress/?p=124</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Please, no one take this as an excuse to blow off the Board of Immigration Appeals deadlines, but the 9th Circuit recently restated its holding that the BIA&#8217;s appeals deadline is not jurisdictional, overturning (in that circuit) the BIA&#8217;s attempted overruling of circuit precedent.  In a decision found here, the 9th Circuit called the 30-day &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2011/06/05/9th-circuit-reiterates-that-bias-30-day-appeals-deadline-is-non-jurisdictional/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">9th Circuit Reiterates that BIA&#8217;s 30-Day Appeals Deadline is Non-Jurisdictional</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2011/06/05/9th-circuit-reiterates-that-bias-30-day-appeals-deadline-is-non-jurisdictional/">9th Circuit Reiterates that BIA&#8217;s 30-Day Appeals Deadline is Non-Jurisdictional</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Please, no one take this as an excuse to blow off the Board of Immigration Appeals deadlines, but the 9th Circuit recently restated its holding that the BIA&#8217;s appeals deadline is not jurisdictional, overturning (in that circuit) the BIA&#8217;s attempted overruling of circuit precedent.  In a decision found <a href="http://www.metnews.com/sos.cgi?0611%2F07-71806" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>, the 9th Circuit called the 30-day deadline a &#8220;claim-processing rule&#8221; rather than a limit on jurisdiction.</p>
<p><span id="more-124"></span></p>
<p>The court noted that in its previous case, <em><a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=17492048931404309740&amp;q=Oh+v.+Gonzales&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=2,21" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Oh v. Gonzales</a></em>, it had held that the BIA&#8217;s position that it had no authority to accept a late filing was incorrect as a matter of law &#8220;because the BIA, despite its  &#8216;jurisdictional&#8217; argument, claimed authority to excuse late filings in  &#8216;rare circumstances.&#8217;  The Second Circuit had made a similar holding in <em><a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=5489537184331094306&amp;q=Zhong+Guang+Sun+v.+U.S.+Department+of+Justice.&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=2,21" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Zhong Guang Sun v. U.S. Department of Justice</a></em>.</p>
<p>After reviewing a number of Supreme Court decisions where court filing deadlines were treated as non-jurisdictional, the 9th Circuit noted that the BIA itself treated its appeals deadline as non-jurisdictional when it suited:</p>
<blockquote><p>Congress did not set the thirty-day time limit before us. It delegated to the agency the power to issue regulations with respect to the time period for filing. And the regulation does not say that it is jurisdictional. Nor does the agency itself treat the time limit as jurisdictional. Instead, the agency sua sponte decides to exercise its authority where the reasons for lateness are  “extraordinary,” something it could not do if the time limit was jurisdictional. By reviewing cases where the lateness is extraordinary, the agency interprets its own regulation as a non-jurisdictional claim-processing rule.</p></blockquote>
<p>The court went further and suggested that the Board should adopt e-filing, implying that by not adopting e-filing, the Board may be acting arbitrarily in applying its deadline, stating:</p>
<blockquote><p>The BIA argues that the alien should “file as far in advanceof the deadline as possible.” That answer is unsatisfactory because a person with fundamental interests at stake is entitled to certainty about when he must ask to be heard in order to get a hearing.</p>
<p>. . .</p>
<p>Just as we have for many decades assumed the availability of telephones, automobiles, and airplanes, we ought now toassume the availability of email and the internet when we assess the reasonableness of government action.</p></blockquote>
<p>This is an important decision &#8211; it will be interesting to see whether other circuits follow suit and how the BIA reacts.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2011/06/05/9th-circuit-reiterates-that-bias-30-day-appeals-deadline-is-non-jurisdictional/">9th Circuit Reiterates that BIA&#8217;s 30-Day Appeals Deadline is Non-Jurisdictional</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">124</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meeting the &#8220;public benefit&#8221; standard in FOIA attorney fees cases.</title>
		<link>/2011/04/13/meeting-the-public-benefit-standard-in-foia-attorney-fees-cases-pt-1/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2011 10:03:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Attorney Fees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FOIA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Public Benefit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Statutory Interpretation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://new.theclementsfirm.com/wordpress/?p=78</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In FOIA attorney fee cases, courts have created a false dichotomy between those requests for information that are in the public interest and those that further a private commercial interest, except those private commercial interests represented by mainstream media.  This distinction fails to consider that the commercial frequently becomes political.  For example, look at what &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2011/04/13/meeting-the-public-benefit-standard-in-foia-attorney-fees-cases-pt-1/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Meeting the &#8220;public benefit&#8221; standard in FOIA attorney fees cases.</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2011/04/13/meeting-the-public-benefit-standard-in-foia-attorney-fees-cases-pt-1/">Meeting the &#8220;public benefit&#8221; standard in FOIA attorney fees cases.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;">In FOIA attorney fee cases, courts have created a false dichotomy between those requests for information that are in the public interest and those that further a private commercial interest, except those private commercial interests represented by mainstream media.  This distinction fails to consider that the commercial frequently becomes political.  For example, look at what happened when Eller &amp; Co, a South Florida-based terminal and stevedoring company,  <a href="http://www.nti.org/e_research/e3_75.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">raised a stink</a> about becoming &#8220;involuntary partner&#8221; of DP World &#8211; the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dubai_Ports_World_controversy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Dubai Ports World Scandal</a>, ultimately leading to a vigorous debate on issues of national security in our ports.  The purpose of this post is to identify a principle that would allow a corporation or individual not involved in media to satisfy the public interest test for attorney fees.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span id="more-78"></span>To get attorney fees, an applicant must show that 1) she is &#8220;eligible&#8221; for an attorney fee award, and 2) she is &#8220;entitled&#8221; to such an award.  <em><a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?as_sdt=2,21&amp;case=11057826869401692458&amp;scilh=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> Church of Scientology of California v. Harris</a></em>, 653 F. 2d 584, 587 (D.C. Cir.1981).  The eligibility factor tests whether the petitioner &#8220;substantially prevailed&#8221; in obtaining documents through the FOIA litigation, which as I explained <a title="Plain text readings of EAJA and FOIA fee shifting statutes don’t tell the whole story: the test for FOIA attorney fees." href="http://new.theclementsfirm.com/wordpress/?p=49" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>, is defined by statute to mean documents either voluntarily disclosed as a result of the litigation, or ordered by a court to be disclosed.  <a href="http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/html/uscode05/usc_sec_05_00000552----000-.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">5 U.S.C. § 552(a)(4)(E)(ii)</a>.  Courts have added an additional requirement that the litigation have been &#8220;necessary&#8221; to obtain the requested documents.  <em>Church of Scientology</em>, 653 F.2d at 587-88.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">As discussed <a title="Plain text readings of EAJA and FOIA fee shifting statutes don’t tell the whole story: the test for FOIA attorney fees." href="http://new.theclementsfirm.com/wordpress/?p=49" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>, the entitlement showing is a court-created test that balances four factors:  (1) the benefit to the public, if any, derived from the case; (2) the commercial benefit to the complainant; (3) the nature of the complainant’s interest in the records sought; and (4) whether the government’s withholding of the records had a reasonable basis in law.  <em>Id.</em> The remainder of this post will discuss how the first factor, the public benefit test, has been applied in the DC federal courts.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">While &#8220;the release of any government document benefits the public by increasing citizens&#8217; knowledge of their government,&#8221; the courts have interpreted the legislative history of the FOIA attorney fees provision to narrow the &#8220;public benefit&#8221; to those cases &#8220;where the complainant&#8217;s victory is likely to add to the fund of information that citizens may use in making vital political choices.&#8221; <em><a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=3543079369645862057&amp;as_sdt=2,21" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Fenster v. Brown</a></em>, 617 F. 2d 740, 744 (D.C. Cir. 1979) (quoting <a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=11655075136199103521&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=2,21"><em>Blue v. Bureau of Prisons,</em> 570 F.2d 529 (5th Cir. 1978)</a>).  This &#8220;fund of information&#8221; test is no less nebulous than the general &#8220;public interest&#8221;, but seemed to have been intended to draw a line between the commercial and the political.  In <em>Fenster,</em> the district court noted that few copies of a released Defense Contractor Audit manual were sold; in approving the denial of attorney fees, the circuit court stated that because the manual helped contractors with audits, its release &#8220;basically furthers a private commercial, and not the general public, interest.&#8221;  <em>Fenster</em>, 617 F.2d at 745.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">In looking at the DP World Ports example, which I chose as an example precisely because I don&#8217;t believe that Eller &amp; Co had a FOIA case, if Eller had gotten documents through a litigated FOIA case, even though Eller&#8217;s motivation was to further a private interest, the general public certainly showed interest in the DP World issue.  Eller&#8217;s (hypothetical) actions &#8220;add[ed] to the fund of information that citizens may use in making vital political choices.&#8221;  Courts are supposed to look at commercial benefit and the complainant&#8217;s interest in elements (2) &amp;(3) of the entitlement test; the DP World example shows how the public interest could benefit even if elements (2) &amp; (3) pointed to a private commercial interest.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">The confusion in the courts among these elements seems to stem from the original confusion in the Senate Committee discussion of the public interest factor.  In <em><a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=7484198223662470092&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=2,21&amp;scilh=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Nationwide Bldg. Maintenance, Inc. v. Sampson</a></em>, 559 F. 2d 704, 712 (D.C. Cir. 1978), in reversing the district court to allow it to apply all entitlement factors, the court quoted from the Senate Committee discussion of the public interest factor:</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: left;">Under the first criterion a court would ordinarily award fees, for example, where a newsman was seeking information to be used in a publication or a public interest group was seeking information to further a project benefitting the general public, but it would not award fees if a business was using the FOIA to obtain data relating to a competitor or as a substitute for discovery in private litigation with the government.</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: left;">Senate Judiciary Committee Report on S. 2543, S.Rep. No. 93-854, at 19.   The court went on to describe some previous applications of the public interest standard:  those denied fees were individuals who sought information related to IRS disputes or their tax litigation (<em> </em><a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=17328429753195683734&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=2,21&amp;scilh=0"><em>Pope v. United States,</em> 424 F.Supp. 962 (S.D.Tex. 1977)</a>; <a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=12081820049633069313&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=2,21&amp;scilh=0"><em>Chamberlain v. Alexander,</em> 419 F.Supp. 235 (S.D.Ala. 1976)</a>); and individuals who sought information to gain commercial advantage in litigation (<a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=17353971802680473192&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=2,21&amp;scilh=0"><em>Kaye v. Burns,</em> 411 F.Supp. 897, 902 (S.D.N.Y. 1976)</a>); whereas &#8220;a television producer who had sought information for use in a public television documentary and a book&#8221; was granted attorney fees (<a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=13731140014486556686&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=2,21&amp;scilh=0"><em>Goldstein v. Levi,</em> 415 F.Supp. 303, 304-05 (D.D.C. 1976)</a>).</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Similar to those cases with individuals who sought documents relating to their tax disputes, in <em><a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=16115346186315863896&amp;q=Lasalle+Extension+University+v.+Federal+Trade+Commission&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=2,21" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LaSalle Extension University v. FTC</a></em>, 627 F. 2d 481 (D.C. Cir. 1980), the release of documents related to an FTC investigation of a distance learning institution was not considered in the public interest; nor was the release of documents related to an employee&#8217;s suit against the Smithsonian.  <em><a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=7299952484463998275&amp;as_sdt=2,21">Cotton v. Heyman</a></em>, 63 F. 3d 1115, 1120 (D.C. Cir. 1995) (&#8220;When a litigant seeks disclosure for a commercial benefit or other personal reasons, an award of fees is usually inappropriate.&#8221;).  In <em><a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=17654508628491440726&amp;as_sdt=2,21" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Barnard v. Dept. of Homeland Sec.</a></em>, 656 F. Supp. 2d 91, 99 (D.D.C. 2009), the court found that documents relating to whether DHS repeatedly detained the director of Physician&#8217;s Committee for Responsible Medicine for improper political reasons was not in the public interest because the plaintiff did not show that &#8220;the documents which were released yielded information that citizens could rely on in marking &#8216;vital political choices.'&#8221;  <em>Id.</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2011/04/13/meeting-the-public-benefit-standard-in-foia-attorney-fees-cases-pt-1/">Meeting the &#8220;public benefit&#8221; standard in FOIA attorney fees cases.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">78</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Judge Randolph&#8217;s Concurrence in Burka v US Dept. of Health and Human Services</title>
		<link>/2011/03/25/judge-randolphs-concurrence-in-burka-v-us-dept-of-health-and-human-services/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2011 01:33:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Attorney Fees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FOIA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Public Benefit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Statutory Interpretation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://new.theclementsfirm.com/wordpress/?p=57</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I have just started looking into FOIA Attorney Fees, and one thing I had found curious is that even though the statutory provision for attorney fees for FOIA applicants has fewer criteria than other provisions, such as EAJA, the courts have applied additional criteria to FOIA attorney fees, making an application MORE difficult.  I wrote &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2011/03/25/judge-randolphs-concurrence-in-burka-v-us-dept-of-health-and-human-services/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Judge Randolph&#8217;s Concurrence in Burka v US Dept. of Health and Human Services</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2011/03/25/judge-randolphs-concurrence-in-burka-v-us-dept-of-health-and-human-services/">Judge Randolph&#8217;s Concurrence in Burka v US Dept. of Health and Human Services</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have just started looking into FOIA Attorney Fees, and one thing I had found curious is that even though the statutory provision for attorney fees for FOIA applicants has fewer criteria than other provisions, such as EAJA, the courts have applied additional criteria to FOIA attorney fees, making an application MORE difficult.  I wrote about the statutes<a href="http://new.theclementsfirm.com/wordpress/?p=49"> here.</a></p>
<p>It seems I am not alone.  Judge Randolph wrote a concurrence in <em><a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=6651589681903229216&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=2&amp;as_vis=1&amp;oi=scholarr">Burka v. US Dept. of Health and Human Servs.</a></em>, 142 F. 3d 1286 (D.C. Cir. 1998) that raised the same concerns.  His concurrence argues much more eloquently than I could:<span id="more-57"></span></p>
<blockquote><p>RANDOLPH, Circuit Judge, concurring:</p>
<p>I join the court&#8217;s opinion in its application of <a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=13809078291952328068&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=2,21&amp;as_vis=1"><em>Kay v. Ehrler,</em> 499 U.S. 432, 111 S.Ct. 1435, 113 L.Ed.2d 486 (1991),</a> to deny this attorney-plaintiff attorney&#8217;s fees. I do so without endorsing the &#8220;criteria&#8221; we have devised for determining whether, in FOIA cases generally, attorney&#8217;s fees should be awarded. Maj. op. at 1288. Judge Wald thinks it significant that the four criteria are &#8220;deeply rooted&#8221; in the legislative history of FOIA. Concur. op. at 1293. I find it far more telling that those criteria were weeded out of the original Senate version of FOIA — where they would have had the binding force of law — and transplanted to the conference report — where they do not. Although we have applied these criteria in the past, they deserve another look. For instance, one of the factors is &#8220;the public benefit derived from the case.&#8221; <a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=6793283045689890879&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=2,21&amp;as_vis=1"><em>Chesapeake Bay Found., Inc. v. United States Dep&#8217;t of Agric.,</em> 11 F.3d 211, 216 (D.C.Cir.1993)</a>. Courts deciding an attorney&#8217;s fees dispute are not in a position to make that sort of judgment objectively. One person&#8217;s public good is often another person&#8217;s public harm. Besides, FOIA plaintiffs do not sue in the public interest; if anyone represents &#8220;the public&#8221; in these cases it is the United States or the agency defending the action. Making eligibility for a fee award turn on &#8220;public benefit&#8221; has a nice ring, but it is not tied to any language or policy of FOIA. Once a FOIA plaintiff receives the information sought from the government, he has no obligation to share it with &#8220;the public,&#8221; or with anyone else. What he plans to do with the documents has no bearing whatever on his right to receive them. I therefore cannot see why such a consideration should be relevant to whether he should recover attorney&#8217;s fees. If the &#8220;public good&#8221; did matter, the fact that the plaintiff plans to use the information for his &#8220;commercial benefit,&#8221; <em>id.,</em> should be a mark in favor of attorney&#8217;s fees. Competition and better products and services promote the public good. But our precedents count commercial benefit as a strike against an award — unless, perhaps, the plaintiff happens to be a &#8220;news organization.&#8221; <em>See, e.g., </em><a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=3525488000149372102&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=2,21&amp;as_vis=1"><em>Tax Analysts v. Department of Justice,</em> 965 F.2d 1092, 1095, 1096 (D.C.Cir.</a><a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=3525488000149372102&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=2,21&amp;as_vis=1"> 1992)</a>. We have also said that when a litigant seeks disclosure &#8220;for personal motives, an award of attorney&#8217;s fees is generally inappropriate.&#8221; <em>Id.</em> at 1095. This too is baffling. I suppose that any individual bringing a lawsuit has &#8220;personal motives.&#8221; On the other hand, it seems odd to attribute &#8220;personal motives&#8221; to a foundation or some other artificial entity. And so our law on attorney&#8217;s fees in FOIA cases is skewed against real people and in favor of organizations. This makes no sense. <em>See </em><a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=11865150436154650434&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=2,21&amp;as_vis=1"><em>Fogerty v. Fantasy, Inc.,</em> 510 U.S. 517, 534 n. 19, 114 S.Ct. 1023, 1033 n. 19, 127 L.Ed.2d 455 (1994)</a>. What also makes no sense is our continued use of this multi-factor, no weights assigned, test in the face of the different (and far simpler) standard supplied in the Equal Access to Justice Act, 28 U.S.C. § 2412. EAJA fits FOIA perfectly. It applies to cases in which the United States or an agency is a party and every FOIA case will be in that category. <em>Compare </em><a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=2238331265220046862&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=2,21&amp;as_vis=1"><em>Gray v. New England Tel. &amp; Tel. Co.,</em> 792 F.2d 251, 259 (1st Cir.1986),</a> refusing to borrow the EAJA standard in cases with private litigants on both sides of the dispute.</p>
<p>Judge Wald believes that &#8220;the purposes of the fee-shifting provisions of EAJA and of FOIA are different.&#8221; Concur. op. at 1292-93 n.1. She distinguishes between the two on the ground that EAJA is narrower and not designed to encourage litigation. <em>See</em> concur. op. at 1292-93 n.1. Yet she would require FOIA plaintiffs to fulfill three additional criteria that do not apply to plaintiffs seeking fees under EAJA,<sup>[1]</sup> frequently making it <em>harder</em> to qualify for an attorney&#8217;s fees award under FOIA than under EAJA. I find it more logical to join the First Circuit, which has concluded that there is &#8220;no fundamental difference&#8221; between the policies underlying EAJA&#8217;s and FOIA&#8217;s attorney&#8217;s fees provisions. <a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=15298150295660571702&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=2,21&amp;as_vis=1">Crooker v. EPA<em>, 763 F.2d 16, 17 (1st Cir.1985)</em></a><em>.</em></p>
<p><small></small><small></small>[1] Under both EAJA and FOIA, courts look to the merit of the Government&#8217;s litigating position in determining whether to award attorney&#8217;s fees. <em>Compare</em> 28 U.S.C. § 2412(d)(1)(A) (A court shall award fees unless the &#8220;position of the United States was substantially justified.&#8221;) <em>with</em> maj. op. at 1288 (The fourth factor to be weighed in determining whether fees should be awarded under FOIA is &#8220;whether the Government had a reasonable basis for withholding requested information.&#8221;).</p></blockquote>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2011/03/25/judge-randolphs-concurrence-in-burka-v-us-dept-of-health-and-human-services/">Judge Randolph&#8217;s Concurrence in Burka v US Dept. of Health and Human Services</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">57</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Plain text readings of EAJA and FOIA fee shifting statutes don&#8217;t tell the whole story: the test for FOIA attorney fees.</title>
		<link>/2011/03/23/plain-text-readings-of-eaja-and-foia-fee-shifting-statutes-dont-tell-the-whole-story-the-test-for-foai-attorney-fees/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2011 11:05:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Attorney Fees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FOIA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Statutory Interpretation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://new.theclementsfirm.com/wordpress/?p=49</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Although the statute for attorney fee awards in Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) cases has fewer conditions on such awards than the statutes for attorney fee awards in the Equal Access to Justice Act (EAJA), courts have imposed their own conditions on FOIA attorney fees that are stricter than those for EAJA.  In this post, I &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2011/03/23/plain-text-readings-of-eaja-and-foia-fee-shifting-statutes-dont-tell-the-whole-story-the-test-for-foai-attorney-fees/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Plain text readings of EAJA and FOIA fee shifting statutes don&#8217;t tell the whole story: the test for FOIA attorney fees.</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2011/03/23/plain-text-readings-of-eaja-and-foia-fee-shifting-statutes-dont-tell-the-whole-story-the-test-for-foai-attorney-fees/">Plain text readings of EAJA and FOIA fee shifting statutes don&#8217;t tell the whole story: the test for FOIA attorney fees.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<p>Although the statute for attorney fee awards in Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) cases has fewer conditions on such awards than the statutes for attorney fee awards in the Equal Access to Justice Act (EAJA), courts have imposed their own conditions on FOIA attorney fees that are stricter than those for EAJA.  In this post, I want to explore the difference between the two statutes and the court decisions dealing with them.<span id="more-49"></span></p>
<p>Contrary to what you may have heard about federal budget shortfalls, the federal government has almost unlimited resources to defend its agencies&#8217; actions in court (what do you think all those lawyers in Washington do?).  Under certain circumstances, however, Congress has provided for the award of <em>reasonable</em> attorneys fees to successful litigants in civil actions in federal court and in adversary administrative proceedings in the Equal Access to Justice Act (EAJA),<a title="28 U.S.C. 2412(d)" href="http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/html/uscode28/usc_sec_28_00002412----000-.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">28 U.S.C. § 2412(d)</a> &amp; <a title="5 USC 504" href="http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/html/uscode05/usc_sec_05_00000504----000-.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">5 U.S.C. § 504(a)</a>.  For example, <a title="28 U.S.C. 2412(d)" href="http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/html/uscode28/usc_sec_28_00002412----000-.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">28 U.S.C. § 2412(d)</a>(1)(A) says in relevant part:</p>
<blockquote><p>Except as otherwise specifically provided by statute, a court shall award to a prevailing party other than the United States fees and other expenses . . . incurred by that party in any civil action . . . brought by or against the United States . . ., unless the court finds that the position of the United States was substantially justified or that special circumstances make an award unjust.</p></blockquote>
<p>In most contested EAJA cases, the main question is whether the petitioner is a prevailing party and/or whether the position of the US was substantially justified.  To be entitled to EAJA attorney fees, the petitioner also must have a net worth &lt; $2,000,00.  28 U.S.C. § 2412(d)(2)(B).  [As an aside, the American Immigration Law Foundation has a great guide to obtaining EAJA attorney fees in the immigration context available <a title="AILF Guide to EAJA Attorney Fees" href="http://www.ailf.org/lac/pa/EAJA_Fees_04_07_06.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>.  I found this guide very useful in obtaining attorney fees after getting a client released from indefinite detention through a <a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=18207601054472606890&amp;q=hajbeh+loiselle&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=2,21" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">habeas action</a>.]</p>
<p>With regard to whether a party is the prevailing party, the Supreme Court settled a circuit split in <em>Buckhannon Board &amp; Care Home, Inc. v. West Virginia Department of Health &amp; Human Resources,</em> <a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?q=Buckhannon+Board+%26+Care+Home&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=2,21&amp;case=18016879269718488474&amp;scilh=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">532 U.S. 598 (2001)</a>, by holding that a &#8220;party that has failed to secure a judgment on the merits or a court-ordered consent decree, but has nonetheless achieved the desired result because the lawsuit brought about a voluntary change in the defendant&#8217;s conduct&#8221; is not a &#8220;prevailing party&#8221; in a decision that his been applied to EAJA and other federal statutes allowing courts to award attorney&#8217;s fees and costs to the &#8220;prevailing party.&#8221;</p>
<p>The FOIA attorney fees provision, on the other hand, does not have the language requiring the prevailing party to show that the government&#8217;s position was not substantially justified:</p>
<blockquote><p>The court may assess against the United States reasonable attorney fees and other litigation costs reasonably incurred in any case under this section in which the complainant has substantially prevailed.</p></blockquote>
<p><a href="http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/html/uscode05/usc_sec_05_00000552----000-.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">5 U.S.C. § 552(a)(4)(E)(i)</a>.  In addition, Congress responded to the <em>Buckhannon </em>decision in the FOIA context by passing the OPEN Government Act of 2007, adding the following definition of &#8220;substantially prevailed&#8221; to the FOIA attorney fees provision (but not to corresponding EAJA provisions):</p>
<blockquote><p>(ii) For purposes of this subparagraph, a complainant has substantially prevailed if the complainant has obtained relief through either—</p>
<div><a name="a_4_E_ii_I"></a>(I) a judicial order, or an enforceable written agreement or consent decree; or</div>
<div><a name="a_4_E_ii_II"></a>(II) a voluntary or unilateral change in position by the agency, if the complainant’s claim is not insubstantial.</div>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/html/uscode05/usc_sec_05_00000552----000-.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">5 U.S.C. § 552(a)(4)(E)(ii)</a>.  Now what I find <del>curious</del> frustrating is that although the FOIA statute seems on its face to allow for attorney fees in circumstances that EAJA does not, i.e., it does not have the requirement that the Government&#8217;s position not be substantially justified, court decisions have put greater limitations on FOIA awards than on EAJA.  For example, in the seminal DC Circuit case <em>Cuneo v. Rumsfeld, </em><a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=18348474621883284741&amp;q=Lasallle+Extension+University+v.+Federal+Trade+Commission&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=2,21&amp;scilh=0#r[4]" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">553 F. 2d 1360, 1364 (D.C. Cir. 1977)</a>, the court adopted a four-part test for FOIA attorney fee entitlement originally contained in the Senate version of the Bill, even though that test was not in the enacted version (!):</p>
<blockquote><p>(1) the benefit to the public, if any, derived from the case;<br />
(2) the commercial benefit to the complainant;<br />
(3) the nature of the complainant&#8217;s interest in the records sought; and<br />
(4) whether the government&#8217;s withholding of the records had a reasonable basis in law.</p></blockquote>
<p>The court read the test back into the statute through its reading of the legislative history, noting that the Conference report stated that &#8220;the conferees did not intend to make the award of attorney fees automatic or to preclude the courts, in exercising their discretion in awarding such fees, from taking such criteria into consideration.&#8221;  <em>Id. </em>I intend to go to the legislative history of the OPEN Government Act to see if there was any commentary on this test.  Another question in my mind is whether the EAJA or other statutes authorizing attorney awards against the government also contained likewise limiting intent (this will necessitate a visit to a good law library sometime in the near future).   In a future post, I will explore how this four-part test has been applied to FOIA applicants seeking attorney fees.</p>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2011/03/23/plain-text-readings-of-eaja-and-foia-fee-shifting-statutes-dont-tell-the-whole-story-the-test-for-foai-attorney-fees/">Plain text readings of EAJA and FOIA fee shifting statutes don&#8217;t tell the whole story: the test for FOIA attorney fees.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">49</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
