<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: The Barefoot Lawyer Breaks Down	</title>
	<atom:link href="/2020/09/03/the-barefoot-lawyer-breaks-down/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/2020/09/03/the-barefoot-lawyer-breaks-down/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 22:29:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: craignmoore		</title>
		<link>/2020/09/03/the-barefoot-lawyer-breaks-down/#comment-14991</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[craignmoore]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 22:29:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1869#comment-14991</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hi Noah--

I received word of your post via LinkedIn and was very happy about it.  I also have to say that your video both touched and moved me very much.  And I could not have agreed more with the sentiments you expressed.  I hope you and your family are enjoying a glorious New England summer. Truth be told, I am more than a little jealous (though I do not begrudge you one moment of joy).  My time will come soon enough.  What am I saying?  My time is virtually here--this retirement gig is great.  But, when Anne-Marie has finished in Super Court, I expect we too shall. be heading northward.  Homeward bound.  Until then or whenever, stay safe.  All the best, Craig]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi Noah&#8211;</p>
<p>I received word of your post via LinkedIn and was very happy about it.  I also have to say that your video both touched and moved me very much.  And I could not have agreed more with the sentiments you expressed.  I hope you and your family are enjoying a glorious New England summer. Truth be told, I am more than a little jealous (though I do not begrudge you one moment of joy).  My time will come soon enough.  What am I saying?  My time is virtually here&#8211;this retirement gig is great.  But, when Anne-Marie has finished in Super Court, I expect we too shall. be heading northward.  Homeward bound.  Until then or whenever, stay safe.  All the best, Craig</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
