<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Witnesses Archives - The Clements Firm</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/witnesses/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/tag/witnesses/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 01:56:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/cropped-TCFLogo012419White-1.png?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>Witnesses Archives - The Clements Firm</title>
	<link>/tag/witnesses/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21395931</site>	<item>
		<title>The Pitbull Cross-Examiner</title>
		<link>/2014/04/13/the-pitbull-cross-examiner/</link>
					<comments>/2014/04/13/the-pitbull-cross-examiner/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 21:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Criminal Law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jury Trials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Witnesses]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://new.theclementsfirm.com/?p=569</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s what everyone says they want &#8211; a pitbull on their side. I like pitbulls &#8211; they are intelligent, loving animals. However, that&#8217;s not the image that most people have in mind when thinking of lawyers or what they want &#8211; the picture that comes to mind is a vicious, dangerous killer that will not &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2014/04/13/the-pitbull-cross-examiner/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">The Pitbull Cross-Examiner</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2014/04/13/the-pitbull-cross-examiner/">The Pitbull Cross-Examiner</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s what everyone says they want &#8211; a pitbull on their side. I like pitbulls &#8211; they are intelligent, loving animals. However, that&#8217;s not the image that most people have in mind when thinking of lawyers or what they want &#8211; the picture that comes to mind is a vicious, dangerous killer that will not let go once it sets its teeth in. In the courtroom, this plays out as an attacking, caustic style, one I think is usually counterproductive.</p>
<p>The New York Times has a couple of pieces on <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/04/11/world/africa/oscar-pistorius-murder-trial.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the prosecutor</a> in the <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/04/14/world/africa/pistorius-murder-trial.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Oscar Pistorious trial</a> (I almost wrote <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D2dtEXzbKyU" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jaco Pastorius</a> &#8211; <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IjS9Y-T589g" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">he&#8217;s a different kind of killer</a>), who has earned <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/04/11/world/africa/oscar-pistorius-murder-trial.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">t</a>he nickname &#8220;Pit Bull.&#8221; His style has been described as &#8220;pugnacious&#8221; with &#8220;a reputation for abrasive, in-your-face cross-examination,&#8221; by turns &#8220;sarcastic, theatrical, skeptical and accusatory.&#8221; He has at times called the defendant a liar while testifying. Does this work?</p>
<p><iframe id="nyt_video_player" title="New York Times Video - Embed Player" src="http://graphics8.nytimes.com/bcvideo/1.0/iframe/embed.html?videoId=100000002818275&amp;playerType=embed" height="373" width="480" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<p><span id="more-569"></span></p>
<p>While Mr. Pistorious may end up convicted, I don&#8217;t think it will be because of the prosecutor&#8217;s &#8220;pitbull&#8221; cross-examination style. At one point in the trial, the judge reprimanded the prosecutor for &#8220;snickering&#8221; at the defendant&#8217;s answer, stating “You possibly think this is entertainment. It is not.” The judge has also warned him to stop calling Mr. Pistorious a liar while he is testifying (this would be grounds for a mistrial in the US). And the  South African Human Rights Commission has received a complaint that the prosecutor&#8217;s &#8220;persistent depiction of Mr. Pistorius as a liar infringed on the runner’s right to be presumed innocent and to have a fair trial.&#8221; (Only one?)</p>
<p>Look at the <a href="http://nyti.ms/1qxOWER" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">short video clip excerpt</a> of the second-day of cross-examination of Mr. Pistorious &#8211; do you think it&#8217;s effective? I thought Mr. Pistorious ended up looking much more sympathetic than he would have without the question.</p>
<p>Terry MacCarthy in <a href="http://www.amazon.com/MacCarthy-Cross-Examination-Terence/dp/1590318862/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1397424991&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=maccarthy+on+cross+examination" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">his book </a>on cross-examination says that while defendants and their families may appreciate the attacking cross, the jury &#8220;is muttering to themselves: &#8216;That guy [meaning you] is an ass.&#8221; A prosecutor may get away with it against a defendant, who is seen as deserving this treatment by dint of getting prosecuted. But it doesn&#8217;t seem to work for criminal defense lawyers except against the snitch.</p>
<p>There is a place for determined, aggressive work in criminal defense &#8211; in preparation. Just remember, vicious creatures get put down.</p>
<p><strong>UPDATE:</strong> My friend Jamison Koehler has a great post along the same lines on &#8220;<a href="http://koehlerlaw.net/2014/04/on-the-benefits-of-restraint-during-cross-examination/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Benefits of Restraint During Cross-Examination.</a>&#8221;</p>
<p><b>2nd UPDATE: </b>Master criminal defense lawyer Roy Black has <a href="http://www.royblack.com/blog/the-bull-dog-cross/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">an entirely different view</a> of the Pistorius cross-examination. Black says:</p>
<blockquote><p>Nel is a sarcastic SOB which I enjoy so long as he is not assaulting one of my clients. I have never seen a prosecutor as skilled in the art, but remember this was a judge trial. No rational prosecutor could do an assault like this in front of a jury. They would see it as too over bearing and smack of inspector Javert, but you can’t beat this for pure sadistic enjoyment.</p>
<p>. . . And his method is easy to grasp: He challenges every detail of the story, every claim, every dodge, every obfuscation.</p></blockquote>
<p>While it&#8217;s easy to see why my experiences in bullying a witness can differ from a prosecutor&#8217;s (i.e., the perception that the defendant deserves it), when Roy Black speaks or writes about cross-examination, it&#8217;s a good idea to pay attention. Black&#8217;s post is well worth studying to determine whether any of the techniques used by the prosecutor can be applied by a defense lawyer.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2014/04/13/the-pitbull-cross-examiner/">The Pitbull Cross-Examiner</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/04/13/the-pitbull-cross-examiner/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">569</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Police Officer&#8217;s Selective Memory in DUI Trial</title>
		<link>/2013/07/06/police-officers-selective-memory-in-dui-trial/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2013 18:14:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Criminal Law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DUI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[District of Columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DWI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OWI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Witnesses]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://new.theclementsfirm.com/?p=416</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I am working on an appeal from a DUI conviction. I enjoy reading other lawyers&#8217; trial transcripts seeing what works and doesn&#8217;t and coming up with ideas for my own trials. In DC, first offense DUI defendants are not entitled to a jury trial, which can be frustrating as many judges will accept what police &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2013/07/06/police-officers-selective-memory-in-dui-trial/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Police Officer&#8217;s Selective Memory in DUI Trial</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/07/06/police-officers-selective-memory-in-dui-trial/">Police Officer&#8217;s Selective Memory in DUI Trial</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am working on an appeal from a DUI conviction. I enjoy reading other lawyers&#8217; trial transcripts seeing what works and doesn&#8217;t and coming up with ideas for my own trials. In DC, first offense DUI defendants are not entitled to a jury trial, which can be frustrating as many judges will accept what police officers say as gospel, even when obviously &#8220;shading the truth&#8221; (that&#8217;s just a nice way of saying lying). Rarely, however, do I see an officer make it so obvious as the following when responding to questions about the procedures he followed in giving the Field Sobriety Tests:</p>
<blockquote><p>A. Are we going to go back and forth with another smoke screen? . . . You know, we’re going to go back and forth with these smokescreen questions. I’m just going to tell you I don’t recall.</p></blockquote>
<p><span id="more-416"></span>It&#8217;s bad enough that they bring in this pseudo-scientific hoakum (the field sobriety tests &#8211; the horizontal gaze nystagmus eye test, the walk-and-turn, and the one-leg-stand balance tests) as evidence of driving under the influence of alcohol, but then when a defense lawyer questions them on the actual procedures they used and how they compare to what they are supposed to do, you can get some variation of the above.</p>
<p>Reading the transcripts, it&#8217;s difficult to fault anything my colleague, a well-respected DUI lawyer, did. But I hope I would have not let that statement stand. In that passage, the cop is basically saying that if you ask me a question I think is a &#8220;smokescreen&#8221;, I am going to lie and say that I don&#8217;t remember. I would like to think that I would have had the presence of mind to press the officer on that: &#8220;So if I ask a question that you think is a smokescreen, you will tell me you don&#8217;t recall?&#8221; &#8220;Didn&#8217;t you swear to tell the truth?&#8221; &#8220;Just because someone can&#8217;t prove what you do and don&#8217;t recall, that doesn&#8217;t make it less of a lie does it?&#8221; I hope when I am in my next DUI trial and the officer says something like that, I will not let it stand.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/07/06/police-officers-selective-memory-in-dui-trial/">Police Officer&#8217;s Selective Memory in DUI Trial</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">416</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>In Drug Cases, Cross-Examine that &#8220;Expert&#8221;!</title>
		<link>/2013/01/03/in-drug-cases-cross-examine-that-expert/</link>
					<comments>/2013/01/03/in-drug-cases-cross-examine-that-expert/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 02:10:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Criminal Law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[District of Columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drug Cases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evidence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Felonies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jury Trials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Misdemeanors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pre-trial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scientific Evidence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Witnesses]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://new.theclementsfirm.com/?p=362</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I was in court just before the Christmas break, waiting for a chance to talk to the clerk, and I got to see part of a colleague&#8217;s misdemeanor marijuana possession trial. I was very disheartened to see that when it came time for the DEA chemist&#8217;s testimony, the defense lawyer did not challenge her qualifications, &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2013/01/03/in-drug-cases-cross-examine-that-expert/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">In Drug Cases, Cross-Examine that &#8220;Expert&#8221;!</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/01/03/in-drug-cases-cross-examine-that-expert/">In Drug Cases, Cross-Examine that &#8220;Expert&#8221;!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/photo-1.jpg?ssl=1"><img decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-371" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/photo-1.jpg?resize=300%2C224&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="300" height="224" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/photo-1.jpg?resize=300%2C224&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/photo-1.jpg?resize=1024%2C764&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/photo-1.jpg?w=1296&amp;ssl=1 1296w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a>I was in court just before the Christmas break, waiting for a chance to talk to the clerk, and I got to see part of a colleague&#8217;s misdemeanor marijuana possession trial. I was very disheartened to see that when it came time for the DEA chemist&#8217;s testimony, the defense lawyer did not challenge her qualifications, did not challenge the identification of the seized evidence as marijuana, and did not cross-examine the chemist <em>at all</em>, not even to have the chemist at least list the procedures performed, etc.<span id="more-362"></span></p>
<p>And unfortunately, this is the normal standard procedure: every day in courts around the country, defense lawyers play chicken with the government; the defense exercises its confrontation clause rights and insists that the government call the chemist hoping for a no-show, but doesn&#8217;t do anything when she does show. The government (and frankly, most judges) would prefer that we just trust the black box of its pseudo-science: this is X drug, because we, the experts, say so.</p>
<p>Civil lawyers intuitively know that experts are fallible, usually in favor of the party paying, and judges also know to treat expert testimony <em>in civil cases</em> with skepticism. But this skepticism goes out the window in criminal cases. If the forensic crime lab scandals of the past few years have taught us nothing else, it&#8217;s that we can&#8217;t trust the government&#8217;s &#8220;scientific experts&#8221; to be unbiased.   Defendants, our clients, deserve more.<!--more--></p>
<p>In the <a href="http://www.thetakeaway.org/2012/dec/03/crime-lab-chemist-allegedly-tampered-evidence-years/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">recent Massachusetts forensic</a> <a href="https://www.boston.com/news/local/massachusetts/2012/09/30/how-chemist-drug-lab-scandal-circumvented-safeguards/A29LZnAw1eW4hvjn4xX7rL/story.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">crime lab scandal</a>, <a href="http://www.masslive.com/news/index.ssf/2012/09/annie_dookhan_former_state_che.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Annie Dookhan</a>, a drug chemist, is believed to have falsified test results for many years &#8211; this chemist was responsible for the tests of 60,000 samples in 34,000 criminal cases. Many of those cases resulted in convictions (1,141 inmates have been identified so far). Could better cross-examination have helped uncover her fraud more quickly?</p>
<p>This is something that&#8217;s easy to question in hindsight, but it&#8217;s hard to see how we as defense lawyers can go wrong if we &#8220;QUESTION EVERYTHING&#8221;, as my new hero <a href="http://www.dctrafficattorney.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bryan Brown</a> says.*</p>
<p>So, where to start? Another new hero, <a href="http://www.themcshanefirm.com/pa-dui-attorneys/justin-j-mcshane/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Justin McShane</a>, <a href="http://www.thetruthaboutforensicscience.com/the-myth-of-specific-identification-of-marijuana-in-criminal-court-part-3-what-is-microscopic-morphological-examination-is-it-a-good-test/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">publishes</a> <a href="http://www.thetruthaboutforensicscience.com/the-myth-of-specific-identification-of-marijuana-in-criminal-court-part-4/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tons of free</a> <a href="http://www.thetruthaboutforensicscience.com/mass-spectroscopy-for-lawyers-part-9-other-topics-of-interest-in-gc-ms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">information on the science, or lack thereof</a>, behind drug testing. There&#8217;s lots of fodder for cross-examination there. I am finding that our local DEA lab doesn&#8217;t even want to disclose its practices and standards, so that&#8217;s something we get to fight about. I can also highly recommend Jim Shellow&#8217;s book, <a href="http://www.lexisnexis.com/store/catalog/booktemplate/productdetail.jsp?pageName=relatedProducts&amp;prodId=prod12340326" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Cross-Examination of the Analyst in Drug Prosecutions</a>. Shellow also wrote <a href="http://www.nacdl.org/Champion.aspx?id=22942" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">an article for the Champion</a> (membership req&#8217;d) suggesting that defense lawyers call analysts out for not using the computer matching that most GC/MS machines can do, but rely on subjective spectra matching. Shellow was cited by Scalia in the prophetic <a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=7136706767059629384&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=2&amp;as_vis=1&amp;oi=scholarr" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Melendez-Diaz v. Massachusetts</a> majority opinion.</p>
<p>The funny thing is that since I have started pushing on these issues, I can&#8217;t seem to get a drug case to trial. I&#8217;m not reading too much into it, but I can&#8217;t see how one can go wrong by being ready to force the government to prove its case. It&#8217;s what my clients want from me.</p>
<p>* Bryan Brown is one of the primary lawyers responsible for blowing the lid off of the <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2010/06/09/AR2010060906257.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">breathalyzer scandal in DC</a>, so to speak.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/01/03/in-drug-cases-cross-examine-that-expert/">In Drug Cases, Cross-Examine that &#8220;Expert&#8221;!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/01/03/in-drug-cases-cross-examine-that-expert/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">362</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Accomplice Corroboration Rule in Maryland</title>
		<link>/2011/05/26/the-accomplice-corroboration-rule-in-maryland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 08:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Criminal Law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-Defendants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Corroboration Rule]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evidence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Witnesses]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://new.theclementsfirm.com/wordpress/?p=117</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In criminal trials, a defendant is judged by people who weren&#8217;t there, didn&#8217;t see what happened, and usually have little experience with the type of crime involved.  What jury could resist testimony from someone who can definitively say that the defendant was guilty of the crime because they committed the crime together?  The accomplice can &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2011/05/26/the-accomplice-corroboration-rule-in-maryland/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">The Accomplice Corroboration Rule in Maryland</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2011/05/26/the-accomplice-corroboration-rule-in-maryland/">The Accomplice Corroboration Rule in Maryland</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In criminal trials, a defendant is judged by people who weren&#8217;t there, didn&#8217;t see what happened, and usually have little experience with the type of crime involved.  What jury could resist testimony from someone who can definitively say that the defendant was guilty of the crime because they committed the crime together?  The accomplice can say: &#8220;I was there,  I know all the details of what happened because I participated in the crime.  I&#8217;m sorry.  The defendant was there and did this too.&#8221;  The problem is that such testimony could be a lie motivated by the prospect of a more lenient sentence.   For that reason, in Maryland, as well as in many other states, convictions may not rest only on the uncorroborated testimony of an accomplice.  <a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=4848922481367091463&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=4,21" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Watson v. State,</em> 117 A.2d 549, 552 (Md. 1955)</a>,  [WARNING: the facts of some of these cases are quite gruesome, especially <em>Watson</em>].  In this post, I will explore what is called the accomplice corroboration rule as it has been applied in Maryland.  I want to explore a bit about what corroboration is required, what is an accomplice, etc..<span id="more-117"></span></p>
<p>The basis of many criminal procedure and evidentiary rules is that convictions should be supported by reliable evidence (where other criminal procedure rules exclude reliable evidence improperly obtained &#8211; both types of rules seek protect the public from the power of the state).    In <em>Watson</em>, the Maryland Court of Appeals described the problem with accomplice testimony as follows:</p>
<blockquote><p>The reason for the rule requiring the testimony of an accomplice to be  corroborated is that it is the testimony of a person admittedly  contaminated with guilt, who admits his participation in the crime for  which he particularly blames the defendant, and it should be regarded  with great suspicion and caution, because otherwise the life or liberty  of an innocent person might be taken away by a witness who makes the  accusation either to gratify his malice or to shield himself from  punishment, or in the hope of receiving clemency by turning State&#8217;s  evidence.</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Watson</em>, 117 A.2d at 552.  Because accomplice testimony usually does not exist without some promise made by the state, some commentators say that prosecutors who present such testimony should bear an extra burden to ensure its truth.  <em>E.g.</em>, Saverda, <em>Accomplices in Federal Court: the Case for Increased Evidentiary Standards</em>, 100 Yale L. J. 785 (1990), <em>available </em><a href="http://www.jstor.org/pss/796671" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here.</a> The Maryland Court of Appeals presented a survey of other states&#8217; rules on accomplice testimony in <a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=3608852777050582984&amp;q=corroboration+rule&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=4,21#[1]" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Brown v. State</em>, 378 A. 2d 1104 n.1 (Md. 1977)</a>.</p>
<p>There have been a number of cases that have turned on whether the witness was an accomplice.  <em> </em> An accomplice is someone who has voluntarily participated in the crime, either as a principle or as an <span style="text-decoration: underline;">accessory before the fact.</span> &#8220;The term `accomplice&#8217; does not include a person who has guilty  knowledge, or is morally delinquent, or who was even an admitted  participant in a related but distinct offense.&#8221;  <em>Coleman v. State</em>, 121 A. 2d 254,<a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=2170671110300352172&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=4,21&amp;kqfp=11890314658497784986&amp;kql=96&amp;kqpfp=2295347861267889148#kq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> 209 Md. 379, 385</a> (1956) (quoting 2 Wharton, <em>Criminal Evidence</em>, 229, Sec. 448, et seq. (12th Ed.)).  &#8220;The test for determining whether a person is an accomplice of a defendant charged with a felony is whether he could be indicted and punished for the crime charged against the defendant.&#8221;<em> <a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=4848922481367091463&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=4,21" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Watson</a></em><a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=4848922481367091463&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=4,21" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">, 117 A.2d at 552-53</a> (accessory after the fact not accomplice); <em>see also <a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=16907555573402155025&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=4,21" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Seward v. State</a></em><a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=16907555573402155025&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=4,21" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">, 118 A. 2d 505 (Md. 1955)</a> (boy who knew that other boys had bomb and intended to use it when he accompanied them and did not leave was accomplice); <a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=9229080724877252723&amp;q=corroboration+rule&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=4,21" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>In re Anthony W</em>, 879 A. 2d 717, 733-34</a> (Md. 2005) (boys who participated in theft and trespass not accomplices to separate crime of vandalism).</p>
<p>The next question is what corroboration is required.  The answer is &#8220;[n]ot much in the way of evidence corroborative of the accomplice&#8217;s testimony has been required.&#8221;  <a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=3608852777050582984&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=4,21" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Brown</em>, 378 A.2d 1104</a>.    Maryland Courts have held &#8220;only slight corroboration is required which would tend either: (1) to identify the defendant with the perpetrators of the crime, or; (2) to show the defendant&#8217;s participation in the crime.&#8221;  <em>Oliver v. State</em>, 454 A. 2d 856, 53 Md. App. 490, 505-06 (1983) (holding officer&#8217;s identification of defendant in close proximity to the crime is adequate corroboration).  That corroboration, however, does have to be from an independent source.  <a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=1820271961273750258&amp;q=corroboration+rule&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=4,21" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Turner v. State</em>, 452 A. 2d 416 (Md. 1982)</a> (holding that a witness testifying about the accomplice&#8217;s excited utterance is not corroboration).</p>
<p>And the courts are serious that the corroboration required is slight.  In <em>Collins v. State</em>, a <span style="text-decoration: underline;">death-penalty</span> case, the Court of Appeals held that a person who saw two black males leave the scene was sufficient corroboration of the accomplice&#8217;s story of the murder to support a death-penalty conviction (presumably the defendant was black).  <em>Collins v. State</em>, 568 A. 2d 1 (Md. 1990) (&#8220;While Gardner&#8217;s testimony in and of itself was not sufficient to substantiate Collins&#8217; participation in the robbery and subsequent murder, it does provide further corroborative evidence tending to connect Collins and Michie to the crime.&#8221;).  It&#8217;s hard to imagine slighter corroboration than &#8220;two black males.&#8221;</p>
<p>In another death-penalty case, a prison visitation card and a guard&#8217;s testimony that the accomplices visited the defendant in prison on the day that the accomplices stated that the defendant hired them to kill someone was sufficient corroboration to support a murder-for-hire conviction.  <a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=17656261630339775864&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=4,21&amp;kqfp=15689549306444375971&amp;kql=85&amp;kqpfp=18429928916369129697#kq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Grandison v. State</em>, 341 Md. 175 (Md. 1995)</a>.  This is slightly more than &#8220;two black males&#8221;, but not much.</p>
<p>While I haven&#8217;t found any decision explicitly stating so, the Court of Appeals&#8217; discussion in <em>Anthony W.</em> seems to assume that having multiple accomplices testify does not satisfy the corroboration requirement, <em>Anthony W.</em>, 879 A.2d at 722, 730, as did the Court of Special Appeals (an intermediate appellate court in Maryland). <a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=16695160865501122175&amp;q=corroboration+rule&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=4,21" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">859 A. 2d 679, 682</a> (Md. Ct. of Spec. App. 2004).  This would make sense as adding another witness with incentive to lie does not add reliable evidence.</p>
<p>I would welcome any pointers and/or other examples of evidence allowed to fulfill the requirements of the accomplice corroboration rule in Maryland.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2011/05/26/the-accomplice-corroboration-rule-in-maryland/">The Accomplice Corroboration Rule in Maryland</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">117</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
