<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Felonies Archives - The Clements Firm</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/felonies/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/tag/felonies/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 01:56:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/cropped-TCFLogo012419White-1.png?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>Felonies Archives - The Clements Firm</title>
	<link>/tag/felonies/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21395931</site>	<item>
		<title>Special Counsel&#8217;s Questionable Testimony in Support of DC&#8217;s Draconian Liquid PCP Possession Penalties</title>
		<link>/2013/09/02/special-counsels-questionable-testimony-in-support-of-dcs-draconian-liquid-pcp-possession-penalties/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 22:16:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Criminal Law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[District of Columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drug Cases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Felonies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Washington]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://new.theclementsfirm.com/?p=397</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Unlike every other drug you can (illegally) possess in the District, the D.C. Council has made possession of any amount of liquid PCP a felony punishable by up to 3 years and/or $3000 fine.* In part, this was because the D.C. Council felt that PCP is a more dangerous drug than other so-called &#8220;hard drugs,&#8221; &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2013/09/02/special-counsels-questionable-testimony-in-support-of-dcs-draconian-liquid-pcp-possession-penalties/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Special Counsel&#8217;s Questionable Testimony in Support of DC&#8217;s Draconian Liquid PCP Possession Penalties</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/09/02/special-counsels-questionable-testimony-in-support-of-dcs-draconian-liquid-pcp-possession-penalties/">Special Counsel&#8217;s Questionable Testimony in Support of DC&#8217;s Draconian Liquid PCP Possession Penalties</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Unlike every other drug you can (illegally) possess in the District, the D.C. Council has made possession of any amount of liquid PCP a felony punishable by up to 3 years and/or $3000 fine.* In part, this was because the D.C. Council felt that PCP is a more dangerous drug than other so-called &#8220;hard drugs,&#8221; in that the Council believes that:</p>
<blockquote><p>Although a person might commit a crime related to heroin or cocaine (usually a robbery to obtain the money to purchase the heroin or cocaine), individuals often commit crimes <em>because</em> they are on PCP. PCP give users the feeling of strength and invulnerability.</p></blockquote>
<p>Obviously, the D.C. Council has collectively forgotten the &#8217;80&#8217;s and the heyday of powder cocaine. Anyway, the D.C. Council then goes on to list several bizarre crimes committed on PCP as testified to by Patricia Riley, special council to the U.S. Attorney for D.C. Ms. Riley testified that:</p>
<blockquote><p>A friend I talked to about this testimony this morning remembered a case where a man stabbed his girlfriend 57 times. I remember a case where a woman put her baby in the microwave and turned it on.</p></blockquote>
<p>There was no support or testimony about any actions Ms. Riley may have taken to verify that these acts actually occurred. Unsupported urban legends don&#8217;t belong in sworn testimony to the D.C. Council.<span id="more-397"></span></p>
<p>While there have been a <a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/8301-504083_162-20064806-504083.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">couple</a> of <a href="http://www.foxnews.com/us/2011/06/21/calif-mom-arrested-after-baby-dies-in-microwave/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">cases</a> where a <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/local/daily/sept99/microwave.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">woman</a> microwaved a baby, and a <a href="http://abclocal.go.com/ktrk/story?section=news/local&amp;id=6017940" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">few</a> <a href="http://www.foxnews.com/story/0,2933,303736,00.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">more</a> where a <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2008/mar/27/usa.internationalcrime1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">man</a> was <a href="http://www.examiner.com/article/father-puts-baby-microwave-says-he-was-drunk-and-high" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">involved</a>, none had any link to PCP (although <a href="http://www.examiner.com/article/father-puts-baby-microwave-says-he-was-drunk-and-high" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">one case</a> where a man put his baby in the microwave after smoking pot all day and splitting a fifth of whiskey with his girlfriend claimed that the marijuana may have been laced with PCP or another hallucinogen). I could find absolutely no news articles about a man stabbing her girlfriend 57 times while high on PCP &#8211; one would expect this to make the news, no? But why let truth get in the way of a good story?</p>
<p>Ms. Riley also listed case studies of crimes involving PCP, which presumably were more fact based (I am not going to check each one), but that does not excuse the fact that she felt the need to testify to the above unsupported horror stories to get the Council to pass this draconian law.</p>
<p>Anyway, I certainly don&#8217;t support PCP or other drug use, but I don&#8217;t judge it either (unless you&#8217;re one of my children, in which case, Bad Kiddie!). But the fact is, no drug compares to alcohol when considering involvement in violent crime. <a href="http://www.ncadd.org/index.php/learn-about-alcohol/alcohol-and-crime">The National Council on Alcoholism and Drug Dependence</a> reports, based on a review of DOJ statistics, that alcohol is involved in 40% of all violent crime in the U.S. But we ignore the link between alcohol and crime because we tried that unsuccessfully in Prohibition.</p>
<p>The real reason for the extra-harsh penalties for possession of liquid PCP is that the D.C. Council believes that liquid PCP is more consistent with distribution than use, but doesn&#8217;t want to make prosecutors have to prove it.  Notwithstanding its recounting of the horrors committed by PCP users, the D.C. Council says that its action &#8220;should not be considered as a bill to punish users.&#8221; The Council stated its belief that &#8220;sellers typically carry liquid, [but] users typically carry one or two dippers.&#8221; This shows that the D.C. Council intended to incorporate an unrebuttable presumption that a person possessing liquid PCP intended to distribute, a presumption that results in unconstitutional burden shifting to defendants.</p>
<p>* These are maximum penalties, not the likely penalties; as a felony, sentencing would most likely follow the <a href="http://acs.dc.gov/acs/frames.asp?doc=/acs/lib/acs/pdf/2013_Voluntary_Sentencing_Guidelines_Manual.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">sentencing guidelines</a>, which would recommend 6-18 months (some or all of which could be suspended) for conviction for possession of liquid PCP for a person with very little criminal history. By contrast, simple possession of other drugs, including PCP in any other form (powder, dipper, etc.) is a misdemeanor with a maximum sentence of 180 days (also not the likely sentence in many cases).</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/09/02/special-counsels-questionable-testimony-in-support-of-dcs-draconian-liquid-pcp-possession-penalties/">Special Counsel&#8217;s Questionable Testimony in Support of DC&#8217;s Draconian Liquid PCP Possession Penalties</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">397</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Need For Discretion</title>
		<link>/2013/06/09/the-need-for-discretion/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 00:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Criminal Law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crime Involving Moral Turpitude]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Criminal Immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[District of Columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Felonies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Immigration Court]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maryland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Removal Defence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Washington]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://new.theclementsfirm.com/?p=399</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Recently, in browsing a well-known local lawyer&#8217;s website, I found the following &#8220;News&#8221; article on their blog: Attorney X convinced a [local] prosecutor to dismiss Armed Robbery charges, all felonies, and all gun charges, despite the defendant being caught nearly red-handed with a shotgun in his fleeing vehicle. The defendant plead to Second Degree Assault, &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2013/06/09/the-need-for-discretion/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">The Need For Discretion</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/06/09/the-need-for-discretion/">The Need For Discretion</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Recently, in browsing a well-known local lawyer&#8217;s website, I found the following &#8220;News&#8221; article on their blog:</p>
<blockquote><p>Attorney X convinced a [local] prosecutor to dismiss Armed Robbery charges, all felonies, and all gun charges, despite the defendant being caught nearly red-handed with a shotgun in his fleeing vehicle.</p>
<p>The defendant plead to Second Degree Assault, a misdemeanor, giving him a strong chance to avoid certain deportation that he would have faced with any felony or gun charge. He will be eligible for parole in one month.</p></blockquote>
<p>While there may be some ethical concern over publicizing past successes without adequately informing potential clients that there is no guarantee of such success in any particular case, that is not my main concern. The biggest problem with this self-serving news article is that it may harm the client in the future.<span id="more-399"></span></p>
<p>What if the ICE Assistant Chief Counsel (the title of immigration prosecutors) in a future deportation case against that client stumbles across this &#8220;article&#8221;? Unfortunately, it would be all too easy for the ICE prosecutor to find. Can the admission by the client&#8217;s attorney be used to try to form the requisite admission of facts?</p>
<p>The fact that this article is not part of the official record of conviction does not end the inquiry &#8211; admission of underlying facts can also be used to show that a conviction is one that leads to removability or deportation. The client would then be in the position of arguing that although his attorney may have admitted the underlying facts, he did not do so himself. Would that argument be successful? I don&#8217;t think anyone knows at this point, but it&#8217;s much better to avoid the situation altogether.</p>
<p>And this situation is avoidable. Is it so important to promote the practice that the attorney should put this up in the first place? Is this attorney hoping that other potential clients &#8220;caught nearly red-handed&#8221; with guns in their fleeing cars will think the attorney will also get them off?</p>
<p>I think a potential client would be better served in knowing that no matter what the alleged facts in their case, the attorney will never divulge them to serve the attorney&#8217;s own interests. They should not be divulged at any time except to the extent that it might help the client.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/06/09/the-need-for-discretion/">The Need For Discretion</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">399</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why It&#8217;s Important To Get Drug Lab Info In Drug Cases</title>
		<link>/2013/03/12/why-its-important-to-get-drug-lab-info-in-drug-cases/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 07:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Criminal Law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[District of Columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drug Cases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evidence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Felonies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jury Trials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Misdemeanors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scientific Evidence]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://new.theclementsfirm.com/?p=381</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>To live up to its name, forensic science must conform to the scientific method, which the Oxford English Dictionary defines as “consisting in systematic observation, measurement, and experiment, and the formulation, testing, and modification of hypotheses.” The scientific method seeks above all to prove or disprove hypotheses through testing in order to determine whether a particular &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2013/03/12/why-its-important-to-get-drug-lab-info-in-drug-cases/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Why It&#8217;s Important To Get Drug Lab Info In Drug Cases</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/03/12/why-its-important-to-get-drug-lab-info-in-drug-cases/">Why It&#8217;s Important To Get Drug Lab Info In Drug Cases</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>To live up to its name, forensic science must conform to the scientific method, which the Oxford English Dictionary defines as “consisting in systematic observation, measurement, and experiment, and the formulation, testing, and modification of hypotheses.” The scientific method seeks above all to prove or disprove hypotheses through testing in order to determine whether a particular conclusion is reliable. If recent history has taught us anything, it&#8217;s that forensic science often falls short of this ideal. But we as criminal defense lawyers can&#8217;t expose these failings without better information on lab procedures. I have written about cross-examining drug experts <a title="In Drug Cases, Cross-Examine that “Expert”!" href="http://new.theclementsfirm.com/?p=362">here</a>.<span id="more-381"></span></p>
<p>The DEA laboratory used by the District of Columbia seems to fight tooth and nail to keep any information that could be used to test or verify its reliability out of the hand of criminal defense lawyers. Without this information, we cannot effectively cross-examine drug analysts. Therefore, it&#8217;s very important to fight just as hard to try to get this info.</p>
<p>The National Academy of Sciences (in an essential report you can get <a href="https://www.ncjrs.gov/pdffiles1/nij/grants/228091.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>) has stated that there are two very important questions that should be answered to determine whether particular forensic science evidence should be admitted and relied upon in criminal trials:</p>
<blockquote><p>(1) the extent to which a particular forensic discipline is founded on a reliable scientific methodology that gives it the capacity to accurately analyze evidence and report findings and</p>
<p>(2) the extent to which practitioners in a particular forensic discipline rely on human interpretation that could be tainted by error, the threat of bias, or the absence of sound operational procedures and robust performance standards.<a title="" href="#_ftn1"><br />
</a></p></blockquote>
<p>The Supreme Court, in <a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=7136706767059629384&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=2&amp;as_vis=1&amp;oi=scholarr" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><i>Melendez-Diaz v. Massachusetts</i></a>, quoted the NRC Report at length and recognized that “ forensic scientists . . . sometimes face pressure to sacrifice appropriate methodology for the sake of expediency.” “Confrontation is designed to weed out not only the fraudulent analyst, but the incompetent one as well.” Is it a coincidence that the laboratory at issue in this case is the same one that has since been the subject of scandal after it found two analysts who falsified test results? (These two analysts are <a href="http://www.masslive.com/news/index.ssf/2012/09/annie_dookhan_former_state_che.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Annie Dookhan</a> and  <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2013/01/20/justice/massachusetts-chemist-charged/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sonja Frank</a>).</p>
<p>The Court further noted that there is “wide variability across forensic science disciplines with regard to techniques, methodologies, reliability, types and numbers of potential errors, research, general acceptability, and published material.” The Court recognized that “[c]onfrontation is one means of assuring accurate forensic analysis,” and the one means guaranteed by the Sixth Amendment, but surely confrontation regarding techniques, reliability, and how a forensic analyst applied the particular prescribed methodology can only be effective if that information is disclosed to the defense. At the very least, criminal defense lawyers should try to get the following:</p>
<div>
<p><b><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Standard Operating Procedures, Protocols, and Methods</span></b></p>
<p>Defense access to standard operating procedures and methodologies is important both to allow defense counsel to test the reliability of the standard procedures and methods, and to determine whether the testifying analyst actually followed the standard procedures. These are two main questions identified by the NRC Report as determining the reliability of specific forensic evidence.</p>
<p>Other authorities agree, stating “publication of a laboratory&#8217;s work product and data used in . . . analysis, as well as independent replication and validation studies, are essential prerequisites to reliability.”  <a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?q=State+v.+Schwartz,+447+N.W.+2d+422&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=2,21&amp;case=1711603818802243408&amp;scilh=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>State v. Schwartz</em></a>, 447 N.W. 2d 422, 428 (Minn. Sup. Ct. 1989) (citing standards set out by the Technical Working Group on DNA Analysis Methods, a group of 31 scientists coordinated by the FBI). Some commentators suggest that laboratory protocols should be publicly available and even placed on the internet. P. Giannelli, E. Imwinkelried, et al., 1 <a href="http://www.lexisnexis.com/store/catalog/booktemplate/productdetail.jsp?pageName=relatedProducts&amp;prodId=7575" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Scientific Evidence</a> §3.02, p. 160 (5th ed., Dec. 2012).<a title="" href="#_ftn3"><br />
</a></p>
<p>“[N]o one disputes that the procedures such an expert actually employs are discoverable.” <a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?q=cole+v.+state,+835+a.2d+600&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=2,21&amp;case=18337717452595120703&amp;scilh=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><i>Cole v. State</i></a>, 835 A. 2d 600, 609 (Md. Ct. of App., 2003). While some methods may be theoretically valid, a particular analysis may fall short. Giannelli and Imwinkelried paraphrase the late scientific expert Melvin Lewis as saying:</p>
<blockquote><p>“It is no more correct to say that (GC/MS) detects (a drug) than to say that a violin produces music. Unfortunately, it is much easier for unsound scientific opinion to appear valid than for the product of an incompetently manipulated violin to sound euphonic.” <a title="" href="#_ftn5"><br />
</a></p></blockquote>
<p><b><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Proficiency Reports, Calibration and Maintenance Records</span></b></p>
<p>Proficiency reports should be discoverable as they are important to help the court determine the weight to give to the forensic analyst’s conclusions. As the court explained in <em>Cole</em>:</p>
<blockquote><p>The calibration record for the machine the chemist used and the chemist&#8217;s own proficiency testing records with regard to the specific testing devices and written procedures are potentially relevant to the case because an improperly calibrated machine or a machine operated by a chemist who was not proficient in its use could lead to an inaccurate result.”<a title="" href="#_ftn7"><br />
</a></p></blockquote>
<div>
<p>Requesting laboratory information is not a panacea, however. In my recent experience, DC prosecutors have amended charges to &#8220;attempted&#8221; possession rather than producing this information &#8211; in &#8220;attempted&#8221; possession, the government doesn&#8217;t have to prove that the seized substance is an illegal drug, but it does have to prove that the defendant intended to possess a drug.</p>
<p>In some cases, such as where the government is going on a theory of &#8220;constructive&#8221; possession (the drugs aren&#8217;t seen on the defendant, but the government claims defendant has control of them), this raises the burden of proof on the prosecutors a bit. This may put the defense in a better position for trial or make the prosecutors more willing to give a better plea offer. There&#8217;s nothing to be lost in asking for this lab info, and much that can be gained.</p>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/03/12/why-its-important-to-get-drug-lab-info-in-drug-cases/">Why It&#8217;s Important To Get Drug Lab Info In Drug Cases</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">381</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>In Drug Cases, Cross-Examine that &#8220;Expert&#8221;!</title>
		<link>/2013/01/03/in-drug-cases-cross-examine-that-expert/</link>
					<comments>/2013/01/03/in-drug-cases-cross-examine-that-expert/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 02:10:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Criminal Law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[District of Columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drug Cases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evidence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Felonies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jury Trials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Misdemeanors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pre-trial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scientific Evidence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Witnesses]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://new.theclementsfirm.com/?p=362</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I was in court just before the Christmas break, waiting for a chance to talk to the clerk, and I got to see part of a colleague&#8217;s misdemeanor marijuana possession trial. I was very disheartened to see that when it came time for the DEA chemist&#8217;s testimony, the defense lawyer did not challenge her qualifications, &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2013/01/03/in-drug-cases-cross-examine-that-expert/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">In Drug Cases, Cross-Examine that &#8220;Expert&#8221;!</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/01/03/in-drug-cases-cross-examine-that-expert/">In Drug Cases, Cross-Examine that &#8220;Expert&#8221;!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/photo-1.jpg?ssl=1"><img decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-371" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/photo-1.jpg?resize=300%2C224&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="300" height="224" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/photo-1.jpg?resize=300%2C224&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/photo-1.jpg?resize=1024%2C764&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/photo-1.jpg?w=1296&amp;ssl=1 1296w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a>I was in court just before the Christmas break, waiting for a chance to talk to the clerk, and I got to see part of a colleague&#8217;s misdemeanor marijuana possession trial. I was very disheartened to see that when it came time for the DEA chemist&#8217;s testimony, the defense lawyer did not challenge her qualifications, did not challenge the identification of the seized evidence as marijuana, and did not cross-examine the chemist <em>at all</em>, not even to have the chemist at least list the procedures performed, etc.<span id="more-362"></span></p>
<p>And unfortunately, this is the normal standard procedure: every day in courts around the country, defense lawyers play chicken with the government; the defense exercises its confrontation clause rights and insists that the government call the chemist hoping for a no-show, but doesn&#8217;t do anything when she does show. The government (and frankly, most judges) would prefer that we just trust the black box of its pseudo-science: this is X drug, because we, the experts, say so.</p>
<p>Civil lawyers intuitively know that experts are fallible, usually in favor of the party paying, and judges also know to treat expert testimony <em>in civil cases</em> with skepticism. But this skepticism goes out the window in criminal cases. If the forensic crime lab scandals of the past few years have taught us nothing else, it&#8217;s that we can&#8217;t trust the government&#8217;s &#8220;scientific experts&#8221; to be unbiased.   Defendants, our clients, deserve more.<!--more--></p>
<p>In the <a href="http://www.thetakeaway.org/2012/dec/03/crime-lab-chemist-allegedly-tampered-evidence-years/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">recent Massachusetts forensic</a> <a href="https://www.boston.com/news/local/massachusetts/2012/09/30/how-chemist-drug-lab-scandal-circumvented-safeguards/A29LZnAw1eW4hvjn4xX7rL/story.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">crime lab scandal</a>, <a href="http://www.masslive.com/news/index.ssf/2012/09/annie_dookhan_former_state_che.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Annie Dookhan</a>, a drug chemist, is believed to have falsified test results for many years &#8211; this chemist was responsible for the tests of 60,000 samples in 34,000 criminal cases. Many of those cases resulted in convictions (1,141 inmates have been identified so far). Could better cross-examination have helped uncover her fraud more quickly?</p>
<p>This is something that&#8217;s easy to question in hindsight, but it&#8217;s hard to see how we as defense lawyers can go wrong if we &#8220;QUESTION EVERYTHING&#8221;, as my new hero <a href="http://www.dctrafficattorney.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bryan Brown</a> says.*</p>
<p>So, where to start? Another new hero, <a href="http://www.themcshanefirm.com/pa-dui-attorneys/justin-j-mcshane/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Justin McShane</a>, <a href="http://www.thetruthaboutforensicscience.com/the-myth-of-specific-identification-of-marijuana-in-criminal-court-part-3-what-is-microscopic-morphological-examination-is-it-a-good-test/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">publishes</a> <a href="http://www.thetruthaboutforensicscience.com/the-myth-of-specific-identification-of-marijuana-in-criminal-court-part-4/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tons of free</a> <a href="http://www.thetruthaboutforensicscience.com/mass-spectroscopy-for-lawyers-part-9-other-topics-of-interest-in-gc-ms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">information on the science, or lack thereof</a>, behind drug testing. There&#8217;s lots of fodder for cross-examination there. I am finding that our local DEA lab doesn&#8217;t even want to disclose its practices and standards, so that&#8217;s something we get to fight about. I can also highly recommend Jim Shellow&#8217;s book, <a href="http://www.lexisnexis.com/store/catalog/booktemplate/productdetail.jsp?pageName=relatedProducts&amp;prodId=prod12340326" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Cross-Examination of the Analyst in Drug Prosecutions</a>. Shellow also wrote <a href="http://www.nacdl.org/Champion.aspx?id=22942" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">an article for the Champion</a> (membership req&#8217;d) suggesting that defense lawyers call analysts out for not using the computer matching that most GC/MS machines can do, but rely on subjective spectra matching. Shellow was cited by Scalia in the prophetic <a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=7136706767059629384&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=2&amp;as_vis=1&amp;oi=scholarr" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Melendez-Diaz v. Massachusetts</a> majority opinion.</p>
<p>The funny thing is that since I have started pushing on these issues, I can&#8217;t seem to get a drug case to trial. I&#8217;m not reading too much into it, but I can&#8217;t see how one can go wrong by being ready to force the government to prove its case. It&#8217;s what my clients want from me.</p>
<p>* Bryan Brown is one of the primary lawyers responsible for blowing the lid off of the <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2010/06/09/AR2010060906257.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">breathalyzer scandal in DC</a>, so to speak.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/01/03/in-drug-cases-cross-examine-that-expert/">In Drug Cases, Cross-Examine that &#8220;Expert&#8221;!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/01/03/in-drug-cases-cross-examine-that-expert/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">362</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
