<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Estate Planning Archives - The Clements Firm</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/estate-planning/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/category/estate-planning/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 05:17:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/cropped-TCFLogo012419White-1.png?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>Estate Planning Archives - The Clements Firm</title>
	<link>/category/estate-planning/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21395931</site>	<item>
		<title>The Barefoot Lawyer Breaks Down</title>
		<link>/2020/09/03/the-barefoot-lawyer-breaks-down/</link>
					<comments>/2020/09/03/the-barefoot-lawyer-breaks-down/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 18:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beach Walk and Talk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Estate Planning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1869</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>There are bigger issues in the world than whether a family can keep and share their summer home together. But having a place to nurture and develop family ties and increase love is important too. I believe that hurt people hurt people. The answer is always more love. And family summer homes are a place &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2020/09/03/the-barefoot-lawyer-breaks-down/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">The Barefoot Lawyer Breaks Down</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2020/09/03/the-barefoot-lawyer-breaks-down/">The Barefoot Lawyer Breaks Down</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>There are bigger issues in the world than whether a family can keep and share their summer home together. But having a place to nurture and develop family ties and increase love is important too. I believe that hurt people hurt people. The answer is always more love. And family summer homes are a place to nurture that love. </p>



<p> </p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe class="youtube-player" width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8DIXUpnGG-o?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2020/09/03/the-barefoot-lawyer-breaks-down/">The Barefoot Lawyer Breaks Down</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2020/09/03/the-barefoot-lawyer-breaks-down/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1869</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Taking a Moment to Reflect</title>
		<link>/2019/06/11/taking-a-moment-to-reflect/</link>
					<comments>/2019/06/11/taking-a-moment-to-reflect/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Caroline Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 18:27:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beach Walk and Talk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Estate Planning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1674</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I was given the pleasure of attending a baptism on Sunday. The pastor encouraged us to think of other baptisms we had been to and the memories that evoked. &#160;Reflecting on our childrens’ baptism, it became interesting to me what came to mind first. We baptized our three children and the memories I have of &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2019/06/11/taking-a-moment-to-reflect/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Taking a Moment to Reflect</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/06/11/taking-a-moment-to-reflect/">Taking a Moment to Reflect</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>I was given the pleasure of attending a baptism on Sunday. The pastor encouraged us to think of other baptisms we had been to and the memories that evoked. &nbsp;Reflecting on our childrens’ baptism, it became interesting to me what came to mind first.<br></p>



<p>We baptized our three children and the memories I have of each hold a special place in my heart. &nbsp;They were baptized in three different churches in three different cities and the families members present were different each time.<br></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/1999-04-04-Wiley-Michael.jpg?resize=230%2C204&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1687" width="230" height="204" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/1999-04-04-Wiley-Michael.jpg?resize=1024%2C907&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/1999-04-04-Wiley-Michael.jpg?resize=300%2C266&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/1999-04-04-Wiley-Michael.jpg?resize=768%2C680&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/1999-04-04-Wiley-Michael.jpg?w=1068&amp;ssl=1 1068w" sizes="(max-width: 230px) 100vw, 230px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>Michael &amp; Wiley</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Our oldest, Wiley was baptized at St. Michael&#8217;s in New York City.  Both of my sisters and Noah’s brother and sister came to the city for the event.  Wiley was the first niece and this was the first event.  The memory that stands out the most for me involved a battle between Noah and his brother Michael.  Wiley was wearing the baptismal gown that I had worn when I was baptized. </p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/1999-04-03-Wiley-baptism-Steph-Kate.jpg?resize=213%2C170&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1688" width="213" height="170" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/1999-04-03-Wiley-baptism-Steph-Kate.jpg?resize=1024%2C816&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/1999-04-03-Wiley-baptism-Steph-Kate.jpg?resize=300%2C239&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/1999-04-03-Wiley-baptism-Steph-Kate.jpg?resize=768%2C612&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/1999-04-03-Wiley-baptism-Steph-Kate.jpg?w=1343&amp;ssl=1 1343w" sizes="(max-width: 213px) 100vw, 213px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>Stephanie, Kate &amp; Wiley</figcaption></figure></div>



<p> It was a silk gown of several layers and very slippery. Noah insisted on carrying her throughout the ceremony, he was the only one to hold her.  Being the Godfather that he was, Michael tried hard to take a turn, but Noah was not having it.  The gown made her slippery to hold and as the father he was going to hold her.  Makes me chuckle, twenty years later to remember these brothers vying for the privilege of holding the baby.<br></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2001-12-30-Eric-baptism.jpeg?resize=302%2C166&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1689" width="302" height="166" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2001-12-30-Eric-baptism.jpeg?resize=1024%2C564&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2001-12-30-Eric-baptism.jpeg?resize=300%2C165&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2001-12-30-Eric-baptism.jpeg?resize=768%2C423&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2001-12-30-Eric-baptism.jpeg?w=1559&amp;ssl=1 1559w" sizes="(max-width: 302px) 100vw, 302px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>Rick, Nan, Wiley &amp; Eric</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Our son Eric was baptized at Church of the Holy Family in Chapel Hill, NC.  My brother and his wife came to town for the ceremony.  The memory that stands out the strongest from his baptism happened at the end.  After the anointment, the priest raised Eric up above his head and carried him down the aisle.  The act was like that of Simba’s baptism in Lion King where Rafiki presents Simba to the herd. For those of you who have not met my baby boy, he is now 6’7”.  Eric has definitely grown to be a very big boy and can now be seen above a crowd without being held up.<br></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2015-01-01-Elise-Michael-noses.jpg?resize=239%2C219&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1691" width="239" height="219" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2015-01-01-Elise-Michael-noses.jpg?resize=1024%2C944&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2015-01-01-Elise-Michael-noses.jpg?resize=300%2C276&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2015-01-01-Elise-Michael-noses.jpg?resize=768%2C708&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2015-01-01-Elise-Michael-noses.jpg?w=1072&amp;ssl=1 1072w" sizes="(max-width: 239px) 100vw, 239px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>Michael &amp; Elise</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Our sweet Elise was baptised at St.Phillip’s in Durham, NC. &nbsp;Noah’s brother and his wife came for the ceremony.  She was baptised at the Easter Vigil mass and all I can remember was that there were candles and Michael let Elise hold the candle herself. &nbsp;She was three (older than the others at baptism) wearing a white flower girl dress that had become her trademark gown and pink cowgirl boots.  Her independence and desire to participate with the adults was shining through even then.<br></p>



<p>Reflection is such an amazing thing. &nbsp;It gives space for those memories, the smile and the sadness. &nbsp;<br></p>



<p>As I chuckle that Noah and Michael were having a brotherly competition at Wiley’s baptism, my heart hurts knowing that now that Michael has passed there will be no more brotherly competition between those two. &nbsp;<br></p>



<p>Remembering Eric being held up above the priests head brings a smile to face.  My heart aches a bit knowing that my baby boy has grown up.   It is time for him to tackle his own challenges.  <br></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2015-02-18-Elise-Ashley-pool.jpg?resize=274%2C226&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1690" width="274" height="226" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2015-02-18-Elise-Ashley-pool.jpg?w=931&amp;ssl=1 931w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2015-02-18-Elise-Ashley-pool.jpg?resize=300%2C248&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2015-02-18-Elise-Ashley-pool.jpg?resize=768%2C635&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 274px) 100vw, 274px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>Ashley &amp; Elise</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>As sweet Elise sat next to me in the pew on Sunday,  I told her about the candles at her baptism.  At three she had to hold it herself just as she likes to always hold the hymnal now.  A few tears rolled down my cheeks as I realized that her godparents Michael and Ashley were now watching over her from heaven.<br></p>



<p>In the work that Noah and I are doing I am privileged to listen to clients’ reflections. &nbsp;To hear what the important memories are for them.  Some make me laugh out loud and some are sad. &nbsp;All are beautiful.<br></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/06/11/taking-a-moment-to-reflect/">Taking a Moment to Reflect</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2019/06/11/taking-a-moment-to-reflect/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1674</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Working with a coach</title>
		<link>/2019/06/04/working-with-a-coach/</link>
					<comments>/2019/06/04/working-with-a-coach/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Caroline Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 20:32:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beach Walk and Talk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Estate Planning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1666</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>When Noah and I made the decision to start working together we hired a business coach. &#160;Having a neutral third party to assist us in building the business has been crucial. We had a coaching call this morning and the focus was on marketing, specifically setting up educational presentations. &#160; We begin each coaching session &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2019/06/04/working-with-a-coach/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Working with a coach</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/06/04/working-with-a-coach/">Working with a coach</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2019-06-02-NC-presentationjpg.jpg?resize=215%2C287&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1667" width="215" height="287" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2019-06-02-NC-presentationjpg.jpg?resize=768%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2019-06-02-NC-presentationjpg.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1 225w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2019-06-02-NC-presentationjpg.jpg?resize=350%2C467&amp;ssl=1 350w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2019-06-02-NC-presentationjpg.jpg?w=849&amp;ssl=1 849w" sizes="(max-width: 215px) 100vw, 215px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p>When Noah and I made the decision to start working together we hired a business coach. &nbsp;Having a neutral third party to assist us in building the business has been crucial.  We had a coaching call this morning and the focus was on marketing, specifically setting up educational presentations. &nbsp;<br></p>



<p>We begin each coaching session discussing how we feel about our business.  Followed by a recap of what new steps we took over the last month.  After going through the metrics her conclusion was for me to book presentations.  That I should be making 10 phone calls a day to places inquiring if they had educational events.  This was not the first time we had discussed me making phone calls and yet I have only made one call.  My resistance to doing this has not been a secret.<br></p>



<p>When our coach began questioning me why I haven’t made the calls, I went into panic. &nbsp;My body immediately went into a textbook response of: fight, flight, freeze mode.  I was unable to identify the thought that was leading to the feeling of panic, however the emotion was coming on strong and I began to shutdown. &nbsp;Noah immediately stepped in as my savior offering to make the calls.  Without skipping a beat he began asking who should be called, while simultaneously doing a Google search of potential locations near our office.  That’s how Noah works, jumping right in to get more information as quickly as possible.<br></p>



<p>Our coach took a step back and began discussing the rationale. &nbsp;She validated that I have been successful at one-to-one connection and have been increasing our contacts. She also pointed out that I hit the weekly newsletter goal she had set in February. &nbsp;In May I wrote four blogs and sent newsletters weekly for the first time. Our newsletters have a good open rate (thank you for reading and learning more about us) and we are increasing our house list.<br></p>



<p>Part of my job is the marketing and with that the responsibility of setting up presentations.  We ended the call with 3 actions items.   One involves me making these 10 calls  a day with a goal of setting up two presentations.<br></p>



<p>After the call Noah went to meet a chamber member for coffee and I sat down to mediate and journal. &nbsp;Taking 30 minutes to center myself, I ended with a list of the things I like about working with Noah.  <br></p>



<p>I like that we spend more time together now then we have for the 24 years we have known each other.  I like that we are learning to really enjoy spending time together.  I like that we are learning new things together.   We have been to some really interesting lunch-and-learns and the communication training we went to in Colorado was fantastic.  I like that we are talking to families together, bringing our different skills together and listening in a new way.  We have always known that we are different, opposites in so many ways.  </p>



<p>However, I like that we are now being given a space to practice working together.  We are using our differences to cover all of the bases.  Long ago a therapist pointed out that we make decisions differently.  He used a pie analogy to explain this.  We can split the pie in half or work together to have the whole pie .  We are using the whole pie perspective to help families make some really hard decisions, I like that.<br></p>



<p>We hired a coach to help us keep our vision and make clear goals to reach it.  She also pushes us to make those goals.  If Noah had been the one, and he has, to suggest I make the calls, it would have decreased my enjoyment of working with him.  We are making a lot of changes working together and my job description has changed dramatically.  With the guidance of our coach I will continue to grow as I have with attending networking lunches and writing.</p>



<p>So, I don’t like making phone calls. &nbsp;Once I post this blog, I am going to make some anyway.<br></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/06/04/working-with-a-coach/">Working with a coach</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2019/06/04/working-with-a-coach/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1666</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Where to start planning if you have a special needs child?</title>
		<link>/2019/05/10/where-to-start-planning-if-you-have-a-special-needs-child/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 20:28:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Estate Planning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Special Needs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1581</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The best time to plant a tree is 25 years ago, the second-best time is right now. Supposedly, an ancient Chinese proverb, but who knows? It can be overwhelming. Figuring out how to get the care and services for your special needs child is incredibly difficult; figuring out how to pay for it can be &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2019/05/10/where-to-start-planning-if-you-have-a-special-needs-child/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Where to start planning if you have a special needs child?</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/05/10/where-to-start-planning-if-you-have-a-special-needs-child/">Where to start planning if you have a special needs child?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="768" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_6809.jpg?resize=1024%2C768&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1582" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_6809.jpg?resize=1024%2C768&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_6809.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_6809.jpg?resize=768%2C576&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_6809.jpg?resize=350%2C263&amp;ssl=1 350w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>What is a picture of words worth?<br></figcaption></figure></div>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>The best time to plant a tree is 25 years ago, the second-best time is right now.</p><cite>Supposedly, an ancient Chinese proverb, but who knows?</cite></blockquote>



<p>It can be overwhelming. Figuring out how to get the care and services for your special needs child is incredibly difficult; figuring out how to pay for it can be even more difficult. And then add in the effort of being a caregiver. The prospect of planning to provide for all of your child&#8217;s needs when something happens can be scary. How are you going to do it?</p>



<p>First, let&#8217;s not freak out too much. Yes, there are many things to think about, <a href="/services/special-needs-planning/">estate planning</a> techniques we can help you with, etc. But we can also just start where we are. Why not just start with opening an ABLE account? You don&#8217;t need a lawyer for that.</p>



<p>ABLE stands for Achieving a Better Life Experience (cool acronym) and an ABLE account is basically a special kind of state-run investment account that allows families of people with special needs to save money for them, and grow it tax-free, without jeopardizing their ability to receive government benefits. What 529 accounts are to college savings, ABLE accounts are to special needs. Florida&#8217;s ABLE account is called <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="ABLE United (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.ableunited.com/" target="_blank">ABLE United</a> and you can find out about it <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="ABLE United (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.ableunited.com/" target="_blank">here.</a> </p>



<p>As I said above, the earnings in ABLE accounts grow tax-free, and some states will allow a tax-deduction for contributions to those states&#8217; ABLE plans. That doesn&#8217;t help Florida residents as we have no state income tax, but if you have family members in a state like <a href="https://mi.db101.org/mi/programs/job_planning/able/program.htm" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Michigan (opens in a new tab)">Michigan</a>, which does, and <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="which allows tax deductions for ABLE account contributions (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.miable.org/FAQ.php#Question13" target="_blank">which allows tax deductions for ABLE account contributions</a>, they can get a tax deduction for helping provide for your special needs child.</p>



<p>As I noted above, you don&#8217;t need a <a href="/services/special-needs-planning/">special needs </a>or <a href="/services/estate-planning/">estate planning</a> lawyer to set up an ABLE account. That said, we are here to help.</p>



<a href="https://app.acuityscheduling.com/schedule.php?owner=17212147&#038;appointmentType=9159871" target="_blank" class="acuity-embed-button" style="background: #002e5d; color: #fff; padding: 8px 12px; border: 0px; -webkit-box-shadow: 0 -2px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15) inset;-moz-box-shadow: 0 -2px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15) inset;box-shadow: 0 -2px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15) inset;border-radius: 4px; text-decoration: none; display: inline-block;" rel="noopener noreferrer">Schedule Call with Caroline</a><link rel="stylesheet" href="https://embed.acuityscheduling.com/embed/button/17212147.css" id="acuity-button-styles" /><script src="https://embed.acuityscheduling.com/embed/button/17212147.js" async></script>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/05/10/where-to-start-planning-if-you-have-a-special-needs-child/">Where to start planning if you have a special needs child?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1581</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Juxtapose</title>
		<link>/2019/04/16/juxtapose/</link>
					<comments>/2019/04/16/juxtapose/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Caroline Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 22:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beach Walk and Talk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Estate Planning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1561</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>While sitting in church this last Sunday, listening to the Palm Sunday sermon, the significance of this juxtaposition that occurs in so many areas of life struck me. In the Christian faith, this week is a time where the excitement and joy of togetherness and celebration is juxtaposed with the devastation of loss. Conflicting thoughts &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2019/04/16/juxtapose/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Juxtapose</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/04/16/juxtapose/">Juxtapose</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/2019-04-15-beachwalk.jpg?resize=337%2C450&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1562" width="337" height="450" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p>While sitting in church this last Sunday, listening to the Palm Sunday sermon, the significance of this juxtaposition that occurs in so many areas of life struck me. In the Christian faith, this week is a time where the excitement and joy of togetherness and celebration is juxtaposed with the devastation of loss. Conflicting thoughts and feelings are felt at the same time. I am often one to avoid that level of intense feelings. My thoughts centered with this idea of intense feelings caused by a conflicting series of events.  </p>



<p>As Noah mentioned in <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.facebook.com/theClementsFirm/videos/2595636767329903/" target="_blank">his recording</a>, when we got the call that his Grandfather would be moving into Hospice recently, he immediately asked our children if they would like to accompany him, and then he bought plane tickets to fly to California. This is an action Noah has taken several times. He flew to Miami when Michael and Ashley were in the fatal car accident in 2006. He flew to Miami again to help move his father into in-home Hospice in 2009. He flew to Durham, NC when his mother was moved to Hospice in 2017, the same place where he spent a year as she received her double lung transplant 5 years prior. And when we got the call that Michael was in ICU in January 2018, again he flew to Miami to spend the last month with his brother.</p>



<p>During each of these times, we knew of the heartache that was meeting Noah on the other side of the flight, yet each time I encouraged him to get on the plane and go.  Each time I stayed home with our children, doing my best to keep life moving forward. Each time the lives of others changed dramatically. Each time Noah strengthened relationships as he felt the loss of one.</p>



<p>Life presents such complexity and sad sweetness to show up for loss and at the same time to build stronger connection in other relationships. How can the event of losing a loved one also be a conduit for bringing those left behind together and strengthening the connections they share?  </p>



<p>I am aware that it is a total gift that Noah has been able to be there for each of these events. It is not a given that loved ones will come together during these times. Nor is it a given that connection will be made during these times. Just because you are in the same room it does not guarantee that connection will be made. As we learned during our recent workshop in Colorado, connection requires honest safe sharing where participants feel validation and acceptance, and feel heard and understood.</p>



<p>The <a href="/services/estate-planning/">estate planning </a>work Noah and I are doing <a href="/2019/03/18/building-connection-can-estate-planning-improve-relationships/">helps families have more connection.</a> We are aware that times of loss often bring about a lot of hurt feelings, defensiveness and assumptions which all decrease connection. I encourage you to attend <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Noah’s presentation on the 25th (opens in a new tab)" href="https://theclementsfirm.as.me/EPWorkshop" target="_blank">Noah’s presentation on the 26th</a> to hear more about how you can help your family.</p>



<p>I experienced the intense conflicting thoughts and feelings for each of these trips that Noah made. Looking at this last trip to see his Grandfather, I am so grateful he went. The trip was full of sadness but also the strength of coming together with his cousins to share memories and also the gift of being together.</p>



<p>As you are pulled into sadness over loss (it happens to all of us), I encourage you to look for those beautiful moments. For me it was the blue canary by the pool that stayed all day when Ashley passed. It was the “life party” Noah&#8217;s father insisted on having before he passed to see all his old friends. It was knowing Noah, Michael and Grace were together with Ricky in her final moments. It was knowing whether or not Grace was having dinner with her brothers based on the choice of barbecue restaurant. It is here with the connection we have formed with Melissa’s family after Michael’s passing, and the warmth and guidance we are receiving from this tight knit group. And finally, it was the tales of Noah&#8217;s cousins singing old folk songs for Grandpa Sid.</p>



<p>Yes there is a lot of sadness, but there are also the most beautiful of memories. I am learning to sit with the conflicting feelings. And as Noah said at Michael’s funeral, “share your stories of loved ones often.” I’d love to have you make me smile with a beautiful memory &#8211; please share one with me.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/04/16/juxtapose/">Juxtapose</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2019/04/16/juxtapose/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1561</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Building Connection &#8211; Can Estate Planning Improve Relationships?</title>
		<link>/2019/03/18/building-connection-can-estate-planning-improve-relationships/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 15:21:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Estate Planning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1486</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Caroline has been weeding out old pictures. There&#8217;s a good reason for it: we don&#8217;t have much room and the picture books are falling apart. But looking through old pictures of family and friends can stir bittersweet feelings of love and loss. Mad Men&#8217;s Don Draper had it right: family pictures spin us &#8220;around and &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2019/03/18/building-connection-can-estate-planning-improve-relationships/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Building Connection &#8211; Can Estate Planning Improve Relationships?</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/03/18/building-connection-can-estate-planning-improve-relationships/">Building Connection &#8211; Can Estate Planning Improve Relationships?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image alignleft"><img decoding="async" width="480" height="360" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/2006-Austin-family-BnW.jpg?resize=480%2C360&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-699" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/2006-Austin-family-BnW.jpg?w=480&amp;ssl=1 480w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/2006-Austin-family-BnW.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/2006-Austin-family-BnW.jpg?resize=350%2C263&amp;ssl=1 350w" sizes="(max-width: 480px) 100vw, 480px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p>Caroline has been weeding out old pictures. There&#8217;s a good reason for it: we don&#8217;t have much room and the picture books are falling apart. But looking through old pictures of family and friends can stir bittersweet feelings of love and loss. Mad Men&#8217;s Don Draper had it right: family pictures spin us &#8220;around and around and back home again to a place where we know we are loved.&#8221; </p>



<p>If you&#8217;re like me, when looking at old pictures, you’re likely reminded of just how important our relationships are. And as we grow older, you begin to realize how precious little time we have to spend with one another.</p>



<p>For me, the big wakeup call was after our oldest daughter started high school. I felt like I had very little personal relationship with her and knew that she would be leaving home in just a few short years. I really wanted to have my own connection with our children, not just through Caroline. </p>



<p>I&#8217;m sure many fathers are better about it. But I didn&#8217;t feel like I had that connection, even though I went to all school events, was around, etc. Luckily, I got the advice to start setting individual dates/outings with each of my children. At these dates, we would do whatever <em>they</em> wanted, not just inviting them to what I thought would be fun. And I started driving them around to their stuff, even if sometimes it drives me crazy. I have come to understand that &#8220;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.ahaparenting.com/parenting-tools/connection/building-relationship" target="_blank">quality time is a myth, because there’s no switch to turn on closeness</a>.&#8221;</p>



<p>An older friend told me recently that he thought that we&#8217;re never as close with our children as when we just listen to them, without judgment. Caroline recently <a href="/2019/03/13/what-is-family/">wrote about family</a> and it got me thinking about how our work fits into that vision. A large part of my efforts to improve my relationships is to be more open in my relationships and all my communications. And my training in estate planning is a large part of that. </p>



<p>The <a href="/services/estate-planning/">estate planning</a> coaches I use wrote about 4 ways that they claim estate planning can improve relationships with your loved ones. They claim that not only do we &#8220;experience a huge sense of relief and peace,&#8221; knowing we have put a comprehensive plan in place, but that &#8220;estate planning also has the potential to enhance your relationship with loved ones in some major ways.&#8221; They say</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>the [estate planning] process can be the ultimate forum for heartfelt communication and prioritizing what matters most in life. Indeed, communicating clearly about what you want to happen in the event of your incapacity or death (and asking your loved ones what they want to happen) can foster a deeper bond and sense of intimacy than just about anything else you can do.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Who doesn&#8217;t want that? So let&#8217;s look at the claims and see if estate planning can improve the relationships we cherish most:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p><strong>1) It shows you sincerely care</strong></p>



<p>Taking the time and effort to carefully plan for what will happen to you in the event of your incapacity or when you die is a genuine demonstration of your love. It would be far easier to do nothing and simply let you family and friends figure it out for themselves. After all, you won’t be around to deal with any of the fallout.</p>



<p>Planning in advance, though, shows that you truly care about the welfare of your loved ones, even when you’re no longer around to benefit from their love and companionship.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Some people truly don&#8217;t want to be bothered about what will happen to their families after they&#8217;re gone. Perversely, there are some who relish the thought of their loved ones fighting over their assets when they are gone (as if they were fighting over them). And some can&#8217;t or won&#8217;t face the prospect of being incapacitated, and what that would mean for the people who care for them. My father used to say &#8220;I won&#8217;t be a burden, just put me out in a small boat so I can sail off.&#8221; As if that was some type of realistic plan. But that&#8217;s not us &#8211; and it&#8217;s not you if you&#8217;re reading this. </p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p><strong>2) It inspires honest communication about difficult issues</strong></p>



<p>Sitting down and having an honest discussion about life’s most taboo subjects—incapacity and death—is almost certain to bring you and your loved ones closer. By forcing you to face mortality together, planning has a way of highlighting what’s really important in life—and what’s not. </p>



<p>In fact, the estate planning process can help you feel more connected with the people you love the most. And planning helps clarify for many people the lives they want to live during the short time we have here on earth.  </p>
</blockquote>



<p>Both of these things have certainly happened for me. While these discussions can be uncomfortable, I think our relationships benefit from being open about our feelings and intentions. </p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p><strong>3) It builds a deep sense of trust and respect</strong></p>



<p>Whether it’s the individuals you name as your children’s legal guardians or those you nominate to handle your own end-of-life care, estate planning shows your loved ones just how much you trust and admire them. . . .</p>



<p>Though it’s often challenging to verbally express how much you love your family and friends, estate planning demonstrates your affection in a truly tangible way. </p>
</blockquote>



<p>I think this is a beautiful sentiment. Sometimes the guardians chosen may not want the responsibility &#8211; and make no mistake, it is a great responsibility. But in those cases, it is better to know beforehand. </p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p><strong>4) It creates a lasting legacy</strong></p>



<p>Estate planning is primarily viewed as a way to pass on your financial wealth and property. However, it can offer your loved ones much more than just financial security. When done right, it lets you hand down the most precious assets of all—your life stories, lessons, and values.</p>



<p>In fact, the wisdom and experience you’ve gained during your lifetime are among the most treasured gifts you can give. </p>
</blockquote>



<p>When it comes to legacy, I believe that the examples we set speak louder than any words we can say. There&#8217;s no substitute for creating memories. My family is lucky to have members in it who have put in a lot of effort to put together letters and memory books. Caroline often creates photo books for family members as gifts. However, I also wish I had recordings of my parents, my brother, and other loved ones who have passed. </p>



<p>So we have developed a service to help pass on our legacy. With this service, we guide you to create a recording in which you share your most insightful memories and experiences.  </p>



<p><strong>The heart of the matter</strong><br>We can help guide and support you in having these intimate discussions with your loved ones. Planning can enrich your family and friends with far more than just material wealth.</p>



<p>With our help, <strong><a href="/services/estate-planning/">estate planning </a></strong>doesn’t have to be a dreary affair. When done right, it&#8217;s more about putting your life and relationships in clearer focus. Ultimately planning can be a tremendously uplifting experience for everyone involved. Contact us today to learn more.</p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">If you haven&#8217;t seen it, the beautiful, aching, nostalgic Don Draper Carousel pitch:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-4-3 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe class="youtube-player" width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/suRDUFpsHus?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><br></figcaption></figure>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/03/18/building-connection-can-estate-planning-improve-relationships/">Building Connection &#8211; Can Estate Planning Improve Relationships?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1486</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is Family?</title>
		<link>/2019/03/13/what-is-family/</link>
					<comments>/2019/03/13/what-is-family/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Caroline Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 15:20:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beach Walk and Talk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Estate Planning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1448</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Two weeks ago, Noah and I celebrated 23 years of marriage, it is such a beautiful gift that we are enjoying spending time together and were able to celebrate with a date night. &#160;A beautiful dinner with a beautiful view of the sunset thanks to Noah’s planning &#8211; a first for us with an anniversary &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2019/03/13/what-is-family/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">What is Family?</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/03/13/what-is-family/">What is Family?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/2019-02-24.jpg?resize=328%2C245&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1449" width="328" height="245" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/2019-02-24.jpg?resize=1024%2C767&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/2019-02-24.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/2019-02-24.jpg?resize=768%2C575&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/2019-02-24.jpg?resize=350%2C262&amp;ssl=1 350w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/2019-02-24.jpg?w=1065&amp;ssl=1 1065w" sizes="(max-width: 328px) 100vw, 328px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p> Two weeks ago, Noah and I celebrated 23 years of marriage, it is such a beautiful gift that we are enjoying spending time together and were able to celebrate with a date night. &nbsp;A beautiful dinner with a beautiful view of the sunset thanks to Noah’s planning &#8211; a first for us with an anniversary in February that we were able to sit outside and enjoy the sunset. &nbsp;<br></p>



<p>When we got engaged it was a joint decision based on the idea that together we would be a family just the two of us. &nbsp;There was no talk of children and at that time we were so focused on the idea of an adventure to live abroad in the Czech Republic it overshadowed all other ideas. So we began our life together as a family in the Czech Republic.<br></p>



<p>One part of my role in our Estate Planning business is to listen to Noah explain to clients during a Family Wealth Planning session what the state of Florida’s plan is for their family if they have no documents. &nbsp;I’ve listened to several of these now and am struck with how different each family is, and what family means to each person.  Singled, married, divorced, with children without children, step-children, parents, step-parents, nieces, nephews, very close friends who feel like family although there is no blood or legal documents attached, cats, dogs and other pets &#8211; all of these have been discussed and each person views their connection to these relatives differently. &nbsp;What family means to each of them is different.<br></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/2019-03-11-e1552489722909-768x1024.jpg?resize=222%2C296&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1450" width="222" height="296" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/2019-03-11-e1552489722909.jpg?resize=768%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/2019-03-11-e1552489722909.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1 225w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/2019-03-11-e1552489722909.jpg?w=960&amp;ssl=1 960w" sizes="(max-width: 222px) 100vw, 222px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p>What does family mean to me? &nbsp;I have been thinking about this, and Noah and I talked about it on our beach walk this week.  Who do I talk to? Who do I spend time with? Who do I celebrate with? Who do I mourn with? Who do I share DNA with? Who do I share a name with? Who do I share history and traditions with? &nbsp;Who do I love? These are the things I think about when I think about family.  <br></p>



<p>Because of the work we are doing I get to spend time thinking about family a lot. &nbsp;I talk to people about family every day, I share our story of why we have moved to Miami, I share about Noah and I working together as husband and wife. &nbsp;I share about our children, my parents, my siblings, our nieces and nephews, aunts, uncles and cousins.  I talk about my brother in law Jeff building our website and how amazing that experience has been. &nbsp;&nbsp;I talk about being named for my 98 year old grandmother who lived as a child here in Coral Gables.  I think about all of the friends who are so dear to us that they feel like family.  Family, it is such a simple word yet so different for each of us.  Now that I listen to others talk about their families, I&#8217;m aware that it is a word that we each interpret very differently.<br></p>



<p>What is family to you?</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed-soundcloud alignleft wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-soundcloud wp-embed-aspect-4-3 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="What Kind of Love Have You Got by Noah Clements 1" width="1920" height="400" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?visual=true&#038;url=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F246289925&#038;show_artwork=true&#038;maxheight=1000&#038;maxwidth=1920"></iframe>
</div></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube alignright wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe class="youtube-player" width="1920" height="1080" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tcOSUcQ6AUM?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/03/13/what-is-family/">What is Family?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2019/03/13/what-is-family/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1448</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remembering . . .</title>
		<link>/2019/03/04/remembering/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 14:38:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Estate Planning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1390</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Last Tuesday was the first anniversary of my brother&#8217;s death and Saturday was his birthday. His wife (I still have trouble with &#8220;widow&#8221;) threw a party at the last restaurant he managed &#8211; Monty&#8217;s in the Grove. It was a lovely party with family and friends. Last year, right after Michael&#8217;s death, his best friend &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2019/03/04/remembering/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Remembering . . .</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/03/04/remembering/">Remembering . . .</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/IMGP6254.jpg?resize=599%2C398&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1391" width="599" height="398" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/IMGP6254.jpg?resize=1024%2C681&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/IMGP6254.jpg?resize=300%2C199&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/IMGP6254.jpg?resize=768%2C511&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/IMGP6254.jpg?resize=350%2C233&amp;ssl=1 350w" sizes="(max-width: 599px) 100vw, 599px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>Elise &amp; Michael<br><br></figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Last Tuesday was the first anniversary of my brother&#8217;s death and Saturday was his birthday. His wife (I still have trouble with &#8220;widow&#8221;) threw a party at the last restaurant he managed &#8211; Monty&#8217;s in the Grove. It was a lovely party with  family and friends. Last year, right after Michael&#8217;s death, his best friend Shawn threw a birthday party for him at the Coral Reef Yacht club &#8211; it was a time for stories about Michael. Some were funny, some were sad, and some were in poor taste. But that&#8217;s what we needed. We all wanted something to hold on to.</p>



<p>Some things aren&#8217;t meant to be moved on from. This year there were fewer Michael-stories, but more discussions about how everyone was dealing &#8211; how our own lives had changed. Michael&#8217;s family moved to a new house where life will be hopefully easier &#8211; with more children running around and more support. Others have also taken action to spend more time with family as the central part of their lifestyle. </p>



<p>That&#8217;s certainly been part of Caroline and my story since Michael&#8217;s death. After the funeral, we went back up to Silver Spring, where we were living. But then in dealing with our day-to-day and plans for the future, we realized we could not go on as if nothing had happened. My own plans for a new house, for example, just felt so self-indulgent all of a sudden. After ensuring that it would actually be helpful to Michael&#8217;s wife Melissa, we came down to be more of a part of her life and the kids&#8217; lives. And we decided to work together. </p>



<p>Although the impetus for these changes is almost unbearably sad, we have enjoyed the results immensely. I love getting to know Melissa and her family better; I love playing with my niece and nephew so often; and I love spending more time with my own wife and children. When dealing with this kind of pain there can be only one cure &#8211; that&#8217;s more love.</p>



<h2>Eulogy for Michael</h2>



<p>For those who are interested, I am including my eulogy for Michael:</p>



<p>Michael truly was a loving person who was loved by all who knew him &#8211; and this started at an early age.</p>



<p>I remember when we were in elementary school, the two beautiful young stewardesses who lived in the apartment downstairs just doted on him. I remember the Israeli drug dealer our mother was dating at the time would occasionally pause from his general yelling, stroke his chin, look at Michael, and say &#8220;this is a manly child&#8221;.</p>



<p>It was during this time that Michael developed his life-long love for the music of the Bee-Gees. You simply have not seen dancing until you&#8217;ve seen Michael dancing to &#8220;Staying Alive&#8221;.</p>



<p>And Michael was involved in the lives of the people around him &#8211; when he managed a local restaurant chain, he knew details of the lives of every one of the 300 people who worked for him.</p>



<p>And he was generous. When he felt that the company he worked for did not sufficiently reward the people who worked there, he took his own money to make sure they knew he appreciated them. Michael knew that success is a team effort.</p>



<p>And he loved his family.</p>



<p>I remember Michael visiting us when our 1st daughter was born &#8211; he brought all seven dwarves with him, life sized. And he bought out the entire stuffed animal inventory of FAO Schwartz.</p>



<p>When our son was born, he brought a Minnie Mouse that was bigger than him &#8211; I think he had to buy an extra plane seat for that Minnie.</p>



<p>Michael wanted nothing more than to start a family of his own.</p>



<p>And he did. But Michael suffered unspeakable tragedy when his pregnant wife Ashley died in a car accident.</p>



<p>We were all devastated. Michael sank into a depression so deep that we could have lost him then. But Michael&#8217;s love for his family pulled him through.</p>



<p>Michael took in our father and cared for him when he lost his bout with lung cancer. And Michael cared for our Mother when she had her long fight to receive two lung transplants.</p>



<p>Both of these times Michael had Melissa by his side.</p>



<p>Now I&#8217;m not the best person to tell you of the romantic saga of Michael&#8217;s love for Melissa, but I can tell you that I know she was very important to him from the beginning.</p>



<p>And I can tell you that she saved Michael from dying from his unbearable heartbreak.</p>



<p>And since he married you, Melissa, and since you two had this beautiful wild Antonella, and this incredible happy boy Peter, Michael has been the happiest man in the world. You made him so happy.</p>



<p>The last words Michael wrote were to Antonella [he wanted to write to each of you, but he couldn&#8217;t] [I had the original paper at the time, but it is now with Melissa. This is the best I can remember]:</p>



<p>&#8220;I have loved the thought of you for as long as I can remember. You have made me cry tears of incredible joy.&#8221;</p>



<p>Enough of this lovey-dovey stuff.</p>



<p>Michael truly wanted the best for everyone around him. I know everyone here who knew Michael can tell a story about how Michael went out of his way to make your life better.</p>



<p>So I am going to ask you all to do something.</p>



<p>Tell each other, tell me: how did Michael touch you, help you, make your life better.</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s not stop telling each other these stories.</p>



<p>We need to keep Michael here, because he was taken from us way too soon.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/03/04/remembering/">Remembering . . .</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1390</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
