<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>OWI Archives - The Clements Firm</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/owi/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/tag/owi/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 15:57:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/cropped-TCFLogo012419White-1.png?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>OWI Archives - The Clements Firm</title>
	<link>/tag/owi/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21395931</site>	<item>
		<title>Who Cares Whether Urine Scores Are Reliable? DC Still Prosecuting Per Se Urine DUI Cases.</title>
		<link>/2013/10/01/who-cares-whether-urine-scores-are-reliable-dc-still-prosecuting-these-per-se-dui-cases/</link>
					<comments>/2013/10/01/who-cares-whether-urine-scores-are-reliable-dc-still-prosecuting-these-per-se-dui-cases/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2013 00:27:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Criminal Law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DUI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[District of Columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DWI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evidence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jury Trials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OWI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pre-trial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scientific Evidence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trials]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://new.theclementsfirm.com/?p=446</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Even though everyone in the DC government, from the DC Council to the prosecutors at the Office of the Attorney General, knows that alcohol in the urine has a &#8220;loose correlation&#8221; to intoxication, that urinalysis is unreliable, people are still regularly prosecuted and convicted of driving under the influence (DUI) base on their urine scores. Back &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2013/10/01/who-cares-whether-urine-scores-are-reliable-dc-still-prosecuting-these-per-se-dui-cases/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Who Cares Whether Urine Scores Are Reliable? DC Still Prosecuting Per Se Urine DUI Cases.</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/10/01/who-cares-whether-urine-scores-are-reliable-dc-still-prosecuting-these-per-se-dui-cases/">Who Cares Whether Urine Scores Are Reliable? DC Still Prosecuting Per Se Urine DUI Cases.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Even though everyone in the DC government, from the DC Council to the prosecutors at the Office of the Attorney General, knows that alcohol in the urine has a &#8220;loose correlation&#8221; to intoxication, that urinalysis is unreliable, people are still regularly prosecuted and convicted of driving under the influence (DUI) base on their urine scores.</p>
<p>Back in June of 2011, DC Chief Toxicologist Lucas Zarwell of the Office of the Chief Medical Examiner, stated under oath to the DC Council that urine testing cannot reliably determine impairment or blood alcohol levels. In response to a question from council member Phil Mendelson, Mr. Zarwell testified as follows:</p>
<blockquote><p>MENDELSON. How accurate is urine testing for measuring blood alcohol content?</p>
<p>ZARWELL. It&#8217;s not.</p></blockquote>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/FUmhJ_jPF1E" height="315" width="420" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p><span id="more-446"></span>Upon council member Mendelson’s questioning, Mr. Zarwell further explained:</p>
<blockquote><p>MENDELSON. If a urine sample is taken from me and there&#8217;s a high concentration of alcohol in it . . . doesn&#8217;t that suggest that I&#8217;m intoxicated?</p>
<p>ZARWELL. It can. That depends on the officer&#8217;s observations. It can help, I believe, be associated with that. But if you&#8217;re going to look at urine concentrations of alcohol and science, there&#8217;s a very loose correlation. There have been several studies on it. But currently, if you&#8217;re just voiding your urine or urinating into a cup, that does not correlate to a blood concentration. It could be much higher, as much as 40% higher.</p>
<p>MENDELSON. What’s the “it” there? What could be higher?</p>
<p>ZARWELL. The urine concentration could be higher than your blood alcohol concentration, it could be lower than your blood alcohol concentration. . . .</p>
<p>It&#8217;s an old way of doing things. . . . It&#8217;s better to have an officer&#8217;s observations to be able to say, yes, we&#8217;ve got alcohol present. . . .</p>
<p>But there&#8217;s no doubt from a scientific standpoint that blood and breath are a better indicator of, the best indicator to see what kind of effect alcohol is having on the brain. Because the blood is circulating the brain and that&#8217;s where the drug is having its effect and that&#8217;s where we&#8217;re seeing levels of impairment. And this has been studied heavily in the community.</p></blockquote>
<div>
<p>If you&#8217;re interested, you should watch the video. While there was a time that the government prosecutors did not attempt to introduce urine scores, I believe primarily because of confrontation and scheduling issues, that time seems to be over.</p>
<p>I think it&#8217;s unconscionable that the government is using these urine-alcohol scores in <em>per se </em>DUI prosecutions knowing that they are unreliable. Even worse, DC judges have been denying motions to exclude these scores as unreliable by saying that the DC Council is presumed to have considered the evidence in passing the <em>per se</em> DUI laws (a presumption that is demonstrably false). All we as defense attorneys can do is continue to file these motions in the hope that one day we will be successful. And I continue to aggressively fight this fight for my clients.</p>
</div>
<blockquote>
<div>
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref2"><sup><sup> </sup></sup></a></p>
</div>
</div>
</blockquote>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/10/01/who-cares-whether-urine-scores-are-reliable-dc-still-prosecuting-these-per-se-dui-cases/">Who Cares Whether Urine Scores Are Reliable? DC Still Prosecuting Per Se Urine DUI Cases.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/10/01/who-cares-whether-urine-scores-are-reliable-dc-still-prosecuting-these-per-se-dui-cases/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">446</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Police Officer&#8217;s Selective Memory in DUI Trial</title>
		<link>/2013/07/06/police-officers-selective-memory-in-dui-trial/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2013 18:14:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Criminal Law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DUI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[District of Columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DWI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OWI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Witnesses]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://new.theclementsfirm.com/?p=416</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I am working on an appeal from a DUI conviction. I enjoy reading other lawyers&#8217; trial transcripts seeing what works and doesn&#8217;t and coming up with ideas for my own trials. In DC, first offense DUI defendants are not entitled to a jury trial, which can be frustrating as many judges will accept what police &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2013/07/06/police-officers-selective-memory-in-dui-trial/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Police Officer&#8217;s Selective Memory in DUI Trial</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/07/06/police-officers-selective-memory-in-dui-trial/">Police Officer&#8217;s Selective Memory in DUI Trial</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am working on an appeal from a DUI conviction. I enjoy reading other lawyers&#8217; trial transcripts seeing what works and doesn&#8217;t and coming up with ideas for my own trials. In DC, first offense DUI defendants are not entitled to a jury trial, which can be frustrating as many judges will accept what police officers say as gospel, even when obviously &#8220;shading the truth&#8221; (that&#8217;s just a nice way of saying lying). Rarely, however, do I see an officer make it so obvious as the following when responding to questions about the procedures he followed in giving the Field Sobriety Tests:</p>
<blockquote><p>A. Are we going to go back and forth with another smoke screen? . . . You know, we’re going to go back and forth with these smokescreen questions. I’m just going to tell you I don’t recall.</p></blockquote>
<p><span id="more-416"></span>It&#8217;s bad enough that they bring in this pseudo-scientific hoakum (the field sobriety tests &#8211; the horizontal gaze nystagmus eye test, the walk-and-turn, and the one-leg-stand balance tests) as evidence of driving under the influence of alcohol, but then when a defense lawyer questions them on the actual procedures they used and how they compare to what they are supposed to do, you can get some variation of the above.</p>
<p>Reading the transcripts, it&#8217;s difficult to fault anything my colleague, a well-respected DUI lawyer, did. But I hope I would have not let that statement stand. In that passage, the cop is basically saying that if you ask me a question I think is a &#8220;smokescreen&#8221;, I am going to lie and say that I don&#8217;t remember. I would like to think that I would have had the presence of mind to press the officer on that: &#8220;So if I ask a question that you think is a smokescreen, you will tell me you don&#8217;t recall?&#8221; &#8220;Didn&#8217;t you swear to tell the truth?&#8221; &#8220;Just because someone can&#8217;t prove what you do and don&#8217;t recall, that doesn&#8217;t make it less of a lie does it?&#8221; I hope when I am in my next DUI trial and the officer says something like that, I will not let it stand.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/07/06/police-officers-selective-memory-in-dui-trial/">Police Officer&#8217;s Selective Memory in DUI Trial</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">416</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
