<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Caroline Clements, Author at The Clements Firm</title>
	<atom:link href="/author/caroline/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/author/caroline/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 15:14:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/cropped-TCFLogo012419White-1.png?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>Caroline Clements, Author at The Clements Firm</title>
	<link>/author/caroline/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21395931</site>	<item>
		<title>Affirming Goodness</title>
		<link>/2019/06/26/affirming-goodness/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Caroline Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 15:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beach Walk and Talk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1724</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#160;I spent Saturday at a retreat to discover my purpose, passion &#38; plan for a generous life.&#160; I was intrigued with the idea of spending the day with other women who were interested in aligning their work life with their values.&#160; I was flattered to have been invited. I had no idea how much clarity &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2019/06/26/affirming-goodness/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Affirming Goodness</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/06/26/affirming-goodness/">Affirming Goodness</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2019-06-26-App-picture.png?resize=217%2C351&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1727" width="217" height="351" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2019-06-26-App-picture.png?w=396&amp;ssl=1 396w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2019-06-26-App-picture.png?resize=186%2C300&amp;ssl=1 186w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2019-06-26-App-picture.png?resize=350%2C566&amp;ssl=1 350w" sizes="(max-width: 217px) 100vw, 217px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p>&nbsp;I spent Saturday at a retreat to discover my purpose, passion &amp; plan for a generous life.&nbsp; I was intrigued with the idea of spending the day with other women who were interested in aligning their work life with their values.&nbsp; I was flattered to have been invited.  I had no idea how much clarity I would gain over the choices I have made over the last year.<br></p>



<p>The lessons involved watching videos of women telling stories.&nbsp; The idea being that each of our lives holds a story.  Each of these women shared their stories of how they found their purpose.&nbsp; Then, how they aligned their passion and plan for giving to that purpose.  The basic assumption is that our purpose is a constant, regardless of our circumstances it rings true for us and has always been there.&nbsp; Our passion and plan can change and often reflect our life experiences.<br></p>



<p>We answered a series of questions to find a two word definition of our Purpose from a website:  www.onpurpose.com.  My Purpose was determined to be Affirming Goodness.  When I first read it, I thought, well that’s too easy, I already do that, give me something else.  But as I reflected, I realized that was the whole point.  My purpose is something that is already a part of me.  It is a constant within me that I can develop and use to grow.  <br></p>



<p> I am a daily gratitude list maker.  I use the <a href="https://www.intelligentchange.com/pages/five-minute-journal-app">Journal 5 app </a>and have been doing so for years.  I list things I am grateful for in the morning and again at night.  You add a picture for the day which gives it a little something extra (screen shot of my week above).  Sometimes I use a picture taken that day and sometimes a memory.  I often download family and friends’ Facebook photos for their Birthday or to mark a special day.  (Beware).<br></p>



<p>Affirming Goodness, looking at my life as enough.&nbsp; Assurining others that they are enough.  Offering grace and patience.&nbsp; Looking to be curious and appreciative of others.  Allowing others to go first, even in traffic.&nbsp; These all follow the guideline of looking at life through a vision of abundance over one of scarcities.<br></p>



<p>Moving onto Passion was the next step. My passion is something that I believe in so strongly that I am compelled to orient my life towards it.&nbsp; As most of you know, Noah and I are passionate about helping families prepare for when something happens to them.  The events in our lives over the last two years have given us a very clear mission.&nbsp; For some reason, as we talk about the deaths in our family, others are willing to share their experiences and their fears with us.<br></p>



<p>In addition to this, Noah and I have been given the opportunity to work together.&nbsp; We are strengthening our relationship and our family by working together.  We spend more time together now then we ever have and we are learning more and more how we complement one another.&nbsp; This provides an interesting benefit for our clients where they have both of us to talk to.<br></p>



<p>When has my giving been the most joyful? This is the question we were given to find our passion.&nbsp; For me it has been in areas where I feel connection.  Whether it is having a conversation with someone while painting a house for 100 Hands Rebuilding, running a charity 5K with my daughter or meeting a new client and finding out we have the same birthday.&nbsp; I find joy in connection.<br></p>



<p>This all sounds lovely but what does it have to do with work?&nbsp; Well, as I discovered with the Passion exercises, the more I enjoy what I am doing the more I am willing to do.&nbsp; As most of you know, I am writing these blogs weekly so you can get to know us. I have never written for work before and every time I write one of these I am uncertain if I have done it “right”.&nbsp; Well, weekly, someone is nice enough to email me back and let me know that they agreed with me or identified with what I wrote.  Mission accomplished, and so I write again.<br></p>



<p>With regard to Plan, the last step, well, we started working together in this <a href="/services/estate-planning/">estate planning practice</a>. We are still working on that plan. You are watching us as we do it.<br></p>



<p>I hope you are in touch with your purpose and that you find joy and passion with your work. <br></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/06/26/affirming-goodness/">Affirming Goodness</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1724</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Difficult Decisions</title>
		<link>/2019/06/18/difficult-decisions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Caroline Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 15:28:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beach Walk and Talk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Medical Directives]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Living Will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Planning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1713</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday Noah and I took our sweet 11 year old dog Corrina to the vet. &#160;Our neighbor noticed a growth on her hind leg while petting her and gave us the name of her vet. &#160;I made an appointment and we took her in for a check up and to have the growth looked at. &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2019/06/18/difficult-decisions/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Difficult Decisions</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/06/18/difficult-decisions/">Difficult Decisions</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Corrina.jpg?resize=230%2C285&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1714" width="230" height="285" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Corrina.jpg?resize=825%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 825w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Corrina.jpg?resize=242%2C300&amp;ssl=1 242w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Corrina.jpg?resize=768%2C953&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Corrina.jpg?resize=350%2C434&amp;ssl=1 350w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Corrina.jpg?w=1978&amp;ssl=1 1978w" sizes="(max-width: 230px) 100vw, 230px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>Corrina</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Yesterday Noah and I took our sweet 11 year old dog Corrina to the vet. &nbsp;Our neighbor noticed a growth on her hind leg while petting her and gave us the name of her vet. &nbsp;I made an appointment and we took her in for a check up and to have the growth looked at.  In the 11 years we have had Corrina, it was the first time we had taken her to an appointment together.<br></p>



<p>We got Corrina at the Washington Rescue League in DC shortly after moving there in 2007. &nbsp;She was born at the shelter and we took her home as a 4 month old puppy.  She has an amazing demeanor and has been a wonderful part of our family.<br></p>



<p>There were several parts of the visit that felt routine and familiar even though it was my first time there. &nbsp;The dogs and cats were separated in the waiting room and there were glass jars of animal treats.  It smelled of animal and disinfectant. &nbsp;The technician brought us back to the examining room and began the physical.<br></p>



<p>When Noah discusses living wills with clients, they often refer to choices available to pets. &nbsp;As he talks through incapacity, many clients refer to how pets are handled in old age as medical issues arise. &nbsp;Clients comment that they wish they could choose the options they have chosen for their pet.<br></p>



<p>Well, walking through this yesterday, did not feel easier nor was it simple. The vet  explained that the growth was not superficial.  That most likely it is in the muscle and possibly into the bone.  The options of getting a biopsy and pathology report were discussed.  Clarity on what potential surgeries would look like and what we could expect were clarified.<br></p>



<p>I sat there listening to all of this, thinking “and this is easier?” &nbsp;Making these decisions for another is difficult.  Even in this situation where the rational brain is so strong and clear. &nbsp;The dog is 11, life expectancy for flat coated retrievers is 8-14 years.  Prior to our neighbor finding the growth we had noticed no change in her behavior. &nbsp;<br></p>



<p>Noah mentioned to the doctor multiple times that we walk her 2 miles every evening, it became clearer and clearer that at the moment she is not suffering. &nbsp;She is not limping, there is no change in diet or mood.  Yet she has this growth on her leg and the signs of her aging are present.  The vet presented us with our options and asked us to make a choice.<br></p>



<p>When the doctor stepped out, Noah and I re-stated what we have talked about numerous times, no surgery. &nbsp;The surgery will reduce her quality of life. I was surprised at how hard this was, how I kept reminding myself that this is the right decision. &nbsp;Even in this circumstance, where our values are clear, it is a difficult decision.  We were making it together, completely on the same page.   Yet, it was really difficult.<br></p>



<p>Returning home, we talked to our children about the visit. &nbsp;Each of them let us know they did not think Corrina should have the surgery. &nbsp;Before we let them know what we were thinking, they voiced our thoughts.  All five of us agree &#8211; no surgery. &nbsp;But it is still a difficult decision. <br></p>



<p>Thinking about it more as I walked her this morning, I became grateful that Noah and I have living wills and that we have talked about our wishes. &nbsp;I know what he would want and I know he knows my wishes.  These wishes are in writing.  It is comforting knowing that I have done what I can to make this easier for Noah and he has done what he can to make it easier for me.<br></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/06/18/difficult-decisions/">Difficult Decisions</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1713</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Taking a Moment to Reflect</title>
		<link>/2019/06/11/taking-a-moment-to-reflect/</link>
					<comments>/2019/06/11/taking-a-moment-to-reflect/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Caroline Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 18:27:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beach Walk and Talk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Estate Planning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1674</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I was given the pleasure of attending a baptism on Sunday. The pastor encouraged us to think of other baptisms we had been to and the memories that evoked. &#160;Reflecting on our childrens’ baptism, it became interesting to me what came to mind first. We baptized our three children and the memories I have of &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2019/06/11/taking-a-moment-to-reflect/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Taking a Moment to Reflect</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/06/11/taking-a-moment-to-reflect/">Taking a Moment to Reflect</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>I was given the pleasure of attending a baptism on Sunday. The pastor encouraged us to think of other baptisms we had been to and the memories that evoked. &nbsp;Reflecting on our childrens’ baptism, it became interesting to me what came to mind first.<br></p>



<p>We baptized our three children and the memories I have of each hold a special place in my heart. &nbsp;They were baptized in three different churches in three different cities and the families members present were different each time.<br></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/1999-04-04-Wiley-Michael.jpg?resize=230%2C204&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1687" width="230" height="204" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/1999-04-04-Wiley-Michael.jpg?resize=1024%2C907&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/1999-04-04-Wiley-Michael.jpg?resize=300%2C266&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/1999-04-04-Wiley-Michael.jpg?resize=768%2C680&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/1999-04-04-Wiley-Michael.jpg?w=1068&amp;ssl=1 1068w" sizes="(max-width: 230px) 100vw, 230px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>Michael &amp; Wiley</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Our oldest, Wiley was baptized at St. Michael&#8217;s in New York City.  Both of my sisters and Noah’s brother and sister came to the city for the event.  Wiley was the first niece and this was the first event.  The memory that stands out the most for me involved a battle between Noah and his brother Michael.  Wiley was wearing the baptismal gown that I had worn when I was baptized. </p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/1999-04-03-Wiley-baptism-Steph-Kate.jpg?resize=213%2C170&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1688" width="213" height="170" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/1999-04-03-Wiley-baptism-Steph-Kate.jpg?resize=1024%2C816&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/1999-04-03-Wiley-baptism-Steph-Kate.jpg?resize=300%2C239&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/1999-04-03-Wiley-baptism-Steph-Kate.jpg?resize=768%2C612&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/1999-04-03-Wiley-baptism-Steph-Kate.jpg?w=1343&amp;ssl=1 1343w" sizes="(max-width: 213px) 100vw, 213px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>Stephanie, Kate &amp; Wiley</figcaption></figure></div>



<p> It was a silk gown of several layers and very slippery. Noah insisted on carrying her throughout the ceremony, he was the only one to hold her.  Being the Godfather that he was, Michael tried hard to take a turn, but Noah was not having it.  The gown made her slippery to hold and as the father he was going to hold her.  Makes me chuckle, twenty years later to remember these brothers vying for the privilege of holding the baby.<br></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2001-12-30-Eric-baptism.jpeg?resize=302%2C166&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1689" width="302" height="166" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2001-12-30-Eric-baptism.jpeg?resize=1024%2C564&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2001-12-30-Eric-baptism.jpeg?resize=300%2C165&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2001-12-30-Eric-baptism.jpeg?resize=768%2C423&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2001-12-30-Eric-baptism.jpeg?w=1559&amp;ssl=1 1559w" sizes="(max-width: 302px) 100vw, 302px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>Rick, Nan, Wiley &amp; Eric</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Our son Eric was baptized at Church of the Holy Family in Chapel Hill, NC.  My brother and his wife came to town for the ceremony.  The memory that stands out the strongest from his baptism happened at the end.  After the anointment, the priest raised Eric up above his head and carried him down the aisle.  The act was like that of Simba’s baptism in Lion King where Rafiki presents Simba to the herd. For those of you who have not met my baby boy, he is now 6’7”.  Eric has definitely grown to be a very big boy and can now be seen above a crowd without being held up.<br></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2015-01-01-Elise-Michael-noses.jpg?resize=239%2C219&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1691" width="239" height="219" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2015-01-01-Elise-Michael-noses.jpg?resize=1024%2C944&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2015-01-01-Elise-Michael-noses.jpg?resize=300%2C276&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2015-01-01-Elise-Michael-noses.jpg?resize=768%2C708&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2015-01-01-Elise-Michael-noses.jpg?w=1072&amp;ssl=1 1072w" sizes="(max-width: 239px) 100vw, 239px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>Michael &amp; Elise</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Our sweet Elise was baptised at St.Phillip’s in Durham, NC. &nbsp;Noah’s brother and his wife came for the ceremony.  She was baptised at the Easter Vigil mass and all I can remember was that there were candles and Michael let Elise hold the candle herself. &nbsp;She was three (older than the others at baptism) wearing a white flower girl dress that had become her trademark gown and pink cowgirl boots.  Her independence and desire to participate with the adults was shining through even then.<br></p>



<p>Reflection is such an amazing thing. &nbsp;It gives space for those memories, the smile and the sadness. &nbsp;<br></p>



<p>As I chuckle that Noah and Michael were having a brotherly competition at Wiley’s baptism, my heart hurts knowing that now that Michael has passed there will be no more brotherly competition between those two. &nbsp;<br></p>



<p>Remembering Eric being held up above the priests head brings a smile to face.  My heart aches a bit knowing that my baby boy has grown up.   It is time for him to tackle his own challenges.  <br></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2015-02-18-Elise-Ashley-pool.jpg?resize=274%2C226&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1690" width="274" height="226" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2015-02-18-Elise-Ashley-pool.jpg?w=931&amp;ssl=1 931w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2015-02-18-Elise-Ashley-pool.jpg?resize=300%2C248&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2015-02-18-Elise-Ashley-pool.jpg?resize=768%2C635&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 274px) 100vw, 274px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>Ashley &amp; Elise</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>As sweet Elise sat next to me in the pew on Sunday,  I told her about the candles at her baptism.  At three she had to hold it herself just as she likes to always hold the hymnal now.  A few tears rolled down my cheeks as I realized that her godparents Michael and Ashley were now watching over her from heaven.<br></p>



<p>In the work that Noah and I are doing I am privileged to listen to clients’ reflections. &nbsp;To hear what the important memories are for them.  Some make me laugh out loud and some are sad. &nbsp;All are beautiful.<br></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/06/11/taking-a-moment-to-reflect/">Taking a Moment to Reflect</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2019/06/11/taking-a-moment-to-reflect/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1674</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Working with a coach</title>
		<link>/2019/06/04/working-with-a-coach/</link>
					<comments>/2019/06/04/working-with-a-coach/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Caroline Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 20:32:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beach Walk and Talk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Estate Planning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1666</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>When Noah and I made the decision to start working together we hired a business coach. &#160;Having a neutral third party to assist us in building the business has been crucial. We had a coaching call this morning and the focus was on marketing, specifically setting up educational presentations. &#160; We begin each coaching session &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2019/06/04/working-with-a-coach/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Working with a coach</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/06/04/working-with-a-coach/">Working with a coach</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2019-06-02-NC-presentationjpg.jpg?resize=215%2C287&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1667" width="215" height="287" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2019-06-02-NC-presentationjpg.jpg?resize=768%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2019-06-02-NC-presentationjpg.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1 225w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2019-06-02-NC-presentationjpg.jpg?resize=350%2C467&amp;ssl=1 350w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/2019-06-02-NC-presentationjpg.jpg?w=849&amp;ssl=1 849w" sizes="(max-width: 215px) 100vw, 215px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p>When Noah and I made the decision to start working together we hired a business coach. &nbsp;Having a neutral third party to assist us in building the business has been crucial.  We had a coaching call this morning and the focus was on marketing, specifically setting up educational presentations. &nbsp;<br></p>



<p>We begin each coaching session discussing how we feel about our business.  Followed by a recap of what new steps we took over the last month.  After going through the metrics her conclusion was for me to book presentations.  That I should be making 10 phone calls a day to places inquiring if they had educational events.  This was not the first time we had discussed me making phone calls and yet I have only made one call.  My resistance to doing this has not been a secret.<br></p>



<p>When our coach began questioning me why I haven’t made the calls, I went into panic. &nbsp;My body immediately went into a textbook response of: fight, flight, freeze mode.  I was unable to identify the thought that was leading to the feeling of panic, however the emotion was coming on strong and I began to shutdown. &nbsp;Noah immediately stepped in as my savior offering to make the calls.  Without skipping a beat he began asking who should be called, while simultaneously doing a Google search of potential locations near our office.  That’s how Noah works, jumping right in to get more information as quickly as possible.<br></p>



<p>Our coach took a step back and began discussing the rationale. &nbsp;She validated that I have been successful at one-to-one connection and have been increasing our contacts. She also pointed out that I hit the weekly newsletter goal she had set in February. &nbsp;In May I wrote four blogs and sent newsletters weekly for the first time. Our newsletters have a good open rate (thank you for reading and learning more about us) and we are increasing our house list.<br></p>



<p>Part of my job is the marketing and with that the responsibility of setting up presentations.  We ended the call with 3 actions items.   One involves me making these 10 calls  a day with a goal of setting up two presentations.<br></p>



<p>After the call Noah went to meet a chamber member for coffee and I sat down to mediate and journal. &nbsp;Taking 30 minutes to center myself, I ended with a list of the things I like about working with Noah.  <br></p>



<p>I like that we spend more time together now then we have for the 24 years we have known each other.  I like that we are learning to really enjoy spending time together.  I like that we are learning new things together.   We have been to some really interesting lunch-and-learns and the communication training we went to in Colorado was fantastic.  I like that we are talking to families together, bringing our different skills together and listening in a new way.  We have always known that we are different, opposites in so many ways.  </p>



<p>However, I like that we are now being given a space to practice working together.  We are using our differences to cover all of the bases.  Long ago a therapist pointed out that we make decisions differently.  He used a pie analogy to explain this.  We can split the pie in half or work together to have the whole pie .  We are using the whole pie perspective to help families make some really hard decisions, I like that.<br></p>



<p>We hired a coach to help us keep our vision and make clear goals to reach it.  She also pushes us to make those goals.  If Noah had been the one, and he has, to suggest I make the calls, it would have decreased my enjoyment of working with him.  We are making a lot of changes working together and my job description has changed dramatically.  With the guidance of our coach I will continue to grow as I have with attending networking lunches and writing.</p>



<p>So, I don’t like making phone calls. &nbsp;Once I post this blog, I am going to make some anyway.<br></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/06/04/working-with-a-coach/">Working with a coach</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2019/06/04/working-with-a-coach/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1666</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Routines</title>
		<link>/2019/05/28/new-routines/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Caroline Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 18:14:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beach Walk and Talk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1657</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This was my first Memorial Day weekend in Miami. &#160;It had me completely off tilt. Having spent most of my life in the North and my childhood years on military bases, Memorial Day weekend involved flags, the day off from school, picnics, and if we were lucky a trip to the pool. &#160;A day to &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2019/05/28/new-routines/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">New Routines</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/05/28/new-routines/">New Routines</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2019-05-26-waves.jpg?resize=224%2C279&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1658" width="224" height="279" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2019-05-26-waves.jpg?resize=821%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 821w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2019-05-26-waves.jpg?resize=241%2C300&amp;ssl=1 241w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2019-05-26-waves.jpg?resize=768%2C957&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2019-05-26-waves.jpg?resize=350%2C436&amp;ssl=1 350w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2019-05-26-waves.jpg?w=1858&amp;ssl=1 1858w" sizes="(max-width: 224px) 100vw, 224px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p> This was my first Memorial Day weekend in Miami. &nbsp;It had me completely off tilt.  Having spent most of my life in the North and my childhood years on military bases, Memorial Day weekend involved flags, the day off from school, picnics, and if we were lucky a trip to the pool. &nbsp;A day to take a moment and remember those who have died for our country followed by a celebration for the beginning of summer.  It was a clear shift to summer, the pool was now open and wearing white pants and white shoes was now allowed.<br></p>



<p>Here in South Florida, the pools and the ocean are always open and the only change in wardrobe I have witnessed is that if it drops below 70 degrees, winter coats, sweaters and boots are worn. It has felt like summer since we moved here last August. &nbsp;<br></p>



<p>This year, the friends who hosted the barbecue I’ve attended for the last few years were too far away. &nbsp;Nothing felt the same. I would not be going to the barbecue to hear Noah’s band play as I had done for the last few years. &nbsp;My plans and the people I would be sharing it with were all going to be different. <br></p>



<p>The degree to which I was out of sorts allowed me to really notice and examine the situation. &nbsp;Holidays are special and provide a clear distinction of what I was doing last time the Holiday rolled around. &nbsp;My plan for the day would need to be different this year.<br></p>



<p>As I thought about this more, I realized that I am not alone. There are many others who are experiencing dramatic changes in their lives. &nbsp;I began to think of others who would not be celebrating with the same people they had in the past, due to death, divorce, illness, or a move. &nbsp;Activities that had been part of their ritual would not be taking place.  This meant they would be doing something new, and probably had to make decisions about what that was going to be. &nbsp;<br></p>



<p>I recently went to a workshop on the brain, learning that only 10% of our brain operates in the conscious frontal lobe where we are making decisions. &nbsp;The other 90% is in our subconscious and unconscious brain where, thanks to habits and rituals we are able to function with much less effort.  I am a big habit and ritual person. &nbsp;I find comfort in routines and balance in my day to day life. <br></p>



<p>This is possibly one reason that I also feel out-of-sorts more than most when my routines and habits are altered. &nbsp;A couple of things that have been working for me so far is to remind myself to give it time.  “Give it a year” was the advice a friend gave me when I went back to full-time work in an office after having been at home for 15 years. &nbsp;She was right, it didn’t take a year to feel comfortable with going into an office everyday but saying that certainly helped. It helps for me to be aware of how many times my routines have changed and remember that at some point the new routine became comfortable. &nbsp;Going off to college, leaving college, getting married, moving, having children, children going to school &#8211; all of these have required new routines and eventually I got used to all of them.<br></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2019-05-26-icecream.jpg?resize=319%2C226&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1660" width="319" height="226" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2019-05-26-icecream.jpg?resize=1024%2C726&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2019-05-26-icecream.jpg?resize=300%2C213&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2019-05-26-icecream.jpg?resize=768%2C545&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2019-05-26-icecream.jpg?w=1669&amp;ssl=1 1669w" sizes="(max-width: 319px) 100vw, 319px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p>So this weekend, I got to jump in the waves with my niece and nephew visiting from Michigan. &nbsp;James did not remember the ocean and it was fun to be with him as he splashed in the surf.  We also ate ice cream, because we always eat ice cream with my sister Stephanie, but this year Clara found the spot thanks to Yelp and her new phone.<br></p>



<p>Our lives are constantly changing, and we are adapting to those changes with new routines. &nbsp;The more deliberate or life altering changes will feel more out of place than simple routines. However it is reassuring to know that we are all changing and that eventually we will find comfort in our new surroundings and routines.<br><br></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/05/28/new-routines/">New Routines</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1657</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Productivity</title>
		<link>/2019/05/21/productivity/</link>
					<comments>/2019/05/21/productivity/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Caroline Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 15:34:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beach Walk and Talk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1636</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I asked my 17-year-old daughter Elise this morning what I should write my blog about and without taking a breath she answered, productivity. &#160;“Mom, you are always talking about it”. I then proceeded to survey my 19-year-old son Eric and 20-year-old daughter Wiley about their thoughts on productivity. &#160;The responses started with “Mom, you know &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2019/05/21/productivity/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Productivity</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/05/21/productivity/">Productivity</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/IMG_6907.jpg?resize=275%2C380&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1642" width="275" height="380" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/IMG_6907.jpg?resize=741%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 741w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/IMG_6907.jpg?resize=217%2C300&amp;ssl=1 217w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/IMG_6907.jpg?resize=768%2C1061&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/IMG_6907.jpg?resize=350%2C484&amp;ssl=1 350w" sizes="(max-width: 275px) 100vw, 275px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>Eric &amp; Wiley</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>I asked my 17-year-old daughter Elise this morning what I should write my blog about and without taking a breath she answered, productivity. &nbsp;“Mom, you are always talking about it”. I then proceeded to survey my 19-year-old son Eric and 20-year-old daughter Wiley about their thoughts on productivity. &nbsp;The responses started with “Mom, you know that is subjective.”  <br></p>



<p>So I altered the question, &nbsp;“When do you feel productive?” How do you set yourself up to feel productive? &nbsp;In talking about the details of approach more I realized that all three of my children take the approach that getting started is the hardest part and they just keep going once started to avoid having to start again. <br></p>



<p>Another approach they had in common is to make a long to do list, setting the expectations high. &nbsp;They find that this gives them space to be satisfied with the amount done even if it is not the entire list. &nbsp;<br></p>



<p>Wiley said she is a to-do-list maker, and a tactic she picked up from my sister Stephanie is to write something on the list you have already done so you can check it off. &nbsp;She said this gives her the illusion that she is on a roll and she can just keep going instead of needing to start. Noah does that too.<br></p>



<p>Eric needs an entrance so he plays music, repeats a mantra and then goes for it. &nbsp;He finds that momentum is key and once he is going he tries to get as much done as possible because starting is such a challenge. Again, Noah has a lot in common with our children.<br></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/IMG_6905.jpg?resize=242%2C218&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1637" width="242" height="218" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/IMG_6905.jpg?resize=1024%2C923&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/IMG_6905.jpg?resize=300%2C270&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/IMG_6905.jpg?resize=768%2C692&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 242px) 100vw, 242px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>Elise&#8217;s books</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Elise finds the surrounding environment important. &nbsp;She got the bulk of her AP studying done at the library. &nbsp;She makes a plan, heads to the library, and doesn’t leave until the task is done.<br></p>



<p> I am very different from my children, I am much more focused on setting small achievable goals and accumulating wins. &nbsp;For me, setting one achievable goal for the day is key.  It is too easy for me to get lost in the checking off of tiny tasks. &nbsp;I focus on one goal for the five areas of my life that are important to me and go from there.  <br></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/IMG_6908-1.jpg?resize=228%2C362&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1643" width="228" height="362" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/IMG_6908-1.jpg?resize=643%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 643w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/IMG_6908-1.jpg?resize=768%2C1222&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/IMG_6908-1.jpg?w=1749&amp;ssl=1 1749w" sizes="(max-width: 228px) 100vw, 228px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>My checklist</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>So for today, I meditated first thing, prayed, and did my journaling; spiritual health &#8211; check. &nbsp;Ran with Wiley and then walked to work; physical health &#8211; check.  I am planning to eat dinner with Wiley and Eric at the restaurant where Elise works (fish tacos yum) then walk the dog with Noah; family time &#8211; check. Writing this blog and getting the newsletter are the work tasks for today, so when they are done I will have felt it was a productive work day. Then final area of my life, my mind hmmm….</p>



<p><br></p>



<a href="https://app.acuityscheduling.com/schedule.php?owner=17212147&#038;appointmentType=9215013" target="_blank" class="acuity-embed-button" style="background: #002e5d; color: #fff; padding: 8px 12px; border: 0px; -webkit-box-shadow: 0 -2px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15) inset;-moz-box-shadow: 0 -2px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15) inset;box-shadow: 0 -2px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15) inset;border-radius: 4px; text-decoration: none; display: inline-block;" rel="noopener noreferrer">Attend FREE Estate Planning Workshop!</a><link rel="stylesheet" href="https://embed.acuityscheduling.com/embed/button/17212147.css" id="acuity-button-styles" /><script src="https://embed.acuityscheduling.com/embed/button/17212147.js" async></script>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/05/21/productivity/">Productivity</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2019/05/21/productivity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1636</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Laughter through tears</title>
		<link>/2019/05/15/laughter-through-tears/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Caroline Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 15:56:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beach Walk and Talk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1625</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Enough already! I am learning that church seems to be the place where I cry, it has happened several times now and this week I accepted it as a healthy place for me to feel my feelings. &#160;When Noah and I were in Boulder for our communication workshop we learned that finding safe spaces to &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2019/05/15/laughter-through-tears/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Laughter through tears</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/05/15/laughter-through-tears/">Laughter through tears</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2000-01-08-Wiley-crying-e1557933810596-667x1024.jpg?resize=254%2C390&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1630" width="254" height="390" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2000-01-08-Wiley-crying-e1557933810596.jpg?resize=667%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 667w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2000-01-08-Wiley-crying-e1557933810596.jpg?resize=196%2C300&amp;ssl=1 196w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2000-01-08-Wiley-crying-e1557933810596.jpg?resize=768%2C1178&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2000-01-08-Wiley-crying-e1557933810596.jpg?resize=350%2C537&amp;ssl=1 350w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2000-01-08-Wiley-crying-e1557933810596.jpg?w=1168&amp;ssl=1 1168w" sizes="(max-width: 254px) 100vw, 254px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>Wiley 2000<br><br></figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Enough already! I am learning that church seems to be the place where I cry, it has happened several times now and this week I accepted it as a healthy place for me to feel my feelings. &nbsp;When Noah and I were in Boulder for our communication workshop we learned that finding safe spaces to cry is important for being able to feel our feelings accurately.  We learned that when we have practiced resisting crying when certain feelings like sadness or frustration happen, our bodies get confused from blocking the natural release of crying and it becomes hard to identify what we are feeling.  So we were encouraged to pay attention to what works for us to feel feelings of sadness.  Things that work for many are music, movies, certain spaces, certain people and when we find them, let the feelings flow in that safe space. &nbsp;I guess I have found a safe space that works for me.<br></p>



<p>During the service, my tears stopped as I began to sing with my daughter Elise.   A certain psalm we sing every week reminds me of Aladdin and I joke with her every time that I’m on a magic carpet when we sing it.  As you can imagine the joke has gotten old, but Elise plays along with me anyway, which I think is part of the fun.<br></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2019-05-12.jpg?resize=212%2C243&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1627" width="212" height="243" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2019-05-12.jpg?w=852&amp;ssl=1 852w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2019-05-12.jpg?resize=262%2C300&amp;ssl=1 262w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2019-05-12.jpg?resize=768%2C881&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 212px) 100vw, 212px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>Elise &amp; me on Mother&#8217;s Day 2019</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>My heart immediately felt lighter and a sense of peace came over me as we began to sing and laugh. &nbsp;I was reminded of an exercise we did with a depression counselor a few years ago that laughter is one of the best antidotes for sadness. &nbsp;When you are laughing you can not feel anxious, angry or sad.  By focusing on adding more laughter to your life you become able to shift perspective and open to more light and carefree possibilities. &nbsp;When was the last time you had a really good laugh? I hope it was today.  The exercise we did was watch a sitcom and pay attention to the laugh track, laughing really is contagious and it works.<br></p>



<p>Laughter through tears is an amazing thing. &nbsp;The opportunity to feel my feelings thoroughly in the moment. &nbsp;To feel the deep sadness of loss and the release through tears followed by the carefree lightness of laughter. &nbsp;I am grateful for the regular release of stress and sadness through tears  and the daily endorphins and lightness through laughter. &nbsp;I hope you are enjoying the range of your emotions and that you have a safe place to cry on occasion and wonderful things to laugh and smile about each and every day.<br></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/05/15/laughter-through-tears/">Laughter through tears</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1625</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Just keep swimming</title>
		<link>/2019/05/10/just-keep-swimming/</link>
					<comments>/2019/05/10/just-keep-swimming/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Caroline Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 21:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beach Walk and Talk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1611</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Last week was a tough week; everyone has them.  Sunday I flew to Maryland, had a fabulous breakfast with an amazing friend, and prepared to step in and help another friend as she underwent cancer surgery.  I knew the hospital stay would be tough and I was ready, I’d meditated, gotten enough sleep and done &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2019/05/10/just-keep-swimming/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Just keep swimming</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/05/10/just-keep-swimming/">Just keep swimming</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<ul class="is-layout-flex wp-block-gallery-1 wp-block-gallery columns-2 is-cropped"><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img decoding="async" width="543" height="521" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2019-04-29-Denise.jpg?resize=543%2C521&#038;ssl=1" alt="" data-id="1612" data-link="/?attachment_id=1612" class="wp-image-1612" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2019-04-29-Denise.jpg?w=543&amp;ssl=1 543w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2019-04-29-Denise.jpg?resize=300%2C288&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2019-04-29-Denise.jpg?resize=350%2C336&amp;ssl=1 350w" sizes="(max-width: 543px) 100vw, 543px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></li><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img decoding="async" width="788" height="1024" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2018-07-23-Gigi-1.jpg?resize=788%2C1024&#038;ssl=1" alt="" data-id="1615" data-link="/?attachment_id=1615" class="wp-image-1615" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2018-07-23-Gigi-1.jpg?resize=788%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 788w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2018-07-23-Gigi-1.jpg?resize=231%2C300&amp;ssl=1 231w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2018-07-23-Gigi-1.jpg?resize=768%2C998&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/2018-07-23-Gigi-1.jpg?w=834&amp;ssl=1 834w" sizes="(max-width: 788px) 100vw, 788px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></li></ul>



<p>Last week was a tough week; everyone has them.  Sunday I flew to Maryland, had a fabulous breakfast with an amazing friend, and prepared to step in and help another friend as she underwent cancer surgery.  I knew the hospital stay would be tough and I was ready, I’d meditated, gotten enough sleep and done what needed to be done at home and work to be away for a week.  I’d also reached out to my swim partner and knew I’d get some laps in.<br></p>



<p>But the week was harder than I planned for. &nbsp;The surgery was more complex than expected, requiring a longer stay in the hospital. &nbsp;A dear friend’s mother died Monday; I found out Tuesday the break to my father’s foot was more complex than expected; and on Friday my 98-year-old Grandmother who I was named for passed away. &nbsp;It was one of those weeks where my emotions were on the surface at all times.  My emotions made themselves known as I could not stop crying while standing in church on Sunday and I refused to leave the house for the rest of the day. Noah spent Sunday with family at a Cinco de Mayo party and I stayed home. My emotions were raw and I needed time to refuel. &nbsp;It was the right and perfect thing for me to do, to get quiet and reset.  I went for a run with Elise and spent the rest of the day in silence.<br></p>



<p>That’s all well and good, but what about Monday morning? &nbsp;After a week away, it was time to get back to work.  Thankfully, Noah and I have now been time blocking for 7 months and we have set up a schedule. I was able to slip into the schedule and move through the actions physically until my emotions caught up with me and I felt more like myself. &nbsp;<br></p>



<p>Mondays are for taking care of business (TCB). &nbsp;We start the day with a walk on the beach.  These beach walks began as a time for us to talk about how we wanted to set up the administrative parts of the business. &nbsp;Honestly, I was much more willing to listen to Noah’s ideas if I was walking on the beach.  We were new at working together and I was not sure how all of this togetherness was going to go. &nbsp;The Monday beach walks have evolved into deeper discussions about the work we are doing and how the death of his mother and brother have completely changed our lives.  It has become clearer and clearer every week that for some reason we are in a unique position to help others navigate this legal process that no one likes to think about. &nbsp;<br></p>



<p>Illness and death are part of everyone’s lives, as I was reminded of this week. &nbsp;I was also very aware this last week that families and friends were coming together. I talked to my parents more this last week than I usually do, spoke to my siblings and extended family. &nbsp;Spent time with friends and shared memories as well as delicious food.<br></p>



<p>So I am going to just keep swimming. &nbsp;These newsletters are scheduled for Tuesday but this week it’s Friday. &nbsp;We met with clients, Noah drafted documents while I balanced the books, we had coffee with new people and even got in some training. &nbsp;It was a good work week.  My heart is still sore and it will be for awhile, but I am going to keep swimming and I hope you will too.<br></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/05/10/just-keep-swimming/">Just keep swimming</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2019/05/10/just-keep-swimming/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1611</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Making the appointment</title>
		<link>/2019/04/23/making-the-appointment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Caroline Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 21:31:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beach Walk and Talk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1571</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Making the appointment to move forward on getting your affairs in order is huge. &#160;I think many people feel unwilling to move forward with making a will until they are clear on who they would name as beneficiaries, guardians or even health care surrogates. &#160;&#160;The funny thing about that is that if it is unclear &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2019/04/23/making-the-appointment/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Making the appointment</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/04/23/making-the-appointment/">Making the appointment</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/2019-04-21-Noah-Peter.jpg?resize=324%2C204&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1573" width="324" height="204" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p> Making the appointment to move forward on getting your affairs in order is huge. &nbsp;I think many people feel unwilling to move forward with making a will until they are clear on who they would name as beneficiaries, guardians or even health care surrogates. &nbsp;&nbsp;The funny thing about that is that if it is unclear to you now while you are living  it is going to be even more unclear to those family members left behind when you are no longer here.<br></p>



<p>Families are messy, relationships are messy and that is the greatest news of all.  Yesterday I had the pleasure of attending a beautiful sunrise service with my daughter and friends and then an Easter Brunch with extended family and friends.  The sermon was on the mess and the sadness of the burning of Notre Dame and the mess and the sadness of Holy week.  The  conclusion for me was that faith is what keeps us going, faith that the church will be rebuilt, and faith that religious beliefs are not for naught. <br></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/2019-04-21-Noah-Elise-768x1024.jpg?resize=238%2C316&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1572" width="238" height="316" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/2019-04-21-Noah-Elise.jpg?resize=768%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/2019-04-21-Noah-Elise.jpg?resize=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1 225w" sizes="(max-width: 238px) 100vw, 238px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p>The Easter Brunch was a wonderful opportunity to watch family and friends come together and enjoy fabulous food and childish egg hunt fun. &nbsp;&nbsp;Our family has all the things that family has. It has heartache from divorce and death and it has love and joy from births and partnerships.  There was space during the gathering to talk with those I have not seen since we moved back to Miami, to meet new spouses and loved ones. &nbsp;To watch people who I remember as teenagers now navigating parenthood and their parents evolving as grandparents.<br></p>



<p>The facts of how these people are related either by love or by blood are complex. &nbsp;However you can not tell this by looking at the photos.  The photos are of children laughing and adults enjoying the afternoon. &nbsp;It is going to be unclear how the people left behind will navigate once you are no longer here.  However, I am certain that your heart will be lighter if you move forward and begin making plans. &nbsp;Make the appointment to begin putting your plans in place, there is never going to be a perfect time to do it.</p>



<p><a href="https://app.acuityscheduling.com/schedule.php?owner=17212147&#038;appointmentType=9159851" target="_blank" class="acuity-embed-button" style="background: #002e5d; color: #fff; padding: 8px 12px; border: 0px; -webkit-box-shadow: 0 -2px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15) inset;-moz-box-shadow: 0 -2px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15) inset;box-shadow: 0 -2px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15) inset;border-radius: 4px; text-decoration: none; display: inline-block;" rel="noopener noreferrer">Schedule Appointment</a><link rel="stylesheet" href="https://embed.acuityscheduling.com/embed/button/17212147.css" id="acuity-button-styles" /><script src="https://embed.acuityscheduling.com/embed/button/17212147.js" async></script></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/04/23/making-the-appointment/">Making the appointment</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1571</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Juxtapose</title>
		<link>/2019/04/16/juxtapose/</link>
					<comments>/2019/04/16/juxtapose/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Caroline Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 22:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beach Walk and Talk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Estate Planning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1561</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>While sitting in church this last Sunday, listening to the Palm Sunday sermon, the significance of this juxtaposition that occurs in so many areas of life struck me. In the Christian faith, this week is a time where the excitement and joy of togetherness and celebration is juxtaposed with the devastation of loss. Conflicting thoughts &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2019/04/16/juxtapose/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Juxtapose</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/04/16/juxtapose/">Juxtapose</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/2019-04-15-beachwalk.jpg?resize=337%2C450&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-1562" width="337" height="450" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>



<p>While sitting in church this last Sunday, listening to the Palm Sunday sermon, the significance of this juxtaposition that occurs in so many areas of life struck me. In the Christian faith, this week is a time where the excitement and joy of togetherness and celebration is juxtaposed with the devastation of loss. Conflicting thoughts and feelings are felt at the same time. I am often one to avoid that level of intense feelings. My thoughts centered with this idea of intense feelings caused by a conflicting series of events.  </p>



<p>As Noah mentioned in <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.facebook.com/theClementsFirm/videos/2595636767329903/" target="_blank">his recording</a>, when we got the call that his Grandfather would be moving into Hospice recently, he immediately asked our children if they would like to accompany him, and then he bought plane tickets to fly to California. This is an action Noah has taken several times. He flew to Miami when Michael and Ashley were in the fatal car accident in 2006. He flew to Miami again to help move his father into in-home Hospice in 2009. He flew to Durham, NC when his mother was moved to Hospice in 2017, the same place where he spent a year as she received her double lung transplant 5 years prior. And when we got the call that Michael was in ICU in January 2018, again he flew to Miami to spend the last month with his brother.</p>



<p>During each of these times, we knew of the heartache that was meeting Noah on the other side of the flight, yet each time I encouraged him to get on the plane and go.  Each time I stayed home with our children, doing my best to keep life moving forward. Each time the lives of others changed dramatically. Each time Noah strengthened relationships as he felt the loss of one.</p>



<p>Life presents such complexity and sad sweetness to show up for loss and at the same time to build stronger connection in other relationships. How can the event of losing a loved one also be a conduit for bringing those left behind together and strengthening the connections they share?  </p>



<p>I am aware that it is a total gift that Noah has been able to be there for each of these events. It is not a given that loved ones will come together during these times. Nor is it a given that connection will be made during these times. Just because you are in the same room it does not guarantee that connection will be made. As we learned during our recent workshop in Colorado, connection requires honest safe sharing where participants feel validation and acceptance, and feel heard and understood.</p>



<p>The <a href="/services/estate-planning/">estate planning </a>work Noah and I are doing <a href="/2019/03/18/building-connection-can-estate-planning-improve-relationships/">helps families have more connection.</a> We are aware that times of loss often bring about a lot of hurt feelings, defensiveness and assumptions which all decrease connection. I encourage you to attend <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Noah’s presentation on the 25th (opens in a new tab)" href="https://theclementsfirm.as.me/EPWorkshop" target="_blank">Noah’s presentation on the 26th</a> to hear more about how you can help your family.</p>



<p>I experienced the intense conflicting thoughts and feelings for each of these trips that Noah made. Looking at this last trip to see his Grandfather, I am so grateful he went. The trip was full of sadness but also the strength of coming together with his cousins to share memories and also the gift of being together.</p>



<p>As you are pulled into sadness over loss (it happens to all of us), I encourage you to look for those beautiful moments. For me it was the blue canary by the pool that stayed all day when Ashley passed. It was the “life party” Noah&#8217;s father insisted on having before he passed to see all his old friends. It was knowing Noah, Michael and Grace were together with Ricky in her final moments. It was knowing whether or not Grace was having dinner with her brothers based on the choice of barbecue restaurant. It is here with the connection we have formed with Melissa’s family after Michael’s passing, and the warmth and guidance we are receiving from this tight knit group. And finally, it was the tales of Noah&#8217;s cousins singing old folk songs for Grandpa Sid.</p>



<p>Yes there is a lot of sadness, but there are also the most beautiful of memories. I am learning to sit with the conflicting feelings. And as Noah said at Michael’s funeral, “share your stories of loved ones often.” I’d love to have you make me smile with a beautiful memory &#8211; please share one with me.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2019/04/16/juxtapose/">Juxtapose</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2019/04/16/juxtapose/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1561</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
