<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Washington Archives - The Clements Firm</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/washington/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/tag/washington/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 15:58:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/cropped-TCFLogo012419White-1.png?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>Washington Archives - The Clements Firm</title>
	<link>/tag/washington/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21395931</site>	<item>
		<title>DEA Chemists: In Drug Cases, Sometimes They Just Make It Up</title>
		<link>/2013/11/02/dea-chemists-in-drug-cases-sometimes-they-just-make-it-up/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 18:41:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Criminal Law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[District of Columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drug Cases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evidence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jury Trials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maryland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Misdemeanors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pre-trial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scientific Evidence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Washington]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://new.theclementsfirm.com/?p=463</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I have written before how in criminal drug prosecutions, the government analyst should be cross-examined&#160;&#160;and their case file and other information should be requested to prepare a defense case. A colleague sent me a great example of this effort paying off. A chemist at the DEA Mid-Atlantic Laboratory wrote in a report that three samples &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2013/11/02/dea-chemists-in-drug-cases-sometimes-they-just-make-it-up/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">DEA Chemists: In Drug Cases, Sometimes They Just Make It Up</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/11/02/dea-chemists-in-drug-cases-sometimes-they-just-make-it-up/">DEA Chemists: In Drug Cases, Sometimes They Just Make It Up</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have written before how in criminal drug prosecutions, the government analyst should be <a title="In Drug Cases, Cross-Examine that “Expert”!" href="http://new.theclementsfirm.com/in-drug-cases-cross-examine-that-expert/">cross-examined&nbsp;</a>&nbsp;and their case file and other information <a title="Why It’s Important To Get Drug Lab Info In Drug Cases" href="http://new.theclementsfirm.com/why-its-important-to-get-drug-lab-info-in-drug-cases/">should be requested</a> to prepare a defense case. A colleague sent me a great example of this effort paying off.</p>
<figure id="attachment_464" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-464" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/new.theclementsfirm.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/D_L.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-464" alt="D-L Color Test of Three Suspected Marijuana Samples" src="https://i0.wp.com/new.theclementsfirm.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/D_L-300x225.jpg?resize=300%2C225" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/D_L.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/D_L.jpg?resize=1024%2C768&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/D_L.jpg?resize=800%2C600&amp;ssl=1 800w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/D_L.jpg?w=1600&amp;ssl=1 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-464" class="wp-caption-text">D-L Color Test of Three Suspected Marijuana Samples</figcaption></figure>
<p>A chemist at the DEA Mid-Atlantic Laboratory wrote in a report that three samples suspected to be marijuana turned purple in a <a href="http://www.thetruthaboutforensicscience.com/the-myth-of-specific-identification-of-marijuana-in-criminal-court-part-4/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Duquenois-Levine color test.</a> The problem is that the picture of the test (not included in the report but in the analyst&#8217;s case-file) showed only one sample that might conceivably indicate the sample was marijuana (and even that one is weak).<span id="more-463"></span></p>
<p>Is there any reason for the analyst to photograph the color test against a green background other than to obscure the real colors obtained? Compare the picture above against an example of what the D-L color test should look like (copied from <a href="http://www.thetruthaboutforensicscience.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Justin McShane</a>&#8216;s site for purposes of illustration and comment):</p>
<figure style="width: 312px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" alt="" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.thetruthaboutforensicscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/modified-Duquenois-Levine.png?resize=312%2C404" width="312" height="404"  data-recalc-dims="1"><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">This is what a Duquenois-Levine color test of marijuana should look like. The top is purple and the bottom is pink.</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-size: 14px; color: #444444; line-height: 1.7;">The truth is that color tests like these are not specific for marijuana, meaning that the test may show a color even if the sample is not marijuana &#8211; there&#8217;s a huge list of plants and chemicals that could cause a purple or purple-ish color. But if there is no color at all, the chemists tell us in their testimony that this would indicate that the sample is not marijuana. So by that token, the lack of color in the test would be evidence that the sample is not marijuana. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14px; color: #444444; line-height: 1.7;">You can only get this evidence by requesting the information from the government and cross-examining their expert.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/11/02/dea-chemists-in-drug-cases-sometimes-they-just-make-it-up/">DEA Chemists: In Drug Cases, Sometimes They Just Make It Up</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">463</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Counsel&#8217;s Questionable Testimony in Support of DC&#8217;s Draconian Liquid PCP Possession Penalties</title>
		<link>/2013/09/02/special-counsels-questionable-testimony-in-support-of-dcs-draconian-liquid-pcp-possession-penalties/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 22:16:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Criminal Law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[District of Columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drug Cases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Felonies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Washington]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://new.theclementsfirm.com/?p=397</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Unlike every other drug you can (illegally) possess in the District, the D.C. Council has made possession of any amount of liquid PCP a felony punishable by up to 3 years and/or $3000 fine.* In part, this was because the D.C. Council felt that PCP is a more dangerous drug than other so-called &#8220;hard drugs,&#8221; &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2013/09/02/special-counsels-questionable-testimony-in-support-of-dcs-draconian-liquid-pcp-possession-penalties/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Special Counsel&#8217;s Questionable Testimony in Support of DC&#8217;s Draconian Liquid PCP Possession Penalties</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/09/02/special-counsels-questionable-testimony-in-support-of-dcs-draconian-liquid-pcp-possession-penalties/">Special Counsel&#8217;s Questionable Testimony in Support of DC&#8217;s Draconian Liquid PCP Possession Penalties</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Unlike every other drug you can (illegally) possess in the District, the D.C. Council has made possession of any amount of liquid PCP a felony punishable by up to 3 years and/or $3000 fine.* In part, this was because the D.C. Council felt that PCP is a more dangerous drug than other so-called &#8220;hard drugs,&#8221; in that the Council believes that:</p>
<blockquote><p>Although a person might commit a crime related to heroin or cocaine (usually a robbery to obtain the money to purchase the heroin or cocaine), individuals often commit crimes <em>because</em> they are on PCP. PCP give users the feeling of strength and invulnerability.</p></blockquote>
<p>Obviously, the D.C. Council has collectively forgotten the &#8217;80&#8217;s and the heyday of powder cocaine. Anyway, the D.C. Council then goes on to list several bizarre crimes committed on PCP as testified to by Patricia Riley, special council to the U.S. Attorney for D.C. Ms. Riley testified that:</p>
<blockquote><p>A friend I talked to about this testimony this morning remembered a case where a man stabbed his girlfriend 57 times. I remember a case where a woman put her baby in the microwave and turned it on.</p></blockquote>
<p>There was no support or testimony about any actions Ms. Riley may have taken to verify that these acts actually occurred. Unsupported urban legends don&#8217;t belong in sworn testimony to the D.C. Council.<span id="more-397"></span></p>
<p>While there have been a <a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/8301-504083_162-20064806-504083.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">couple</a> of <a href="http://www.foxnews.com/us/2011/06/21/calif-mom-arrested-after-baby-dies-in-microwave/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">cases</a> where a <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/local/daily/sept99/microwave.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">woman</a> microwaved a baby, and a <a href="http://abclocal.go.com/ktrk/story?section=news/local&amp;id=6017940" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">few</a> <a href="http://www.foxnews.com/story/0,2933,303736,00.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">more</a> where a <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2008/mar/27/usa.internationalcrime1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">man</a> was <a href="http://www.examiner.com/article/father-puts-baby-microwave-says-he-was-drunk-and-high" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">involved</a>, none had any link to PCP (although <a href="http://www.examiner.com/article/father-puts-baby-microwave-says-he-was-drunk-and-high" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">one case</a> where a man put his baby in the microwave after smoking pot all day and splitting a fifth of whiskey with his girlfriend claimed that the marijuana may have been laced with PCP or another hallucinogen). I could find absolutely no news articles about a man stabbing her girlfriend 57 times while high on PCP &#8211; one would expect this to make the news, no? But why let truth get in the way of a good story?</p>
<p>Ms. Riley also listed case studies of crimes involving PCP, which presumably were more fact based (I am not going to check each one), but that does not excuse the fact that she felt the need to testify to the above unsupported horror stories to get the Council to pass this draconian law.</p>
<p>Anyway, I certainly don&#8217;t support PCP or other drug use, but I don&#8217;t judge it either (unless you&#8217;re one of my children, in which case, Bad Kiddie!). But the fact is, no drug compares to alcohol when considering involvement in violent crime. <a href="http://www.ncadd.org/index.php/learn-about-alcohol/alcohol-and-crime">The National Council on Alcoholism and Drug Dependence</a> reports, based on a review of DOJ statistics, that alcohol is involved in 40% of all violent crime in the U.S. But we ignore the link between alcohol and crime because we tried that unsuccessfully in Prohibition.</p>
<p>The real reason for the extra-harsh penalties for possession of liquid PCP is that the D.C. Council believes that liquid PCP is more consistent with distribution than use, but doesn&#8217;t want to make prosecutors have to prove it.  Notwithstanding its recounting of the horrors committed by PCP users, the D.C. Council says that its action &#8220;should not be considered as a bill to punish users.&#8221; The Council stated its belief that &#8220;sellers typically carry liquid, [but] users typically carry one or two dippers.&#8221; This shows that the D.C. Council intended to incorporate an unrebuttable presumption that a person possessing liquid PCP intended to distribute, a presumption that results in unconstitutional burden shifting to defendants.</p>
<p>* These are maximum penalties, not the likely penalties; as a felony, sentencing would most likely follow the <a href="http://acs.dc.gov/acs/frames.asp?doc=/acs/lib/acs/pdf/2013_Voluntary_Sentencing_Guidelines_Manual.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">sentencing guidelines</a>, which would recommend 6-18 months (some or all of which could be suspended) for conviction for possession of liquid PCP for a person with very little criminal history. By contrast, simple possession of other drugs, including PCP in any other form (powder, dipper, etc.) is a misdemeanor with a maximum sentence of 180 days (also not the likely sentence in many cases).</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/09/02/special-counsels-questionable-testimony-in-support-of-dcs-draconian-liquid-pcp-possession-penalties/">Special Counsel&#8217;s Questionable Testimony in Support of DC&#8217;s Draconian Liquid PCP Possession Penalties</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">397</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>DC Post-and-Forfeit Is Not A Conviction For Immigration Purposes</title>
		<link>/2013/07/08/dc-post-and-forfeit-is-not-a-conviction-for-immigration-purposes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2013 04:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Criminal Law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Criminal Immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[District]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Immigration Court]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Misdemeanors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Removal Defence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Statutory Interpretation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Washington]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://new.theclementsfirm.com/?p=421</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A colleague recently asked me whether the DC post-and-forfeit procedure after arrest is properly considered a conviction under federal and immigration law. The simple answer is that the post-and-forfeit procedure does not equate to a conviction. Under immigration laws, a conviction is defined as follows (in 8 U.S.C. § 1101(a)(48)(A)): The term &#8220;conviction&#8221; means, with respect &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2013/07/08/dc-post-and-forfeit-is-not-a-conviction-for-immigration-purposes/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">DC Post-and-Forfeit Is Not A Conviction For Immigration Purposes</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/07/08/dc-post-and-forfeit-is-not-a-conviction-for-immigration-purposes/">DC Post-and-Forfeit Is Not A Conviction For Immigration Purposes</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A colleague recently asked me whether the DC post-and-forfeit procedure after arrest is properly considered a conviction under federal and immigration law. The simple answer is that the post-and-forfeit procedure does not equate to a conviction.<span id="more-421"></span></p>
<p>Under immigration laws, a conviction is defined as follows (in <a href="http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/8/1101" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">8 U.S.C. § 1101(a)(48)(A)</a>):</p>
<blockquote><p>The term &#8220;conviction&#8221; means, with respect to an alien, a formal judgment of guilt of the alien entered by a court or, if adjudication of guilt has been withheld, where:</p>
<p>(i) a judge or jury has found the alien guilty or the alien has entered a plea of guilty or nolo contendere or has admitted sufficient facts to warrant a finding of guilt, and</p>
<p>(ii) the judge has ordered some form of punishment, penalty, or restraint on the alien’s liberty to be imposed.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Under this definition, the DC post-and-forfeit procedure does not involve a conviction.</p>
<p>The DC code regarding its post-and-forfeit procedure is as follows:</p>
<blockquote><p>§5-335.01. Enforcement of the post-and-forfeit procedure.</p>
<p>(a) For the purposes of this section, the term “post-and-forfeit procedure” shall mean the procedure enforced as part of the criminal justice system in the District of Columbia whereby a person charged with certain misdemeanors may simultaneously post and forfeit an amount as collateral (which otherwise would serve as security upon release to ensure the arrestee’s appearance at trial) and thereby obtain a full and final resolution of the criminal charge.</p>
<p>(b) The resolution of a criminal charge using the post-and-forfeit procedure is not a conviction of a crime and shall not be equated to a criminal conviction. The fact that a person resolved a charge using the post-and-forfeit procedure may not be relied upon by any court of the District of Columbia or any agency of the District of Columbia in any subsequent criminal, civil, or administrative proceeding or administrative action to impose any sanction, penalty, enhanced sentence, or civil disability.</p></blockquote>
<p>One thing that is apparent is that there is no admission or adjudication of guilt in the post-and-forfeit procedure and no judge imposes a punishment.</p>
<p>The federal district court in DC has also determined that the post-and-forfeit procedure does not involve a conviction. For example, in a recent case, the DC district court stated that “posting and forfeiting is not an admission of guilt, and it does not result in a criminal conviction.” <a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=9516433629804700761" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Fox v. District of Columbia</em>, 851 F. Supp. 2d 20, 25 (D.D.C. 2012)</a>. The court went on to explain that “the payment does not result in a criminal conviction and it cannot trigger any of the collateral consequences of a criminal conviction, [therefore] it is not appropriately likened to a criminal sentence.” <em>Id.</em> at 31.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/07/08/dc-post-and-forfeit-is-not-a-conviction-for-immigration-purposes/">DC Post-and-Forfeit Is Not A Conviction For Immigration Purposes</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">421</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Need For Discretion</title>
		<link>/2013/06/09/the-need-for-discretion/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 00:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Criminal Law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crime Involving Moral Turpitude]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Criminal Immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[District of Columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Felonies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Immigration Court]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maryland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Removal Defence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Washington]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://new.theclementsfirm.com/?p=399</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Recently, in browsing a well-known local lawyer&#8217;s website, I found the following &#8220;News&#8221; article on their blog: Attorney X convinced a [local] prosecutor to dismiss Armed Robbery charges, all felonies, and all gun charges, despite the defendant being caught nearly red-handed with a shotgun in his fleeing vehicle. The defendant plead to Second Degree Assault, &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2013/06/09/the-need-for-discretion/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">The Need For Discretion</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/06/09/the-need-for-discretion/">The Need For Discretion</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Recently, in browsing a well-known local lawyer&#8217;s website, I found the following &#8220;News&#8221; article on their blog:</p>
<blockquote><p>Attorney X convinced a [local] prosecutor to dismiss Armed Robbery charges, all felonies, and all gun charges, despite the defendant being caught nearly red-handed with a shotgun in his fleeing vehicle.</p>
<p>The defendant plead to Second Degree Assault, a misdemeanor, giving him a strong chance to avoid certain deportation that he would have faced with any felony or gun charge. He will be eligible for parole in one month.</p></blockquote>
<p>While there may be some ethical concern over publicizing past successes without adequately informing potential clients that there is no guarantee of such success in any particular case, that is not my main concern. The biggest problem with this self-serving news article is that it may harm the client in the future.<span id="more-399"></span></p>
<p>What if the ICE Assistant Chief Counsel (the title of immigration prosecutors) in a future deportation case against that client stumbles across this &#8220;article&#8221;? Unfortunately, it would be all too easy for the ICE prosecutor to find. Can the admission by the client&#8217;s attorney be used to try to form the requisite admission of facts?</p>
<p>The fact that this article is not part of the official record of conviction does not end the inquiry &#8211; admission of underlying facts can also be used to show that a conviction is one that leads to removability or deportation. The client would then be in the position of arguing that although his attorney may have admitted the underlying facts, he did not do so himself. Would that argument be successful? I don&#8217;t think anyone knows at this point, but it&#8217;s much better to avoid the situation altogether.</p>
<p>And this situation is avoidable. Is it so important to promote the practice that the attorney should put this up in the first place? Is this attorney hoping that other potential clients &#8220;caught nearly red-handed&#8221; with guns in their fleeing cars will think the attorney will also get them off?</p>
<p>I think a potential client would be better served in knowing that no matter what the alleged facts in their case, the attorney will never divulge them to serve the attorney&#8217;s own interests. They should not be divulged at any time except to the extent that it might help the client.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/06/09/the-need-for-discretion/">The Need For Discretion</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">399</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
