<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Maryland Archives - The Clements Firm</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/maryland/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/tag/maryland/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 15:54:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/cropped-TCFLogo012419White-1.png?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>Maryland Archives - The Clements Firm</title>
	<link>/tag/maryland/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21395931</site>	<item>
		<title>DEA Chemists: In Drug Cases, Sometimes They Just Make It Up</title>
		<link>/2013/11/02/dea-chemists-in-drug-cases-sometimes-they-just-make-it-up/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 18:41:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Criminal Law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[District of Columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drug Cases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evidence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jury Trials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maryland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Misdemeanors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pre-trial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scientific Evidence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Washington]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://new.theclementsfirm.com/?p=463</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I have written before how in criminal drug prosecutions, the government analyst should be cross-examined&#160;&#160;and their case file and other information should be requested to prepare a defense case. A colleague sent me a great example of this effort paying off. A chemist at the DEA Mid-Atlantic Laboratory wrote in a report that three samples &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2013/11/02/dea-chemists-in-drug-cases-sometimes-they-just-make-it-up/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">DEA Chemists: In Drug Cases, Sometimes They Just Make It Up</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/11/02/dea-chemists-in-drug-cases-sometimes-they-just-make-it-up/">DEA Chemists: In Drug Cases, Sometimes They Just Make It Up</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have written before how in criminal drug prosecutions, the government analyst should be <a title="In Drug Cases, Cross-Examine that “Expert”!" href="http://new.theclementsfirm.com/in-drug-cases-cross-examine-that-expert/">cross-examined&nbsp;</a>&nbsp;and their case file and other information <a title="Why It’s Important To Get Drug Lab Info In Drug Cases" href="http://new.theclementsfirm.com/why-its-important-to-get-drug-lab-info-in-drug-cases/">should be requested</a> to prepare a defense case. A colleague sent me a great example of this effort paying off.</p>
<figure id="attachment_464" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-464" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/new.theclementsfirm.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/D_L.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-464" alt="D-L Color Test of Three Suspected Marijuana Samples" src="https://i0.wp.com/new.theclementsfirm.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/D_L-300x225.jpg?resize=300%2C225" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/D_L.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/D_L.jpg?resize=1024%2C768&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/D_L.jpg?resize=800%2C600&amp;ssl=1 800w, https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/D_L.jpg?w=1600&amp;ssl=1 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-464" class="wp-caption-text">D-L Color Test of Three Suspected Marijuana Samples</figcaption></figure>
<p>A chemist at the DEA Mid-Atlantic Laboratory wrote in a report that three samples suspected to be marijuana turned purple in a <a href="http://www.thetruthaboutforensicscience.com/the-myth-of-specific-identification-of-marijuana-in-criminal-court-part-4/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Duquenois-Levine color test.</a> The problem is that the picture of the test (not included in the report but in the analyst&#8217;s case-file) showed only one sample that might conceivably indicate the sample was marijuana (and even that one is weak).<span id="more-463"></span></p>
<p>Is there any reason for the analyst to photograph the color test against a green background other than to obscure the real colors obtained? Compare the picture above against an example of what the D-L color test should look like (copied from <a href="http://www.thetruthaboutforensicscience.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Justin McShane</a>&#8216;s site for purposes of illustration and comment):</p>
<figure style="width: 312px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" alt="" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.thetruthaboutforensicscience.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/modified-Duquenois-Levine.png?resize=312%2C404" width="312" height="404"  data-recalc-dims="1"><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">This is what a Duquenois-Levine color test of marijuana should look like. The top is purple and the bottom is pink.</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-size: 14px; color: #444444; line-height: 1.7;">The truth is that color tests like these are not specific for marijuana, meaning that the test may show a color even if the sample is not marijuana &#8211; there&#8217;s a huge list of plants and chemicals that could cause a purple or purple-ish color. But if there is no color at all, the chemists tell us in their testimony that this would indicate that the sample is not marijuana. So by that token, the lack of color in the test would be evidence that the sample is not marijuana. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 14px; color: #444444; line-height: 1.7;">You can only get this evidence by requesting the information from the government and cross-examining their expert.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/11/02/dea-chemists-in-drug-cases-sometimes-they-just-make-it-up/">DEA Chemists: In Drug Cases, Sometimes They Just Make It Up</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">463</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Need For Discretion</title>
		<link>/2013/06/09/the-need-for-discretion/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 00:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Criminal Law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crime Involving Moral Turpitude]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Criminal Immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[District of Columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Felonies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Immigration Court]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maryland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Removal Defence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Washington]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://new.theclementsfirm.com/?p=399</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Recently, in browsing a well-known local lawyer&#8217;s website, I found the following &#8220;News&#8221; article on their blog: Attorney X convinced a [local] prosecutor to dismiss Armed Robbery charges, all felonies, and all gun charges, despite the defendant being caught nearly red-handed with a shotgun in his fleeing vehicle. The defendant plead to Second Degree Assault, &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2013/06/09/the-need-for-discretion/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">The Need For Discretion</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/06/09/the-need-for-discretion/">The Need For Discretion</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Recently, in browsing a well-known local lawyer&#8217;s website, I found the following &#8220;News&#8221; article on their blog:</p>
<blockquote><p>Attorney X convinced a [local] prosecutor to dismiss Armed Robbery charges, all felonies, and all gun charges, despite the defendant being caught nearly red-handed with a shotgun in his fleeing vehicle.</p>
<p>The defendant plead to Second Degree Assault, a misdemeanor, giving him a strong chance to avoid certain deportation that he would have faced with any felony or gun charge. He will be eligible for parole in one month.</p></blockquote>
<p>While there may be some ethical concern over publicizing past successes without adequately informing potential clients that there is no guarantee of such success in any particular case, that is not my main concern. The biggest problem with this self-serving news article is that it may harm the client in the future.<span id="more-399"></span></p>
<p>What if the ICE Assistant Chief Counsel (the title of immigration prosecutors) in a future deportation case against that client stumbles across this &#8220;article&#8221;? Unfortunately, it would be all too easy for the ICE prosecutor to find. Can the admission by the client&#8217;s attorney be used to try to form the requisite admission of facts?</p>
<p>The fact that this article is not part of the official record of conviction does not end the inquiry &#8211; admission of underlying facts can also be used to show that a conviction is one that leads to removability or deportation. The client would then be in the position of arguing that although his attorney may have admitted the underlying facts, he did not do so himself. Would that argument be successful? I don&#8217;t think anyone knows at this point, but it&#8217;s much better to avoid the situation altogether.</p>
<p>And this situation is avoidable. Is it so important to promote the practice that the attorney should put this up in the first place? Is this attorney hoping that other potential clients &#8220;caught nearly red-handed&#8221; with guns in their fleeing cars will think the attorney will also get them off?</p>
<p>I think a potential client would be better served in knowing that no matter what the alleged facts in their case, the attorney will never divulge them to serve the attorney&#8217;s own interests. They should not be divulged at any time except to the extent that it might help the client.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/06/09/the-need-for-discretion/">The Need For Discretion</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">399</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
