<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Criminal Immigration Archives - The Clements Firm</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/criminal-immigration/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/tag/criminal-immigration/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 15:58:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://i0.wp.com/theclementsfirm.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/cropped-TCFLogo012419White-1.png?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>Criminal Immigration Archives - The Clements Firm</title>
	<link>/tag/criminal-immigration/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21395931</site>	<item>
		<title>To the Permanent Resident Pleading Guilty to Drug Offense and Counting on Cancellation of Removal: Don&#8217;t</title>
		<link>/2013/09/14/to-the-permanent-resident-pleading-guilty-to-drug-offense-and-counting-on-cancellation-of-removal-dont/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 22:29:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Criminal Law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Criminal Immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pre-trial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trials]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://new.theclementsfirm.com/?p=429</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I was consulted on a case the other day where a person had pleaded guilty to misdemeanor possession (of something that&#8217;s not marijuana) over his lawyer&#8217;s warnings that it make him removable. The judge also (post-Padilla) made sure that the person knew that there could be immigration consequences. But all the person could hear was &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2013/09/14/to-the-permanent-resident-pleading-guilty-to-drug-offense-and-counting-on-cancellation-of-removal-dont/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">To the Permanent Resident Pleading Guilty to Drug Offense and Counting on Cancellation of Removal: Don&#8217;t</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/09/14/to-the-permanent-resident-pleading-guilty-to-drug-offense-and-counting-on-cancellation-of-removal-dont/">To the Permanent Resident Pleading Guilty to Drug Offense and Counting on Cancellation of Removal: Don&#8217;t</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was consulted on a case the other day where a person had pleaded guilty to misdemeanor possession (of something that&#8217;s not marijuana) over his lawyer&#8217;s warnings that it make him removable. The judge also (post-Padilla) made sure that the person knew that there could be immigration consequences. But all the person could hear was that the prosecutor would be asking for probation if he accepted the plea deal (which was also the likely sentence even after trial).</p>
<p>So you can guess what happened. After an ill-advised trip abroad, the person received a Notice to Appear in immigration court. As a legal permanent resident with medical issues, he was eligible for cancellation of removal (which he ended up getting, with a sympathetic judge). But it could easily have gone the other way. Cancellation is a discretionary remedy, which means that the judge could have denied it if he had a good reason to do so.<span id="more-429"></span></p>
<p>I would recommend that a legal permanent resident or anyone else who is not a citizen do <a title="In Drug Cases, Cross-Examine that “Expert”!" href="http://new.theclementsfirm.com/in-drug-cases-cross-examine-that-expert/">everything</a> <a title="Why It’s Important To Get Drug Lab Info In Drug Cases" href="http://new.theclementsfirm.com/why-its-important-to-get-drug-lab-info-in-drug-cases/">possible</a> to <a title="If a Misdemeanor Could Lead to Removal of a Non-Citizen, the Charge *Might Be* Jury-Demandable In DC" href="http://new.theclementsfirm.com/if-a-misdemeanor-could-lead-to-removal-of-a-non-citizen-the-charge-might-be-jury-demandable-in-dc/">fight</a> getting a controlled substance conviction, which makes a person removable under the immigration laws  (and in most cases, I recommend that citizens also fight). When you plead guilty you have a 100% chance of conviction. Unless you are getting a significant benefit (having the government drop other charges, etc), it rarely makes sense to plead guilty to a misdemeanor possession charge. There may be grounds for a motion to surpress the arrest and evidence and you never know, the government witnesses may fail to show for trial.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/09/14/to-the-permanent-resident-pleading-guilty-to-drug-offense-and-counting-on-cancellation-of-removal-dont/">To the Permanent Resident Pleading Guilty to Drug Offense and Counting on Cancellation of Removal: Don&#8217;t</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">429</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>DC Post-and-Forfeit Is Not A Conviction For Immigration Purposes</title>
		<link>/2013/07/08/dc-post-and-forfeit-is-not-a-conviction-for-immigration-purposes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2013 04:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Criminal Law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Criminal Immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[District]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Immigration Court]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Misdemeanors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Removal Defence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Statutory Interpretation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Washington]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://new.theclementsfirm.com/?p=421</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A colleague recently asked me whether the DC post-and-forfeit procedure after arrest is properly considered a conviction under federal and immigration law. The simple answer is that the post-and-forfeit procedure does not equate to a conviction. Under immigration laws, a conviction is defined as follows (in 8 U.S.C. § 1101(a)(48)(A)): The term &#8220;conviction&#8221; means, with respect &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2013/07/08/dc-post-and-forfeit-is-not-a-conviction-for-immigration-purposes/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">DC Post-and-Forfeit Is Not A Conviction For Immigration Purposes</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/07/08/dc-post-and-forfeit-is-not-a-conviction-for-immigration-purposes/">DC Post-and-Forfeit Is Not A Conviction For Immigration Purposes</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A colleague recently asked me whether the DC post-and-forfeit procedure after arrest is properly considered a conviction under federal and immigration law. The simple answer is that the post-and-forfeit procedure does not equate to a conviction.<span id="more-421"></span></p>
<p>Under immigration laws, a conviction is defined as follows (in <a href="http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/8/1101" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">8 U.S.C. § 1101(a)(48)(A)</a>):</p>
<blockquote><p>The term &#8220;conviction&#8221; means, with respect to an alien, a formal judgment of guilt of the alien entered by a court or, if adjudication of guilt has been withheld, where:</p>
<p>(i) a judge or jury has found the alien guilty or the alien has entered a plea of guilty or nolo contendere or has admitted sufficient facts to warrant a finding of guilt, and</p>
<p>(ii) the judge has ordered some form of punishment, penalty, or restraint on the alien’s liberty to be imposed.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Under this definition, the DC post-and-forfeit procedure does not involve a conviction.</p>
<p>The DC code regarding its post-and-forfeit procedure is as follows:</p>
<blockquote><p>§5-335.01. Enforcement of the post-and-forfeit procedure.</p>
<p>(a) For the purposes of this section, the term “post-and-forfeit procedure” shall mean the procedure enforced as part of the criminal justice system in the District of Columbia whereby a person charged with certain misdemeanors may simultaneously post and forfeit an amount as collateral (which otherwise would serve as security upon release to ensure the arrestee’s appearance at trial) and thereby obtain a full and final resolution of the criminal charge.</p>
<p>(b) The resolution of a criminal charge using the post-and-forfeit procedure is not a conviction of a crime and shall not be equated to a criminal conviction. The fact that a person resolved a charge using the post-and-forfeit procedure may not be relied upon by any court of the District of Columbia or any agency of the District of Columbia in any subsequent criminal, civil, or administrative proceeding or administrative action to impose any sanction, penalty, enhanced sentence, or civil disability.</p></blockquote>
<p>One thing that is apparent is that there is no admission or adjudication of guilt in the post-and-forfeit procedure and no judge imposes a punishment.</p>
<p>The federal district court in DC has also determined that the post-and-forfeit procedure does not involve a conviction. For example, in a recent case, the DC district court stated that “posting and forfeiting is not an admission of guilt, and it does not result in a criminal conviction.” <a href="http://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=9516433629804700761" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Fox v. District of Columbia</em>, 851 F. Supp. 2d 20, 25 (D.D.C. 2012)</a>. The court went on to explain that “the payment does not result in a criminal conviction and it cannot trigger any of the collateral consequences of a criminal conviction, [therefore] it is not appropriately likened to a criminal sentence.” <em>Id.</em> at 31.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/07/08/dc-post-and-forfeit-is-not-a-conviction-for-immigration-purposes/">DC Post-and-Forfeit Is Not A Conviction For Immigration Purposes</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">421</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Need For Discretion</title>
		<link>/2013/06/09/the-need-for-discretion/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 00:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Criminal Law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crime Involving Moral Turpitude]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Criminal Immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[District of Columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Felonies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Immigration Court]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maryland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Removal Defence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Washington]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://new.theclementsfirm.com/?p=399</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Recently, in browsing a well-known local lawyer&#8217;s website, I found the following &#8220;News&#8221; article on their blog: Attorney X convinced a [local] prosecutor to dismiss Armed Robbery charges, all felonies, and all gun charges, despite the defendant being caught nearly red-handed with a shotgun in his fleeing vehicle. The defendant plead to Second Degree Assault, &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2013/06/09/the-need-for-discretion/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">The Need For Discretion</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/06/09/the-need-for-discretion/">The Need For Discretion</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Recently, in browsing a well-known local lawyer&#8217;s website, I found the following &#8220;News&#8221; article on their blog:</p>
<blockquote><p>Attorney X convinced a [local] prosecutor to dismiss Armed Robbery charges, all felonies, and all gun charges, despite the defendant being caught nearly red-handed with a shotgun in his fleeing vehicle.</p>
<p>The defendant plead to Second Degree Assault, a misdemeanor, giving him a strong chance to avoid certain deportation that he would have faced with any felony or gun charge. He will be eligible for parole in one month.</p></blockquote>
<p>While there may be some ethical concern over publicizing past successes without adequately informing potential clients that there is no guarantee of such success in any particular case, that is not my main concern. The biggest problem with this self-serving news article is that it may harm the client in the future.<span id="more-399"></span></p>
<p>What if the ICE Assistant Chief Counsel (the title of immigration prosecutors) in a future deportation case against that client stumbles across this &#8220;article&#8221;? Unfortunately, it would be all too easy for the ICE prosecutor to find. Can the admission by the client&#8217;s attorney be used to try to form the requisite admission of facts?</p>
<p>The fact that this article is not part of the official record of conviction does not end the inquiry &#8211; admission of underlying facts can also be used to show that a conviction is one that leads to removability or deportation. The client would then be in the position of arguing that although his attorney may have admitted the underlying facts, he did not do so himself. Would that argument be successful? I don&#8217;t think anyone knows at this point, but it&#8217;s much better to avoid the situation altogether.</p>
<p>And this situation is avoidable. Is it so important to promote the practice that the attorney should put this up in the first place? Is this attorney hoping that other potential clients &#8220;caught nearly red-handed&#8221; with guns in their fleeing cars will think the attorney will also get them off?</p>
<p>I think a potential client would be better served in knowing that no matter what the alleged facts in their case, the attorney will never divulge them to serve the attorney&#8217;s own interests. They should not be divulged at any time except to the extent that it might help the client.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2013/06/09/the-need-for-discretion/">The Need For Discretion</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">399</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cancellation of Removal for non-Permanent Residents Checklist</title>
		<link>/2011/09/27/cancellation-of-removal-for-non-permanent-residents-checklist/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noah Clements]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 19:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Criminal Law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cancellation of Removal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Criminal Immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Immigration Court]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Removal Defence]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://new.theclementsfirm.com/?p=175</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Under certain circumstances, some people put into removal proceedings who are not Legal Permanent Residents (LPRs) may be eligible for a form of relief called &#8220;Cancellation of Removal&#8221;, which allows certain non-LPRs to &#8220;adjust status&#8221; and become an LPR.  In plain English, Cancellation of Removal allows some non-green card holders to ask the Immigration Judge &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2011/09/27/cancellation-of-removal-for-non-permanent-residents-checklist/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Cancellation of Removal for non-Permanent Residents Checklist</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2011/09/27/cancellation-of-removal-for-non-permanent-residents-checklist/">Cancellation of Removal for non-Permanent Residents Checklist</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Under certain circumstances, some people put into removal proceedings who are not Legal Permanent Residents (LPRs) may be eligible for a form of relief called &#8220;Cancellation of Removal&#8221;, which allows certain non-LPRs to &#8220;adjust status&#8221; and become an LPR.  In plain English, Cancellation of Removal allows some non-green card holders to ask the Immigration Judge to &#8220;cancel&#8221; their removal proceedings and allow them to stay in the U.S. as an LPR.  The statute that provides this relief is <a href="http://www.uscis.gov/ilink/docView/SLB/HTML/SLB/0-0-0-1/0-0-0-29/0-0-0-6337.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">INA §240A(b)(1).</a>  (There other types of Cancellation for LPRs and for battered spouses or children of LPRs or citizens &#8211; <a href="http://www.uscis.gov/ilink/docView/SLB/HTML/SLB/0-0-0-1/0-0-0-29/0-0-0-6337.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">INA §240A(a) &amp; (b)(2)</a>, respectively). The purpose of this post is to provide a checklist for eligibility for Cancellation of Removal for non-permanent residents.</p>
<p><span id="more-175"></span>Cancellation of Removal is discretionary; the Immigration Judge <em>may</em> cancel removal and grant LPR status to a person inadmissible or removable if:</p>
<ol>
<li>the person has been continuously present in the U.S. for the past 10 years.  Special rules for calculating the physical presence time are set out in <a href="http://www.uscis.gov/ilink/docView/SLB/HTML/SLB/0-0-0-1/0-0-0-29/0-0-0-6337.html#0-0-0-5031" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">INA §240A(d)</a>:</li>
<ol>
<li>the time period ends when the person is served a Notice to Appear;</li>
<li>departures from the U.S. of less-than 90 days does not break the physical presence time, unless the sum of all trips is more than 180 days; and</li>
<li>continuity is not required for a person absent from the U.S. because of service in the U.S. armed forces if the person enlisted in the U.S..</li>
</ol>
<li>the person has had &#8220;good moral character&#8221; during the 10-year period;
<ol>
<li>&#8220;Good moral character&#8221; is defined by statute in <a href="http://www.uscis.gov/ilink/docView/SLB/HTML/SLB/0-0-0-1/0-0-0-29/0-0-0-101/0-0-0-434.html#0-0-0-1191" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">INA§101(f)</a> (see also the <a href="http://www.justice.gov/eoir/vll/benchbook/resources/fundamentals/Fundamentals%20Chapter%2012.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Immigration Court Benchbook</a>). Essentially, the statute says you don&#8217;t have &#8220;good moral character&#8221; if you are:</li>
<ol>
<li>a habitual drunkard (or an addict);</li>
<li>a prostitute (or pimp) or drug trafficker;</li>
<li>a person who makes most of their income from illegal gambling;</li>
<li>a person who has given false testimony to get an immigration benefit;</li>
<li>convicted of an aggravated felony;</li>
<li>a terrorist or torturor, or someone who has belonged to an organization condoning those acts;</li>
<li>a person who has made a false claim to citizenship or voted illegally.</li>
</ol>
<li>If you are not on this list, the statute says that the Immigration Judge may still find that you did not have &#8220;good moral character&#8221; for other reasons.</li>
<li>I will post an analysis of &#8220;good moral character&#8221; soon.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>the person has not been convicted of certain crimes:
<ol>
<li>an offense under section<a href="http://www.uscis.gov/ilink/docView/SLB/HTML/SLB/0-0-0-1/0-0-0-29/0-0-0-2006.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> 212(a)(2)</a> [crimes of moral turpitude, controlled substance offenses, prostitution],</li>
<li> <a href="http://www.uscis.gov/ilink/docView/SLB/HTML/SLB/0-0-0-1/0-0-0-29/0-0-0-5672.html#0-0-0-4479">237(a)(2) </a>[crimes of moral turpitude],</li>
<li>or <a href="http://www.uscis.gov/ilink/docView/SLB/HTML/SLB/0-0-0-1/0-0-0-29/0-0-0-5672.html#0-0-0-4525">237(a)(3)</a> [falsifying documents or failing to register],</li>
<li>There is no time limit to this conviction bar to cancellation, but there may be a waiver of this subsection for victims of domestic violence &#8211; see <a href="http://www.uscis.gov/ilink/docView/SLB/HTML/SLB/0-0-0-1/0-0-0-29/0-0-0-5672.html#0-0-0-4585" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">237(a)(7)</a>; and</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>the person can show that removal would result in &#8220;exceptional and extremely unusual hardship&#8221; to his or her U.S. citizen or LPR spouse, parent, or child.
<ol>
<li>This may be the hardest criterion for most people to meet. &#8220;Exceptional and extremely unusual hardship&#8221; is defined as hardship that is substantially beyond that which would ordinarily be expected to result from your own deportation.</li>
<li>Usually people will be able to show this hardship by a US citizen or LPR child or spouse having a serious medical condition that would be worsened by the person&#8217;s removal. However, &#8220;the hardship standard is not so restrictive that only a handful of applicants, such as those who have a qualifying relative with a serious medical condition, will qualify for relief.&#8221; <a href="http://www.justice.gov/eoir/efoia/bia/Decisions/Revdec/pdfDEC/3479.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Matter of Recinas</em>, 23 I&amp;N Dec. 467, 470 (2002)</a>.</li>
<li> I will post an analysis of &#8220;exceptional and extremely unusual hardship&#8221; soon.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<p>The good folks at the <a href="http://www.firrp.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Florence Immigrant and Refugee Rights Project</a> have created a checklist for the documents helpful in a cancellation case and is available <a href="http://www.firrp.org/media/LPRCDocumentChecklist-en.doc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here.</a>  If you are in removal proceedings and wish to seek Cancellation of Removal, feel free to contact me at (202) 630-0544 or <a title="Contact" href="http://new.theclementsfirm.com/?page_id=42" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>.  Enlisting the help of a good immigration lawyer is highly recommended; this is not something a person should do on his own.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2011/09/27/cancellation-of-removal-for-non-permanent-residents-checklist/">Cancellation of Removal for non-Permanent Residents Checklist</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Clements Firm</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">175</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
